<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 13:12:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 13:16:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007252/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (libsoup), <b>Debian</b> (debian-security-support and redis), <b>Fedora</b> (expat, java-21-openjdk, lemonldap-ng, and phpMyAdmin), <b>Mageia</b> (chromium-browser-stable and git-lfs), <b>Oracle</b> (bzip2, git-lfs, libsoup, mariadb:10.11, mariadb:10.5, python-jinja2, redis, and unbound), <b>Red Hat</b> (git-lfs, libsoup, python-jinja2, rsync, and unbound), <b>SUSE</b> (buildah, chromium, google-osconfig-agent, govulncheck-vulndb, hauler, ignition, krb5, libxml2, python311-pydantic, SDL2_sound, and trivy), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (jquery, linux-azure, linux-azure-4.15, linux-azure-5.15, linux-hwe-5.4, linux-oracle, and mysql-8.0).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007252/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 13:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Freedesktop looking for new home for its GitLab instance</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007032/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Visitors to the <a href="https://www.freedesktop.org/">freedesktop.org</a>
<a href="https://gitlab.freedesktop.org/">GitLab instance</a> are currently being greeted with a message noting that
the company who has been hosting it for free for nearly five years, Equinix, has
asked that it be moved (or start being paid for) by the end of April.  The
<a
href="https://gitlab.freedesktop.org/freedesktop/freedesktop/-/issues/2011">issue
ticket</a> opened by Benjamin Tissoires in order to  track the planning of a move is clear that the project is grateful for
the gift:
"<q>First, I'd like to thank Equinix Metal for the years of support they gave us. They were very kind and generous with us and even if it's a shame we have to move out on a short notice, all things come to an end.</q>"

<p>
The current cost for the services, much of which is for 50TB of bandwidth
per month and a half-dozen beefy servers for running continuous-integration
(CI) jobs, comes to around $24,000 per month.  Tissoires believes that the
project should start paying for service somewhere, in order to avoid
upheaval of this sort, sometimes on short or no notice. "<q>I personally
think we better have fd.o pay for its own servers, and then have sponsors
chip in. This way, when a sponsor goes away, it's technically much simpler
to just replace the money than change datacenter.</q>"  Various options are
being discussed there, but any move is likely to disrupt normal services
for a week or more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007032/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 17:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>GNU C Library 2.41 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007024/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/6975370.R56niFO833@pinacolada">Version 2.41</a> of the GNU
C Library has been released.  Changes include a number of test-suite
improvements, strict-error support in the DNS stub resolver, wrappers for
the the <a
href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man2/sched_setattr.2.html"><tt>sched_setattr()</tt>
and <tt>sched_getattr()</tt></a> system calls,
Unicode 16.0.0 support,
improved C23 support,
support for <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/885818/">extensible restartable
sequences</a>,
Guarded Control Stack support on 64-bit Arm systems,
and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007024/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 16:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Thunderbird moving to monthly updates in March</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006917/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.thunderbird.net/en-US/">Thunderbird</a> project has <a
href="https://thunderbird.topicbox.com/groups/planning/Td58a7d8581e7d60f">announced</a>
that it is making its <a
href="https://developer.thunderbird.net/releases/channels">Release
channel</a> the default download beginning with the 135.0 release in
March. This will move users to major monthly releases instead of the
annual major Extended Support Release (ESR) that is the current
default.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
One of our goals for 2025 is to increase active installations on the
release channel to at least 20% of the total installations. At last
check, we had 29,543 active installations on the release channel,
compared to 20,918 on beta, and 5,941 on daily. The release channel
installations currently account for 0.27% of the 10,784,551 total
active installations tracked on stats.thunderbird.net.
</blockquote>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006917/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 14:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006978/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (redis:7), <b>Debian</b> (bind9, chromium, flightgear, pam-u2f, and simgear), <b>Red Hat</b> (fence-agents, git-lfs, libsoup, python3.9, rsync, and traceroute), <b>Slackware</b> (bind), <b>SUSE</b> (apache2-mod_security2, corepack22, go1.24, hplip, ignition, iperf, kernel, kernel-devel-longterm, nginx, nodejs22, openvpn, owasp-modsecurity-crs, and shadow), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (bind9, jinja2, libxml2, linux-lowlatency-hwe-6.8, php7.0, tomcat6, and vlc).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006978/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 14:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>LWN.net Weekly Edition for January 23, 2025</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005296/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Inside this week's LWN.net Weekly Edition:
        <p>
        <ul>
<li> <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1005296/">Front</a>: Rsync vulnerability; Going mouseless; Commit IDs; 6.13 Development statistics; Python string formating; Python None-aware operators.
            <li> <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1005298/">Briefs</a>: Kernel 6.13; Dillo 3.2.0; GDB 16.1; OpenVox; Wine 10.0; Quotes; ...
            <li> <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1005299/">Announcements</a>: Newsletters, conferences, security updates, patches, and more.
            </ul>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005296/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A revamped Python string-formatting proposal</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005000/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The proposal to add a more general facility for string formatting to
Python, which we <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/985346/">looked at</a> in August 2024,
has changed a great deal since, so it merits another look.  The
changes take multiple forms: a new title for <a
href="https://peps.python.org/pep-0750/">PEP
750</a> ("Template Strings"), a different mechanism for creating and using templates,
a new <tt>Template</tt> type to hold them, and several additional authors for the PEP.
Meanwhile, one controversial part of the original proposal, lazy evaluation
of the interpolated values, has been changed so that it requires an
explicit opt-in (via <a
href="https://docs.python.org/3.8/tutorial/controlflow.html#lambda-expressions"><tt>lambda</tt></a>);
template strings are a generalization of <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/919426/">f-strings</a> and lazy evaluation was seen by some
as a potentially confusing departure from their behavior.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005000/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 18:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A mouseless tale: trying for a keyboard-driven desktop</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005332/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The computer mouse is a wonderful invention, but for the past few
months I've been working to use mine as little as possible for
productivity and ergonomic reasons. It should not be surprising that
there are quite a few open-source applications, utilities, and
configuration options that are either designed to or incidentally
assist in creating a keyboard-driven desktop. This includes tiling window
management with <a
href="https://github.com/paperwm/PaperWM?tab=readme-ov-file#paperwm">PaperWM</a>, the <a
href="https://vimium.github.io/">Vimium</a> browser extension, <a
href="https://github.com/sezanzeb/input-remapper?tab=readme-ov-file#input-remapper">Input Remapper</a>, and more.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005332/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A look at the recent rsync vulnerability</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005302/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
On January&nbsp;14, Nick Tait
<a href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/CALDM2HfAOzs+zr3XLCDAKH8oOosigdaNooUANDf=Ez5mLSvQcQ@mail.gmail.com/">
announced</a> the discovery of six vulnerabilities in
<a href="https://rsync.samba.org/">
rsync</a>, the popular file-synchronization tool. While software vulnerabilities are
not uncommon, the
<a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2024-12084">
most serious one</a> he announced allows for remote code execution
on servers that run <tt>rsyncd</tt> — and possibly other configurations.
The bug itself is fairly simple, but this event provides a nice opportunity to
dig into it, show why it is so serious, and consider ways
the open-source community can prevent such mistakes in the
future.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005302/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 16:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Development statistics for 6.13</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004998/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The 6.13 development cycle ended on January&nbsp;19 with the <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/CAHk-=wiprabAQcCwb3qNhrT5P50MJNqunC9JU5v99kdvM-2rsg@mail.gmail.com/">release</a>
of the 6.13 kernel.  This cycle was, on its surface, one of the slowest we
have seen in some time; the LWN merge-window summaries (<a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/998623/">part&nbsp;1</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/998990/">part&nbsp;2</a>) and <a
href="https://kernelnewbies.org/Linux_6.13">the KernelNewbies 6.13 page</a>
can be consulted for a refresher on all it contains.  Here, instead, we
will take our usual look at where all of those changes came from.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004998/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 17:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Incus 6.9 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006769/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://discuss.linuxcontainers.org/t/incus-6-9-has-been-released/22679">Version 6.9</a> of the <a href="https://linuxcontainers.org/incus/">Incus</a> container and virtual-machine management system has been released. Changes include a command to provide virtual machine memory dumps, ability to set network ACLs for instances on bridged networks, and more.</p>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006769/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 18:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>LWN in EPUB format</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006562/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[For years we have had occasional requests to be able to receive LWN in
a format for ebook readers.  It took a while, but we are now happy to
announce that all of LWN's feature content is available, to subscribers at
the "professional hacker" level and above, in the EPUB format.  To obtain
the weekly edition as an EPUB file, just click the "Download EPUB" link in
the left column.  There is a separate <a href="https://lwn.net/headlines/">RSS feed</a>
for the EPUB format as well.  Any other feature content can be turned into
an ebook by appending <tt>/epub</tt> to its URL.
<p>
We will also be creating special EPUB books at times.  As an example of
what is possible, our complete coverage from <a
href="https://lwn.net/images/epub/kangrejos-2024.epub">Kangrejos 2024</a> and <a
href="https://lwn.net/images/epub/lsfmmbpf-2024.epub">the 2024 Linux Storage, Filesystem,
Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a> are available to all readers.
<p>
There are surely places where our EPUB books can be improved; please feel
free to drop us a note (at <a
href="mailto:lwn@lwn.net"><tt>lwn@lwn.net</tt></a>) with suggestions.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006562/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 16:57:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Credential-leaking vulnerability in some Git credential managers</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006691/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Security researcher RyotaK
<a href="https://flatt.tech/research/posts/clone2leak-your-git-credentials-belong-to-us/">
has shared</a> a series of vulnerabilities that all have to do with how Git
interfaces with external
credential managers. In short, while Git guards against newline characters
(<tt>\n</tt>) being injected into a repository's URL, some programming languages
also treat carriage return characters (<tt>\r</tt>) as being newlines. Adding a
carriage return to a repository's URL can cause Git and the credential manager
to disagree on how the URL should be parsed, ultimately resulting in Git
credentials being sent to the wrong host. Malicious repositories could include
Git submodules with malformed URLs, triggering the bug. Only password-based authentication
with an external credential manager is
vulnerable to this attack; SSH-based authentication remains secure. The Git project
has chosen to consider this a vulnerability in Git, given the large amount of
external software affected. The project has fixed the bug on its end by
<a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/git/git/master/Documentation/RelNotes/2.48.1.txt">
releasing updates</a> for all supported versions that ban
carriage returns in URLs entirely.
</p>

<p>
Affected software includes GitHub Desktop, Git LFS, and possibly other Git utilities:
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Since Git itself doesn't use .lfsconfig file, specifying the URL that contains
the newline character in .lfsconfig causes Git LFS to insert the newline character
into the message, while bypassing [...] Git's validation.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006691/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 16:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006677/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (bzip2, gimp:2.8, keepalived, mariadb:10.11, mariadb:10.5, python-jinja2, and redis), <b>Debian</b> (iperf3, libtar, and pdns-recursor), <b>Fedora</b> (abseil-cpp, dotnet8.0, dotnet9.0, golang, libsoup3, and vaultwarden), <b>Oracle</b> (gimp:2.8, iperf3, keepalived, kernel, redis:7, and unbound), <b>Red Hat</b> (libsoup), <b>SUSE</b> (amazon-ssm-agent, go1.22, go1.23, iperf, java-21-openjdk, nginx, openvpn, and python311-asteval), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (kernel, libmicrodns, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-hwe, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-4.15, linux-hwe,
 linux-kvm, linux-oracle, linux, linux-azure, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.15, linux-gke, linux-gkeop,
 linux-hwe-5.15, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.15, linux-intel-iotg,
 linux-intel-iotg-5.15, linux-kvm, linux-lowlatency,
 linux-lowlatency-hwe-5.15, linux-nvidia, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-5.15,
 linux-raspi, linux, linux-azure, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-6.8, linux-gke, linux-gkeop,
 linux-hwe-6.8, linux-ibm, linux-lowlatency, linux-nvidia,
 linux-nvidia-6.8, linux-nvidia-lowlatency, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-6.8,
 linux-raspi, linux, linux-azure, linux-gcp, linux-oem-6.11, linux-raspi, linux-realtime, linux, linux-bluefield, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.4, linux-ibm,
 linux-ibm-5.4, linux-kvm, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-5.4, linux-raspi, linux-oem-6.8, rsync, and tcpreplay).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006677/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 14:04:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Ubuntu developer discussion moving to Matrix</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006622/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Ubuntu will be moving its "<q>official realtime communications
channels</q>" from IRC to Matrix, beginning March&nbsp;1,&nbsp;2025, following
a <a
href="https://lists.ubuntu.com/archives/ubuntu-devel/2025-January/043224.html">discussion</a>
on the ubuntu-devel mailing list.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
"Official" communication, such as making realtime requests of privileged
Ubuntu developer teams, could be expected to be actioned if requested on
Matrix only. Similarly, you can consider your social responsibility to
other developers in relation to your work in Ubuntu development to be
fulfilled if you are present on that platform. And Canonical will
follow in its requirement for its employed Ubuntu developers to be
present on that agreed platform during their working hours.
</blockquote>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006622/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 14:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006486/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (git and openjpeg2), <b>Mageia</b> (virtualbox), <b>SUSE</b> (podman), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (clamav, frr, libreoffice, linux-xilinx-zynqmp, and quagga).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006486/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 15:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Linux-related discussion as a cybersecurity threat</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006328/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://distrowatch.com/weekly.php?issue=20250127">DistroWatch
January 27 edition</a> includes this interesting tidbit:
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Starting on January 19, 2025 Facebook's internal policy makers
	decided that Linux is malware and labeled groups associated with
	Linux as being "cybersecurity threats". Any posts mentioning
	DistroWatch and multiple groups associated with Linux and Linux
	discussions have either been shut down or had many of their posts
	removed.
<p>
	We've been hearing all week from readers who say they can no longer
	post about Linux on Facebook or share links to DistroWatch. Some
	people have reported their accounts have been locked or limited for
	posting about Linux. 
</blockquote>
<p>
One can only hope that this is a mistake that will be resolved soon.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006328/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 15:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006261/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (git-lfs, java-17-openjdk, java-21-openjdk, kernel, and python-jinja2), <b>Debian</b> (git and git-lfs), <b>Fedora</b> (buildah, chromium, containers-common, freeipa, glibc, golang, mediawiki, pam-u2f, podman, and rsync), <b>Mageia</b> (glibc, iperf, openssl, phpmyadmin, and poppler), <b>Oracle</b> (firefox, git-lfs, grafana, java-17-openjdk, java-21-openjdk, kernel, python-jinja2, and redis:6), and <b>SUSE</b> (chromium, go1.22-1.22.11-1.1, go1.23-1.23.5-1.1, go1.24-1.24rc2-1.1, java-11-openjdk, kernel, libopenssl-3-devel, libQt6Bluetooth6, nodejs18, nodejs20, python311-azure-storage-blob, qt6-connectivity, and ruby3.4-rubygem-nokogiri-1.18.2-1.1).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006261/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 14:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006103/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (chromium and python-django), <b>Fedora</b> (git-lfs and pam-u2f), <b>Mageia</b> (golang), <b>Red Hat</b> (java-11-openjdk with Extended Lifecycle Support, java-17-openjdk, and java-21-openjdk), <b>SUSE</b> (cheat, dante, docker-stable, grafana, and kernel), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (cacti, cyrus-imapd, HTMLDOC, and PCL).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006103/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 15:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>