<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 23:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 04:12:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992030/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (chromium and trafficserver), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium), <b>Mageia</b> (apache-mod_jk, gnome-shell, kernel, kmod-xtables-addons, and kmod-virtualbox, kernel-linus, and python3), <b>Oracle</b> (container-tools:ol8, dovecot, emacs, expat, firefox, git-lfs, gtk3, kernel, nano, net-snmp, osbuild-composer, python3, python3.11, python3.12, ruby:3.3, and virt:ol and virt-devel:rhel), <b>Slackware</b> (boost), <b>SUSE</b> (kernel), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (configobj, cups, cups-browsed, cups-filters, libcupsfilters, and libppd).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992030/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 13:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Remote exploit of CUPS</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991929/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Security researcher Simone Margaritelli 
<a href="https://www.evilsocket.net/2024/09/26/Attacking-UNIX-systems-via-CUPS-Part-I/">
has reported</a> a new vulnerability in 
<a href="https://openprinting.github.io/cups/">
CUPS</a>, the software that many Linux systems use to manage printers and print jobs. Margaritelli describes the impact of the attack by saying:
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
A remote unauthenticated attacker can silently replace existing printers' (or install new ones) IPP urls with a malicious one, resulting in arbitrary command execution (on the computer) when a print job is started (from that computer).
</blockquote>

<p>
The vulnerability relies on a few related problems in CUPS libraries and utilities; versions before 2.0.1 or 2.1b1 (depending on the component) may be affected.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991929/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>PostgreSQL 17 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991904/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://www.postgresql.org/about/news/postgresql-17-released-2936/">Version
17</a> of the <a href="https://www.postgresql.org/">PostgreSQL</a> database has been released.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
This release of PostgreSQL adds significant overall performance gains,
including an overhauled memory management implementation for vacuum,
optimizations to storage access and improvements for high concurrency
workloads, speedups in bulk loading and exports, and query execution
improvements for indexes. PostgreSQL 17 has features that benefit
brand new workloads and critical systems alike, such as additions to
the developer experience with the SQL/JSON JSON_TABLE command, and
enhancements to logical replication that simplify management of high
availability workloads and major version upgrades.
</blockquote>

<p>LWN recently <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/984599/">covered</a>
some of the interesting new features and security enhancements in
PostgreSQL 17.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991904/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 15:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Uniting for Internet Freedom: Tor Project &amp; Tails Join Forces (Tor blog)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991899/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The online-privacy-focused <a href="https://www.torproject.org/">Tor
project</a> has <a
href="https://blog.torproject.org/tor-tails-join-forces/">announced</a>
that it has "<q>joined forces and merged operations</q>" with the <a
href="https://tails.net/">Tails OS</a> Linux distribution.

<blockquote class="bq">
Countering the threat of global mass surveillance and censorship to a free Internet, Tor and Tails provide essential tools to help people around the world stay safe online. By joining forces, these two privacy advocates will pool their resources to focus on what matters most: ensuring that activists, journalists, other at-risk and everyday users will have access to improved digital security tools.
<p>
In late 2023, Tails approached the Tor Project with the idea of merging operations. Tails had outgrown its existing structure. Rather than expanding Tails's operational capacity on their own and putting more stress on Tails workers, merging with the Tor Project, with its larger and established operational framework, offered a solution. By joining forces, the Tails team can now focus on their core mission of maintaining and improving Tails OS, exploring more and complementary use cases while benefiting from the larger organizational structure of The Tor Project.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991899/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 15:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991897/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (container-tools:rhel8, dovecot, emacs, expat, git-lfs, go-toolset:rhel8, golang, grafana, grafana-pcp, gtk3, kernel, kernel-rt, nano, python3, python3.11, python3.12, and virt:rhel and virt-devel:rhel), <b>Debian</b> (mediawiki and puredata), <b>Fedora</b> (chisel), <b>Mageia</b> (glib2.0, gtk+2.0 and gtk+3.0, and python-astropy), <b>Red Hat</b> (git-lfs, grafana, grafana-pcp, kernel, and kernel-rt), <b>SUSE</b> (kubernetes1.24, kubernetes1.25, kubernetes1.26, kubernetes1.27, kubernetes1.28, opensc, and python36), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (apparmor, apr, ca-certificates, linux, linux-aws, linux-kvm, linux-lts-xenial, linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-5.15, linux-raspi, openjpeg2, ruby-rack, and tomcat8, tomcat9).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991897/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 14:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Eliminating Memory Safety Vulnerabilities at the Source
(Google Security Blog)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991775/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Here's <a
href="https://security.googleblog.com/2024/09/eliminating-memory-safety-vulnerabilities-Android.html">a
post on the Google Security Blog</a> on how switching to a memory-safe
language can quickly reduce vulnerabilities in a project, even if a large
body of older code persists.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	 This leads to two important takeaways:
<p>
<ul class="spacylist">
    <li> The problem is overwhelmingly with new code, necessitating a
    fundamental change in how we develop code. 
    <li> Code matures and gets safer with time, exponentially, making the
    returns on investments like rewrites diminish over time as code gets
    older.
</ul>
<p>
For example, based on the average vulnerability lifetimes, 5-year-old code
has a 3.4x (using lifetimes from the study) to 7.4x (using lifetimes
observed in Android and Chromium) lower vulnerability density than new
code.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991775/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 06:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for September 19, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989982/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for September 19, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989982/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 05:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Kernel developers at Cauldron</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990379/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[A Linux system is made up of a large number of interdependent components,
all of which must support each other well.  It can thus be surprising that,
it seems, the developers working on those components do not often speak
with each other.  In the hope of improving that situation, efforts have
been made in recent years to attract toolchain developers to the
kernel-heavy Linux Plumbers Conference.  This year, though, the opposite
happened as well: the <a href="https://gcc.gnu.org/wiki/cauldron2024">2024
GNU Tools Cauldron</a> hosted a discussion where kernel developers were
invited to discuss their needs.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990379/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A discussion of Rust safety documentation</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990273/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
<a href="https://kangrejos.com/">
Kangrejos 2024</a> started off with a talk from Benno Lossin about his
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/982868/">recent work</a>
to establish a standard for safety documentation in Rust kernel code. Lossin
began his talk by giving a brief review of what safety documentation is, and
why it's needed, before moving on to the current status of his work. Safety
documentation is easier to read and write when there's a shared vocabulary for
discussing common requirements; Lossin wants to establish that shared vocabulary
for Rust code in the Linux kernel.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990273/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 18:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Vanilla OS 2: an immutable distribution to run all software</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989629/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://vanillaos.org">Vanilla OS</a>, an immutable desktop
Linux distribution designed for developers and advanced users, has
recently published its <a
href="https://vanillaos.org/blog/article/2024-07-28/vanilla-os-2-orchid---stable-release">2.0
"Orchid" release</a>. Previously based on Ubuntu, Vanilla OS has now
shifted to Debian unstable ("sid"). The release has made it easier to
install software from other distributions' package repositories, and it
is now theoretically possible to install and run Android applications as well.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989629/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 17:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] An update on BPF generation from GCC</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990343/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The generation of binary code for the kernel's BPF virtual machine has been
limited to the Clang compiler since the beginning; even developers who
use GCC to build kernels must use Clang to compile to BPF.  Work has
been underway for some years on adding a BPF backend to GCC as well; the
developers involved ran a session at the <a
href="https://gcc.gnu.org/wiki/cauldron2024">2024 GNU Tools Cauldron</a> to
provide an update on that project.  It would seem that the BPF backend is
close to being ready for production use.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990343/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Fedora evicts WolfSSL</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989687/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://docs.fedoraproject.org/en-US/fesco/">Fedora
Engineering Steering Committee</a> (FESCo) has voted to
immediately remove the <a href="https://www.wolfssl.com">WolfSSL</a> package from all of Fedora's
repositories due to its maintainer failing to gain approval to package
a new cryptography library for Fedora. Its brief travels through
Fedora's package system highlights gaps in documentation, as well as
in the package&#8209;review process. The good news is that this may stir
Fedora to improve its documentation and revive a formal security
team.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989687/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 16:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Some 6.11 development statistics</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989528/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The 6.11 kernel was <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/CAHk-=whVpSHw9+4ov=oLevfv8sPYbh59T_9VKif-6Vqkr41jQA@mail.gmail.com/">released</a>
on September&nbsp;15 after a typical nine-week development cycle.  This
release integrates 13,890 non-merge changesets, so it was a moderately busy
cycle, slightly more so that 6.10 was.  With a new release comes a new round
of development statistics; read on for the details.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989528/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 14:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The RCU API, 2024 edition</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/988638/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Read-copy-update (RCU) is a synchronization mechanism that was added to the
Linux kernel in October 2002.  RCU is most frequently used as a <a
href="https://linuxfoundation.org/webinars/unraveling-rcu-usage-mysteries/">replacement
for reader-writer locking</a>, but is also used in <a
href="https://linuxfoundation.org/webinars/unraveling-rcu-usage-mysteries-additional-use-cases/">a
number of other ways</a>.  This article covers recent changes to the RCU
API; it was contributed by Paul McKenney, Boqun Feng, Frederic Weisbecker,
Joel Fernandes, Neeraj Upadhyay, and Uladzislau Rezki.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/988638/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 15:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Debating ifupdown replacements for Debian trixie</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989055/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Debian does not have an official way to configure
networking. Instead, it has <a
href="https://wiki.debian.org/NetworkConfiguration">four</a>
recommended ways to configure networking, one of which is the
venerable <a
href="https://salsa.debian.org/debian/ifupdown">ifupdown</a>, which
has part of Debian since the turn of the century and is showing its
age. A conversation about its maintainability and possible replacement with <a
href="https://github.com/ifupdown-ng/ifupdown-ng">ifupdown&#8209;ng</a> has
led to discussions about the default network-management tools for
Debian "<a href="https://www.debian.org/releases/trixie/">trixie</a>"
(Debian 13, which expected in 2025) and beyond. No route to consensus
has been found, yet.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989055/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 15:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Vanilla OS 2 - future plans, updates, and next release</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991722/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://vanillaos.org/">Vanilla OS</a> project has
published <a
href="https://vanillaos.org/blog/article/2024-09-25/vanilla-os-2---future-plans-updates-and-next-release">a
blog post</a> to answer questions that users have raised since the release of <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/989629/">Vanilla OS 2</a>. The post has information about the update strategy for the distribution,
an <a href="https://vanillaos.org/enterprise-support">enterprise
version with support</a>, and plans for an experimental version called
Vanilla OS Vision.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>We are not planning for a potential Vanilla OS 3 because it is not
yet necessary. As previously explained, our focus right now is on bug
fixing and making the system as solid as possible, especially in light
of collaborations with OEMs. We're all excited about laying the
foundation for a third version of Vanilla OS, but we have
responsibilities to attend to first.</p>

<p>This does not mean that there will never be one, nor does it mean
that Orchid will become stagnant. On the contrary, as previously
mentioned, our updates not only bring fixes but also updates to system
components, improvements to existing features, and updates to
components like GNOME (we are planning the release of GNOME 47 soon,
for example).</p>
</blockquote>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991722/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 17:13:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991701/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (booth), <b>Gentoo</b> (Xpdf), <b>Oracle</b> (go-toolset:ol8, golang, grafana, grafana-pcp, kernel, libnbd, openssl, pcp, and ruby:3.3), <b>Red Hat</b> (container-tools:rhel8, go-toolset:rhel8, golang, kernel, and kernel-rt), <b>SUSE</b> (apr, cargo-audit, chromium, obs-service-cargo, python311, python36, quagga, traefik, and xen), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (intel-microcode, linux-azure-fde-5.15, and puma).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991701/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 13:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>HarfBuzz 10.0.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991529/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://github.com/harfbuzz/harfbuzz/releases/tag/10.0.0">Version
10.0.0</a> of the <a href="https://harfbuzz.github.io/">HarfBuzz</a>
text-shaping engine has been released. Notable changes in this release
include <a
href="https://www.unicode.org/versions/Unicode16.0.0/">Unicode
16.0.0</a> support, adding Cairo script as an output format for
<tt>hb-view</tt>, and a number of bug fixes.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991529/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 14:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991492/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Gentoo</b> (GCC, Hunspell, Tor, and ZNC), <b>SUSE</b> (apr-devel, cargo-c, chromedriver, firefox, kernel, libecpg6, libmfx, onefetch, postgresql12, postgresql13, postgresql14, postgresql15, postgresql16, python310-azure-identity, python39, qemu, rage-encryption, stgit, and system-user-zabbix), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (kernel, linux-ibm-5.15, linux-oracle-5.15, linux-xilinx-zynqmp, linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-5.15, linux-raspi, and py7zr).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991492/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 11:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hy 1.0.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991401/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Version 1.0.0 of <a
href="http://hylang.org/">Hy</a>, a Lisp dialect that is embedded in Python, has been <a
href="https://github.com/hylang/hy/discussions/2608">released</a>
after nearly 12 years in development. This is the first stable release of the project:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Henceforth, breaking changes to documented parts of the language
(other than dropping support for versions of Python that are
themselves no longer supported by the CPython developers) will
increase the major version number, and my intention is for that not to
happen often, if at all.
</blockquote>

<p>The 1.0.0 release supports Python 3.8 through 3.13. See the <a
href="http://hylang.org/hy/doc/v1.0.0">documentation</a> and the "<a
href="http://hylang.org/hy/doc/v1.0.0/whyhy">Why Hy?</a>" page for why
one might want to use it.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991401/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 19:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991377/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (expat, fence-agents, firefox, libnbd, openssl, pcp, ruby:3.3, and thunderbird), <b>Debian</b> (ruby-saml), <b>Fedora</b> (aardvark-dns, chromium, expat, jupyterlab, less, openssl, python-jupyterlab-server, python-notebook, python3-docs, and python3.12), <b>Gentoo</b> (calibre, curl, Emacs, org-mode, Exo, file, GPL Ghostscript, gst-plugins-good, liblouis, Mbed TLS, OpenVPN, Oracle VirtualBox, PJSIP, Portage, PostgreSQL, pypy, pypy3, Rust, Slurm, stb, VLC, and Xen), <b>SUSE</b> (container-suseconnect, ffmpeg-4, kernel, libpcap, python3, python310, python36, and wpa_supplicant), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (firefox, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-hwe, linux-azure, linux-azure-4.15, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-4.15, linux-hwe, linux-kvm, linux-oracle, linux-azure, and linux-ibm-5.15, linux-oracle-5.15).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991377/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 14:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>