<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 08:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 3 Oct 2024 08:35:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for September 26, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990791/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for September 26, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990791/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 01:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] What the Nova GPU driver needs</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990736/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
In March, Danilo Krummrich <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/966129">announced</a> the new
Nova GPU driver — a successor to Noveau for controlling NVIDIA GPUs.
At Kangrejos 2024, Krummrich gave a
presentation about what it is, why it's needed, and where it's
going next. Hearing about the needs of the driver provoked extended discussion
on related topics, including what level of safety is reasonable to expect from
drivers, given that they must interact with the hardware.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990736/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 15:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Linus and Dirk on succession, Rust, and more</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990534/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The "Linus and Dirk show" has been a fixture at Open Source Summit for as
long as the conference has existed; it started back when the conference was
called LinuxCon.  Since Linus Torvalds famously does not like to give
talks, as he said during this year's edition at <a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/open-source-summit-europe/">Open Source Summit Europe</a>
(OSSEU) in Vienna, Austria, he and Dirk Hohndel have been sitting down for an
informal chat on a wide range of topics as a keynote session.  That way,
Torvalds does not need to prepare, but also does not know what topics
will be brought up, which makes it "so much more fun for one of us", Hohndel
said with a grin.   The topics this time ranged from the just-released&nbsp;6.11
kernel and the upcoming Linux&nbsp;6.12, through Rust for the kernel, to the recurring topic of succession and
the graying of Linux maintainers.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990534/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 13:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] KDE sets its goals through 2026</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990604/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Almost a decade ago <a href="https://ev.kde.org/">KDE&nbsp;e.V.</a>,
the non-profit organization that supports <a
href="http://kde.org/">KDE</a>, started a <a href="https://community.kde.org/Goals/Goals_Process">process</a> for
selecting <a href="https://kde.org/goals/">goals</a> to help the community unite behind a common vision for where the
project should go in the near future. KDE
recently wrapped up its 2022-2024 <a
href="https://community.kde.org/Goals">cycle</a> and announced the goals for 2024-2026 at <a
href="https://akademy.kde.org/2024/">Akademy</a> on September&nbsp;7, in Würzburg,
Germany. This time around, KDE will be looking to streamline its
application-development experience, improve support for input devices,
and bring in new contributors.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990604/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 15:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Committing to Rust in the kernel</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991062/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The project to enable the writing of kernel code in Rust has been underway
for several years, and each kernel release includes more Rust code.  Even
so, some developers have expressed frustration at the time it takes to get
new functionality merged, and an air of uncertainty still hangs over
the project.  At the 2024 Maintainers Summit, Miguel Ojeda led a discussion
on the status of Rust in the kernel and whether the time had come to stop
considering it an experimental project.  There were not answers to all of the
questions, but it seems clear that Rust in the kernel will continue
steaming ahead.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991062/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 11:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Resources for learning Rust for kernel development</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990619/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Dirk Behme led a second session, back-to-back with
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/990489/">his session on error handling</a> at
Kangrejos 2024, discussing providing better guidance for users of the kernel's
Rust abstractions. Just after that,
Carlos Bilbao and Miguel Ojeda had their own time slot dedicated to collecting
resources that could be of use to someone trying to come up to speed
on kernel development in
Rust. The attendees provided a lot of guidance in both sessions, and
discussed what they could do to make things easier for people coming
from non-Rust backgrounds.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990619/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 15:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Tools for kernel developers</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991033/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Konstantin Ryabitsev started a session on development tooling at the 2024
Maintainers Summit by saying that he does not want to be a "wrecking ball".
If a given workflow is working for people, he does not want to try to force
any sort of change.  That said, he has ideas for how he can continue his
work on providing better tooling for the development community.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991033/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 11:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The 6.12 merge window begins</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990750/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[As of this writing, 6,778 non-merge changesets have been pulled into the
mainline kernel for the 6.12 release — over half of the work that had been
staged in linux-next prior to the opening of the merge window.  There has
been a lot of refactoring and cleanup work this time around, but also some
significant changes.  Read on for a summary of the first half of the 6.12
merge window.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990750/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 14:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Considering kernel pass-through interfaces</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990802/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The kernel normally sits firmly between user space and the system's
peripheral devices, and provides a standard interface to those devices.  At
times, though, a more direct interface to a device is desired — but such
interfaces can be controversial.  At the 2024 Maintainers Summit, the
assembled developers considered a specific case — the proposed <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/969383/">fwctl subsystem</a> — as well as the role of such
drivers in general.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990802/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 12:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Best practices for error handling in kernel Rust</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990489/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Dirk Behme led a session discussing the use of Rust's question-mark operator in
the kernel at Kangrejos 2024. He was particularly concerned with the concept of
"silent" errors that don't print any messages to the console.
Other attendees were less convinced that this was a problem, but his presentation
sparked a lot of discussion about whether the Rust-for-Linux project could
improve error handling in kernel Rust code.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990489/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 15:54:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] RPM 4.20 is coming</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/988927/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://rpm.org/">RPM Package Manager</a> (RPM) project is
nearing the release of RPM&nbsp;4.20, the last major planned update for the RPM 4.x
series. It has few user-facing changes, but
several additions and enhancements for developers&mdash;as well as
some small incompatibilities that will likely require RPM packagers to
revise their <a
href="https://rpm-packaging-guide.github.io/#what-is-a-spec-file">spec
files</a>. 4.20 will be rolling out to many users soon, in
Fedora&nbsp;41, which is scheduled for October. RPM&nbsp;6.0 is
already in the works, with a new package format and opening the door
to enabling C++ use in the RPM codebase.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/988927/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 13:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The uncertain future of kernel regression tracking</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990599/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Tracking of regressions seems like an important task for any project; there
is no other way to ensure that known problems are fixed.  At the 2024
Maintainers Summit, though, Thorsten Leemhuis, who has been doing that work
for the kernel, expressed some doubts about whether it is worth continuing.
The result was an energetic session on how regression tracking should be
done better, and how this work should be supported.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990599/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 06:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Manjaro 24.1 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992660/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://forum.manjaro.org/t/manjaro-24-1-xahea-released/168699/1">Version
24.1</a> of the Arch-based <a href="https://manjaro.org/">Manjaro</a>
distribution is now available with the 6.10 Linux kernel,
GNOME&nbsp;46.5, KDE&nbsp;Plasma&nbsp;6.1 and KDE&nbsp;Gear&nbsp;24.08:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Plasma 6.1 on Wayland now has a feature that "remembers" what you were
doing in your last session like it did under X11. Although this is
still work in progress, If you log off and shut down your computer
with a dozen open windows, Plasma will now open them for you the next
time you power up your desktop, making it faster and easier to get
back to what you were doing. At Manjaro we are still defaulting to
X11, however switching to Wayland can be done easily by selecting the
wanted session in your display manager.
</blockquote>

<p>The project also offers minimal install images with the 6.6 LTS and
6.1 LTS kernels to support older hardware as needed.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992660/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 14:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992650/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (grafana), <b>Fedora</b> (cjson and php), <b>Oracle</b> (389-ds-base, freeradius, grafana, kernel, and krb5), <b>Slackware</b> (cryfs, cups, and mozilla), <b>SUSE</b> (OpenIPMI, openssl-3, openvpn, thunderbird, and tomcat), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (cups, cups-filters, knot-resolver, linux-raspi, linux-raspi-5.4, orc, php7.4, php8.1, php8.3, python-asyncssh, ruby-devise-two-factor, and vim).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992650/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 13:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>FFmpeg 7.1 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992496/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://ffmpeg.org//index.html#pr7.1">Version 7.1</a> of
the FFmpeg audio/video toolkit has been released. Important changes in
this release include the VVC decoder reaching stable status, and
inclusion of support for MV-HEVC decoding (which is generated by
recent phones and VR headsets), as well as support for Vulkan encoding
with H264 and HEVC. See the announcement and <a
href="https://git.ffmpeg.org/gitweb/ffmpeg.git/shortlog/n7.1">changelog</a>
for full details.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992496/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 17:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Firefox 131.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992489/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/131.0/releasenotes/">Version
131.0</a> of the Firefox browser has been released.  Changes include the
ability to temporarily grant permissions to sites and a preview that pops
up when hovering over tabs.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992489/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 16:43:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992444/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (debian-security-support, nghttp2, and sqlite3), <b>Oracle</b> (cups-filters, kernel, and osbuild-composer), <b>SUSE</b> (openssl-3), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (bubblewrap, flatpak and python2.7, python3.5).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992444/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 12:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Four new stable kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992292/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/992294/">6.11.1</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/992295/">6.10.12</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/992296/">6.6.53</a>, and <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/992297/">6.1.112</a> stable kernels have been released.
Each contains important fixes and users of those series should upgrade.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992292/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 16:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tcl/Tk 9.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992284/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The most recent major release of the <a href="https://www.tcl.tk/">Tcl/Tk</a> language and graphical-user-interface toolkit, <a href="https://www.tcl-lang.org/software/tcltk/9.0.html">Tcl/Tk 9.0</a>, has been released, a mere 27 years after the <a href="http://www.tcl.tk/software/tcltk/8.0.html">8,0 major release</a> in 1997.  There have been plenty of releases in the interim, though, as can be seen in the <a href="https://wiki.tcl-lang.org/page/Tcl+chronology">Tcl chronology</a>.  The 9.0 release brings 64-bit data values, better Unicode support, the ability to use zip files as filesystems, a switch to use <tt>epoll()</tt> or <tt>kqueue()</tt> where they are available, SVG support in Tk, access to notifications and other desktop-platform services in Tk, and lots more.  For more information, see the release notes for Tcl and Tk that can be downloaded as Markdown files from the announcement page. (Thanks to Matt Bradley.)]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992284/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992281/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (cups-filters, net-snmp, and osbuild-composer), <b>Debian</b> (booth, cups, cups-filters, python-asyncssh, ruby-httparty, ruby-loofah, ruby-rails-html-sanitizer, tryton-server, unbound, and wireshark), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, cjson, cups, cups-browsed, libcupsfilters, and libppd), <b>Gentoo</b> (Apache HTTPD, Docker, HashiCorp Consul, IcedTea, nginx, tmux, and yt-dlp), <b>Mageia</b> (java-1.8.0-openjdk, java-11-openjdk, java-17-openjdk, &amp; java-latest-openjdk and libreoffice), <b>Red Hat</b> (git-lfs, grafana, and osbuild-composer), and <b>SUSE</b> (chromedriver, chromium, coredns, json-java-20240303, kernel, libmozjs-128-0, maven-archetype, python3, python312, and quagga).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992281/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Arch Linux getting support from Valve</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992194/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Arch Linux project has announced that Valve will be helping the
distribution with a couple of important initiatives:
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
Valve is generously providing backing for two 
critical projects that will have a huge impact on our distribution: a 
build service infrastructure and a secure signing enclave. By supporting 
work on a freelance basis for these topics, Valve enables us to work on 
them without being limited solely by the free time of our volunteers.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992194/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 07:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.12-rc1</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992185/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/992184/">released 6.12-rc1</a> and closed the
merge window for this release.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Despite conference travel (both for me and several maintainers),
	things seemed to go mostly fairly normally. There's a couple of
	notable new features in here: For one thing, PREEMPT_RT is now
	mainlined and enabled as a config option (you do need to enable
	"EXPERT" to get the question). For another, sched_ext also got
	merged.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992185/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 06:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Górny: The perils of transition to 64-bit time_t</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992120/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Michał Górny <a
href="https://blogs.gentoo.org/mgorny/2024/09/28/the-perils-of-transition-to-64-bit-time_t/">describes
the challenges</a> involved in transitioning Gentoo to year-2038-safe time
representations:
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	There is a general agreement that the way forward is to change
	time_t to a 64-bit type. Musl has already switched to that, glibc
	supports it as an option. A number of other distributions such as
	Debian have taken the leap and switched. Unfortunately,
	source-based distributions such as Gentoo don't have it that
	easy. So we are still debating the issue and experimenting, trying
	to figure out a maximally safe upgrade path for our users.
<p>
	Unfortunately, that's nowhere near trivial. Above all, we are
	talking about a breaking ABI change.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992120/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 07:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992030/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (chromium and trafficserver), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium), <b>Mageia</b> (apache-mod_jk, gnome-shell, kernel, kmod-xtables-addons, and kmod-virtualbox, kernel-linus, and python3), <b>Oracle</b> (container-tools:ol8, dovecot, emacs, expat, firefox, git-lfs, gtk3, kernel, nano, net-snmp, osbuild-composer, python3, python3.11, python3.12, ruby:3.3, and virt:ol and virt-devel:rhel), <b>Slackware</b> (boost), <b>SUSE</b> (kernel), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (configobj, cups, cups-browsed, cups-filters, libcupsfilters, and libppd).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992030/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 13:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Remote exploit of CUPS</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991929/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Security researcher Simone Margaritelli 
<a href="https://www.evilsocket.net/2024/09/26/Attacking-UNIX-systems-via-CUPS-Part-I/">
has reported</a> a new vulnerability in 
<a href="https://openprinting.github.io/cups/">
CUPS</a>, the software that many Linux systems use to manage printers and print jobs. Margaritelli describes the impact of the attack by saying:
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
A remote unauthenticated attacker can silently replace existing printers' (or install new ones) IPP urls with a malicious one, resulting in arbitrary command execution (on the computer) when a print job is started (from that computer).
</blockquote>

<p>
The vulnerability relies on a few related problems in CUPS libraries and utilities; versions before 2.0.1 or 2.1b1 (depending on the component) may be affected.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991929/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>PostgreSQL 17 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991904/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://www.postgresql.org/about/news/postgresql-17-released-2936/">Version
17</a> of the <a href="https://www.postgresql.org/">PostgreSQL</a> database has been released.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
This release of PostgreSQL adds significant overall performance gains,
including an overhauled memory management implementation for vacuum,
optimizations to storage access and improvements for high concurrency
workloads, speedups in bulk loading and exports, and query execution
improvements for indexes. PostgreSQL 17 has features that benefit
brand new workloads and critical systems alike, such as additions to
the developer experience with the SQL/JSON JSON_TABLE command, and
enhancements to logical replication that simplify management of high
availability workloads and major version upgrades.
</blockquote>

<p>LWN recently <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/984599/">covered</a>
some of the interesting new features and security enhancements in
PostgreSQL 17.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991904/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 15:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Uniting for Internet Freedom: Tor Project &amp; Tails Join Forces (Tor blog)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991899/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The online-privacy-focused <a href="https://www.torproject.org/">Tor
project</a> has <a
href="https://blog.torproject.org/tor-tails-join-forces/">announced</a>
that it has "<q>joined forces and merged operations</q>" with the <a
href="https://tails.net/">Tails OS</a> Linux distribution.

<blockquote class="bq">
Countering the threat of global mass surveillance and censorship to a free Internet, Tor and Tails provide essential tools to help people around the world stay safe online. By joining forces, these two privacy advocates will pool their resources to focus on what matters most: ensuring that activists, journalists, other at-risk and everyday users will have access to improved digital security tools.
<p>
In late 2023, Tails approached the Tor Project with the idea of merging operations. Tails had outgrown its existing structure. Rather than expanding Tails's operational capacity on their own and putting more stress on Tails workers, merging with the Tor Project, with its larger and established operational framework, offered a solution. By joining forces, the Tails team can now focus on their core mission of maintaining and improving Tails OS, exploring more and complementary use cases while benefiting from the larger organizational structure of The Tor Project.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991899/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 15:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991897/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (container-tools:rhel8, dovecot, emacs, expat, git-lfs, go-toolset:rhel8, golang, grafana, grafana-pcp, gtk3, kernel, kernel-rt, nano, python3, python3.11, python3.12, and virt:rhel and virt-devel:rhel), <b>Debian</b> (mediawiki and puredata), <b>Fedora</b> (chisel), <b>Mageia</b> (glib2.0, gtk+2.0 and gtk+3.0, and python-astropy), <b>Red Hat</b> (git-lfs, grafana, grafana-pcp, kernel, and kernel-rt), <b>SUSE</b> (kubernetes1.24, kubernetes1.25, kubernetes1.26, kubernetes1.27, kubernetes1.28, opensc, and python36), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (apparmor, apr, ca-certificates, linux, linux-aws, linux-kvm, linux-lts-xenial, linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-5.15, linux-raspi, openjpeg2, ruby-rack, and tomcat8, tomcat9).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991897/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 14:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>