<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 09:46:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 09:48:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.10-rc1</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/975145/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/975144/">released
6.10-rc1</a> and closed the merge window for this release.  For reasons
that have not been spelled out, the codename for the release has been
changed to "Baby Opossum Posse".]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/975145/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 22:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Eight weekend stable kernel updates</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/975072/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/975073/">6.9.2</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/975074/">6.8.11</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/975075/">6.6.32</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/975076/">6.1.92</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/975078/">5.15.160</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/975079/">5.10.218</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/975077/">5.4.277</a>, and <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/975080/">4.19.315</a>
stable kernel updates have all been released. Each contains an
important set of fixes. Users of those kernels should upgrade.</p>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/975072/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:07:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>BitKeeper, Linux, and licensing disputes: How Linus wrote Git in 14 days 
(Graphite blog)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974914/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a
href="https://graphite.dev/blog/bitkeeper-linux-story-of-git-creation">This
Graphite blog post</a> retells the history of the BitKeeper fiasco and the
dawn of the Git era.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	When we think of history, we often romanticize it as being born of
	a sudden stroke of inspiration. But the creation of git shows the
	far harsher reality of invention: a slowly escalating disagreement
	over a license; the need for a scrappy backup solution to unblock
	work; and then continued polishing and iteration through years and
	years, led not by the inventor, but rather a community.
</blockquote>
<p>
For those who weren't around in those days, a perusal of the LWN coverage
from the time might be of interest too, including:
<p>
<ul>
<li> <a href="https://lwn.net/1998/1015/kernel.php3">Our first mention of BitKeeper</a>
     in October 1998
<li> <a href="https://lwn.net/1999/features/BitKeeper.php3">Not quite open source</a>,
     1999
<li> <a href="https://lwn.net/2002/0207/kernel.php3">Linus tries out BitKeeper</a>, 2002
<li> <a href="https://lwn.net/2002/0425/">The free software community and proprietary
     packages</a>, 2002
<li> <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/130746/">The kernel and BitKeeper part ways</a>,
     2005
<li> <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/132938/">How Tridge reverse engineered
     BitKeeper</a>, 2005
<li> <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/131657/">The guts of Git</a>, 2005
</ul>
<p>
...and a lot more for those who care to search for it.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974914/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 13:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974913/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, libreoffice, and thunderbird), <b>Red Hat</b> (.NET 7.0, .NET 8.0, gdk-pixbuf2, git-lfs, glibc, python3, and xorg-x11-server-Xwayland), <b>SUSE</b> (firefox, opensc, and ucode-intel), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (cjson and gnome-remote-desktop).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974913/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 13:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>KDE Gear 24.05.0</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974708/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://kde.org/">KDE Project</a> has <a
href="https://kde.org/announcements/gear/24.05.0/">announced</a> the
release of KDE Gear 24.05.0, with new features and updates for the
more than 200 <a href="https://apps.kde.org/">applications</a> that
are part of the project. In addition to new versions of the <a href="https://apps.kde.org/dolphin/">Dolphin</a>
file manager, <a href="https://kdenlive.org/">Kdenlive</a> video
editor, and <a href="https://apps.kde.org/elisa/">Elisa</a> music player, this
release includes five applications new to KDE Gear: the <a
href="https://apps.kde.org/audex">Audex</a> CD-ripper application,
an application <a href="https://apps.kde.org/accessibilityinspector">Accessibility
Inspector</a>, the <a href="https://apps.kde.org/francis">Francis</a>
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomodoro_Technique">Pomodoro</a> timer, <a
href="https://apps.kde.org/kalm">Kalm</a> to teach breathing techniques, and a <a
href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sokoban">Sokoban</a>-like game
called <a href="https://apps.kde.org/skladnik">Skladnik</a>. See the
<a href="https://kde.org/announcements/changelogs/gear/24.05.0/">full
changelog</a> for a complete list of changes.</p>

<p> </p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974708/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 14:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974824/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (chromium), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, libxml2, pgadmin4, and python-libgravatar), <b>Mageia</b> (ghostscript), <b>Red Hat</b> (389-ds:1.4, ansible-core, bind and dhcp, container-tools:rhel8, edk2, exempi, fence-agents, freeglut, frr, ghostscript, glibc, gmp, go-toolset:rhel8, grafana, grub2, gstreamer1-plugins-bad-free, gstreamer1-plugins-base, gstreamer1-plugins-good, harfbuzz, httpd:2.4, idm:DL1, idm:DL1 and idm:client modules, kernel, kernel-rt, krb5, LibRaw, libreoffice, libsndfile, libssh, libtiff, libX11, libxml2, libXpm, linux-firmware, motif, mutt, openssh, osbuild and osbuild-composer, pam, pcp, pcs, perl-Convert-ASN1, perl-CPAN, perl:5.32, pki-core:10.6 and pki-deps:10.6 modules, pmix, poppler, postgresql-jdbc, python-dns, python-jinja2, python-pillow, python27:2.7, python3.11, python3.11-cryptography, python3.11-urllib3, python39:3.9 and python39-devel:3.9 modules, qt5-qtbase, resource-agents, squashfs-tools, sssd, systemd, tigervnc, tomcat, traceroute, varnish:6, virt:rhel and virt-devel:rhel modules, vorbis-tools, webkit2gtk3, xorg-x11-server, xorg-x11-server-Xwayland, and zziplib), <b>SUSE</b> (chromium, perl, postgresql14, and python-sqlparse), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (klibc, linux-aws-hwe, openssl, and vlc).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974824/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 13:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for May 16, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973073/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for May 16, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973073/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 03:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The state of the page in 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973565/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The advent of the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/849538/">folio</a> structure to
describe groups of pages has been one of the most fundamental
transformations within the kernel in recent years.  Since the folio
transition affects many subsystems, it is fitting that the subject was
covered at the beginning of the 2024 <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a> in a joint session of the
storage, filesystem, and memory-management tracks.  Matthew Wilcox used the
session to review the work that has been done in this area and to discuss
what comes next.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973565/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 13:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Portable LLMs with llamafile</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971195/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Large language models (LLMs) have been the subject of much discussion and
scrutiny recently. Of particular interest to open-source enthusiasts are the
problems with running LLMs on one's own hardware — especially when doing so
requires NVIDIA's proprietary CUDA toolkit, which remains unavailable in many
environments.
Mozilla has developed
<a href="https://github.com/Mozilla-Ocho/llamafile">llamafile</a> as a
potential solution to these problems. Llamafile can compile LLM weights
into portable, native executables for easy integration, archival, or
distribution. These executables can take advantage of supported GPUs when
present, but do not require them.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971195/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Some 6.9 development statistics</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972605/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The 6.9 kernel was <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-kernel/CAHk-=whnKYL-WARzrZhVTZ8RP3WZc24C9_DT7JMJooONNT2udQ@mail.gmail.com/">released</a>
on May&nbsp;12 after a typical nine-week development cycle.  Once again,
this is a major release containing a lot of changes and new features.  Our
merge-window summaries (<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/965141/">part&nbsp;1</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/965541/">part&nbsp;2</a>) covered those changes; now that
the development cycle is complete, the time has come to look at where all
that work came from — and to introduce a new and experimental LWN feature
for readers interested in this kind of information.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972605/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 17:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Managing expectations with a contributions and credit policy</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971817/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Maintainers of open-source projects sometimes have disagreements with
contributors over how contributions are reviewed, modified, merged, and
credited. A written policy describing how contributions are handled can
help maintainers set reasonable expectations for potential contributors.
In turn, that can make the maintainer's job easier because it can help
reduce a source of friction in the project.  A guide to help create this
kind of policy for a project has recently been developed.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971817/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 15:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Debian dismisses AI-contributions policy</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972331/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In April, the Gentoo Linux project <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/970072/">banned</a> the use of
generative AI/ML tools due to copyright, ethical, and quality
concerns. This means contributors cannot use tools like ChatGPT or GitHub Copilot to
creating content for the distribution such as code, documentation,
bug reports, forum posts. A proposal for Debian to adopt a similar
policy revealed a distinct lack of love for those kinds of tools,
though it would also seem few contributors support
banning them outright. </p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972331/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 16:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Another push for sched_ext</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972710/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The extensible scheduler class (or "sched_ext") is a comprehensive
framework that enables the implementation of CPU schedulers as a set of BPF
programs that can be loaded at run time.  Despite having attracted a fair
amount of interest from the development community, sched_ext has run into
considerable opposition and seems far from acceptance into the mainline.
The posting by Tejun Heo of <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-kernel/20240501151312.635565-1-tj@kernel.org/">a new
version of the sched_ext series</a> at the beginning of May has restarted
this long-running discussion, but it is not clear what the end result will
be.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972710/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 14:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Alpine Linux 3.20.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974576/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://alpinelinux.org/posts/Alpine-3.20.0-released.html">Version
3.20.0</a> of the <a href="https://alpinelinux.org/">Alpine Linux</a>
distribution has been released with initial support for 64-bit
RISC-V. Other important changes include updates to <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/966187/">GNOME&nbsp;46</a>, 
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/963851/">KDE&nbsp;Plasma&nbsp;6</a>, and replacing Redis with Valkey due to Redis's
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/966631/">adoption</a> of a non-free
license model. See the <a
href="https://wiki.alpinelinux.org/wiki/Release_Notes_for_Alpine_3.20.0">release
notes</a> for more on this release.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974576/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 15:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974572/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (webkit2gtk), <b>Fedora</b> (kernel), <b>Mageia</b> (chromium-browser-stable, djvulibre, gdk-pixbuf2.0, nss &amp; firefox, postgresql15 &amp; postgresql13, python-pymongo, python-sqlparse, stb, thunderbird, and vim), <b>Red Hat</b> (go-toolset:rhel8, nodejs, and varnish:6), <b>SUSE</b> (gitui, glibc, and kernel), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (libspreadsheet-parseexcel-perl, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.15, linux-gke, linux-gcp, python-idna, and thunderbird).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974572/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 13:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>AlmaLinux forms engineering steering committee</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974488/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://almalinux.org/">AlmaLinux</a> project has <a
href="https://almalinux.org/blog/2024-05-21-introducing-alesco/">announced</a>
the formation of the AlmaLinux Engineering
Steering Committee (ALESCo):</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
[It] is dedicated to guiding the technical direction of the
AlmaLinux distribution on a day-to-day basis within the guidelines set
forth by the board, ensuring its robustness, reliability,
sustainability, and relevance in the open-source ecosystem. ALESCo
will work collaboratively with, and oversee relevant technical-focused
Special Interest Groups (SIGs) to achieve these goals. It is "air
traffic control" for engineering matters.
</blockquote>

<p>The initial members of ALESCo appointed by the AlmaLinux OS
Foundation board are Andrew Lukoshko, Ben Thomas, Cody Robertson,
Elkhan Mammadli, Jonathan Wright, and Neal Gompa. The <a
href="https://wiki.almalinux.org/alesco.html">AlmaLinux Wiki</a> has
more information on the committee's activities and how to get involved.</p>

<p> </p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974488/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 16:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974450/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (firefox, nodejs, and thunderbird), <b>Fedora</b> (uriparser), <b>Oracle</b> (firefox and thunderbird), <b>Slackware</b> (mariadb), <b>SUSE</b> (cairo, gdk-pixbuf, krb5, libosinfo, postgresql14, and python310), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (firefox, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.15, and linux-azure).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974450/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 12:52:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Axboe: What&apos;s new with io_uring in 6.10</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974341/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Jens Axboe <a
href="https://github.com/axboe/liburing/wiki/What's-new-with-io_uring-in-6.10">describes
the new io_uring features</a> that will be a part of the 6.10 kernel
release.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Bundles are multiple buffers used in a single operation. On the
	receive side, this means a single receive may utilize multiple
	buffers, reducing the roundtrip through the networking stack from N
	per N buffers to just a single one. On the send side, this also
	enables better handling of how an application deals with sends from
	a socket, eliminating the need to serialize sends on a single
	socket. Bundles work with provided buffers, hence this feature also
	adds support for provided buffers for send operations.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974341/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 13:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974339/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (bind9, chromium, and thunderbird), <b>Fedora</b> (buildah, chromium, firefox, mingw-python-werkzeug, and suricata), <b>Mageia</b> (golang), <b>Oracle</b> (firefox and nodejs:20), <b>Red Hat</b> (firefox, httpd:2.4, nodejs, and thunderbird), and <b>SUSE</b> (firefox, git-cliff, and ucode-intel).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974339/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 12:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>