<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 20:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 21:33:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Four Friday stable kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1011263/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Greg Kroah-Hartman has released another four stable kernels:
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1011264/">6.13.4</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1011265/">6.12.16</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1011266/">6.6.79</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1011267/">6.1.129</a>. As usual, all users are advised to upgrade.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1011263/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 14:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1011262/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (bind, bind9.16, and mysql:8.0), <b>Debian</b> (chromium, djoser, libtasn1-6, and postgresql-13), <b>Fedora</b> (python3.12 and vim), <b>Red Hat</b> (libpq, postgresql, postgresql:13, postgresql:15, and postgresql:16), <b>Slackware</b> (ark), <b>SUSE</b> (brise, chromium, emacs, google-osconfig-agent, grafana, grub2, helm, kernel, openssh, openssl-1_1, ovmf, postgresql13, postgresql14, postgresql15, and postgresql17), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (gnutls28, libtasn1-6, openssl, python3.10, python3.12, python3.8, and webkit2gtk).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1011262/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 14:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Linus on Rust and the kernel&apos;s DMA layer</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1011197/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[At the end of January we ran <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1006805/">this article</a>
on the discussions around a set of Rust bindings for the kernel's
DMA-mapping layer.  Many pixels have been expended on the topic since
across the net, most recently in <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/CANiq72m-R0tOakf=j7BZ78jDHdy=9-fvZbAT8j91Je2Bxy0sFg@mail.gmail.com">this
sprawling email thread</a>.  Linus Torvalds has now <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/CAHk-=wgLbz1Bm8QhmJ4dJGSmTuV5w_R0Gwvg5kHrYr4Ko9dUHQ@mail.gmail.com">made
his feelings known</a> on the topic:
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	You are not forced to take any Rust code, or care about any Rust
	code in the DMA code. You can ignore it.
<p>
	But "ignore the Rust side" automatically also means that you don't
	have any *say* on the Rust side.
<p>
	You can't have it both ways. You can't say "I want to have nothing
	to do with Rust", and then in the very next sentence say "And that
	means that the Rust code that I will ignore cannot use the C
	interfaces I maintain".
</blockquote>
<p>
The code in question seems highly likely to be merged for the 6.15 release.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1011197/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 13:43:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rust 1.85.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1011122/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2025/02/20/Rust-1.85.0.html">Version
1.85.0</a> of the Rust language has been released.  Changes in the release
include support for async closures, some convenience iterators for tuples,
and a number of stabilized APIs.  The headline feature, though, is that
this release stabilizes the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1002456/">Rust 2024
edition</a>, described as "<q>the largest edition we have released</q>".
The <a
href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/edition-guide/rust-2024/index.html">2024
edition guide</a> has a detailed listing of all the changes that were
incorporated this time around.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1011122/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 17:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1011056/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (mosquitto), <b>Fedora</b> (gnutls, kernel, libtasn1, microcode_ctl, openssh, python3.10, python3.11, and python3.9), <b>Red Hat</b> (bind, bind9.16, buildah, container-tools:rhel8, podman, and redis:6), <b>Slackware</b> (libxml2), <b>SUSE</b> (dcmtk, google-osconfig-agent, java-17-openj9, kubernetes1.30-apiserver, kubernetes1.31-apiserver, openssh, and ruby3.4-rubygem-grpc), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux, linux-lowlatency and linux-aws, linux-azure, linux-gcp, linux-oracle, linux-raspi, linux-realtime).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1011056/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 14:17:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for February 13, 2025</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1008279/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Inside this week's LWN.net Weekly Edition:
        <p>
        <ul>
<li> <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1008279/">Front</a>: BPF load-time checking; IRQ suspension; Rust for Linux; Rewriting coreutils; Selfish contributors; emlearn.
            <li> <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1008281/">Briefs</a>: RfL policy; OpenWrt 24.10.0; Arti 1.4.0; LibreOffice 25.2; OpenInfra; Plasma 6.3; Attacks on Codeberg; Quotes; ...
            <li> <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1008282/">Announcements</a>: Newsletters, conferences, security updates, patches, and more.
            </ul>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1008279/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Milliwatt machine learning with emlearn</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1009011/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[While large language models and the expensive hardware they require are all
the rage now, other areas of artificial intelligence work within much more
constrained hardware environments. At <a
href="https://fosdem.org/2025/">FOSDEM&nbsp;2025</a>, Jon Nordby presented
his open-source machine-learning inference engine for microcontrollers,
named <a href="https://emlearn.readthedocs.io">emlearn</a>. The project
also boasts bindings for <a href="https://micropython.org">MicroPython</a>,
thus making machine-learning applications even more accessible.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1009011/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 17:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Rewriting essential Linux packages in Rust</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007907/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Most Linux systems depend on a suite of core utilities that the <a
href="https://www.gnu.org/">GNU Project</a> started development on
decades ago and are, of course, written in C. At <a
href="https://fosdem.org/2025/">FOSDEM&nbsp;2025</a>, Sylvestre Ledru
made the case in <a
href="https://fosdem.org/2025/schedule/event/fosdem-2025-6196-rewriting-the-future-of-the-linux-essential-packages-in-rust-/">his
main stage talk</a> that modern systems require safer, more
maintainable tools. Over the past few years, Ledru has led the charge
of rewriting the <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/coreutils/">GNU
Core Utilities</a> (coreutils) in Rust, as the MIT-licensed <a
href="https://github.com/uutils/">uutils</a> project. The goal is to
offer what he said are more secure, and more performant drop-in
replacements for the tools Linux users depend on. At FOSDEM, Ledru
announced that the uutils project is setting its sights even
higher.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007907/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 12:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Smarter IRQ suspension in the networking stack</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1008399/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[High-performance networking is a highly tuned activity; the amount of time
available to deal with each packet may be measured in nanoseconds, so care
must be taken to avoid anything that might slow the process down.
Recently, there has been a fair amount of attention given to <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20241021015311.95468-1-jdamato@fastly.com/">a patch set
merged for 6.13</a> that, it is claimed, can improve processing efficiency
(and, thus, power savings)
in data centers by as much as 30%.  The change itself, contributed by Joe
Damato and Martin Karsten, is a relatively small tweak to existing
optimization techniques; it shows just how much care is needed to optimize
a high-bandwidth server.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1008399/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 15:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Maintainer opinions on Rust-for-Linux</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007921/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Miguel Ojeda gave
<a href="https://fosdem.org/2025/schedule/event/fosdem-2025-6507-rust-for-linux/">
a keynote</a> at
<a href="https://fosdem.org/2025/">
FOSDEM&nbsp;2025</a> about the history of the
<a href="https://rust-for-linux.com/">
Rust-for-Linux</a>
project, and the current attitude of people in the kernel community toward the
experiment. Unlike his
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/952029/">
usual talks</a>, this talk didn't focus so much on the current
state of the project, but rather on discussing history
and predictions for the future. He ended up presenting quotes from more than 30
people involved in kernel development about what they thought of the project and
expected going forward.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007921/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 17:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Improved load-time checking for BPF kfuncs</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007947/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/982077/">BPF verifier</a> is charged with the
challenging task of ensuring that a BPF program is safe for the kernel to
run before that program is loaded.  Among many other concerns, the verifier
must ensure that any kfuncs (kernel functions that have been exported to
BPF programs) are called with the correct parameters and from the right
context.  The "context" part of that enforcement is showing its age in ways
that are hurting performance; Juntong Deng has been working on
infrastructure to provide finer-grained control over when a kfunc can be
called.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007947/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 15:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The selfish contributor revisited</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007426/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Open source is often described as a "gift economy"&mdash;an
ecosystem where contributors are motivated by a desire to make the
world a better place. That is, sometimes, true. However, James
Bottomley used his <a
href="https://fosdem.org/2025/schedule/event/fosdem-2025-6540-the-selfish-contributor-revisited/">main
track slot</a> at <a href="https://fosdem.org/2025/">FOSDEM 2025</a>,
on February&nbsp;1, to make the case that it is better to bank on the
selfish motivations of individuals to drive community success than to
rely on their altruism.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007426/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 15:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mozilla announces leadership updates and next chapter</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010922/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Mark Surman, president of the <a
href="https://www.mozilla.org/">Mozilla Corporation</a>, has <a
href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/mozilla-leadership-growth-planning-updates/">announced</a>
leadership updates for Mozilla. This includes a Mozilla Leadership
Council made up of executives from each Mozilla organization, and new
board chairs for the not-for-profit <a
href="https://foundation.mozilla.org/">Mozilla Foundation</a>, the
Mozilla Corporation, and <a
href="https://www.mozilla.ai/">Mozilla.ai</a>. The announcement also
indicates a desire to further "<q>diversify</q>" Mozilla's focus:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
We've recognized that Mozilla faces major headwinds in terms of both
financial growth and mission impact. While Firefox remains the core of
what we do, we also need to take steps to diversify: investing in
privacy-respecting advertising to grow new revenue in the near term;
developing trustworthy, open source AI to ensure technical and product
relevance in the mid term; and creating online fundraising campaigns
that will draw a bigger circle of supporters over the long
run. Mozilla's impact and survival depend on us simultaneously
strengthening Firefox AND finding new sources of revenue AND
manifesting our mission in fresh ways. That is why we're working hard
on all of these fronts.
</blockquote>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010922/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 21:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mesa 25.0.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010898/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a
href="https://lists.freedesktop.org/archives/mesa-dev/2025-February/226464.html">Version
25.0.0</a> of the Mesa graphics library has been released.  "<q>The flashiest addition is probably the support for Vulkan 1.4 by Anv (Intel),
Asahi (Apple), Lavapipe (software), NVK (NVIDIA), PanVK (Mali), RADV (AMD),
and Turnip (Qualcomm).

Users can expect the usual flurry of improvements across all drivers and
components.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010898/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 17:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>RISC-V and Fedora: All Aboard! (Fedora Magazine)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010857/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/">Fedora Project</a> has <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/risc-v-and-fedora-all-aboard/">announced</a>
two milestones in its journey to supporting the RISC-V architecture: a
dedicated RISC-V Koji build system instance is live in the Fedora data
center, and <a
href="https://dl.fedoraproject.org/pub/alt/risc-v/release/41/">Fedora
41-based images</a> are now available for RISC-V. It is also <a
href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Architectures/RISC-V/QEMU">possible</a>
to run Fedora RISC-V images using QEMU for those without supported
hardware.</p>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010857/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Lange: The secret maze of Debian images</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010855/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Debian Developer Thomas Lange has written a <a
href="https://blog.fai-project.org/posts/cdimages-maze/">blog post</a>
in the attempt to help users find the right Debian image for their
systems.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
It's difficult to find the right Debian image. We have thousands of
ISO files and cloud images and we support multiple CPU architectures
and several download methods. The directory structure of our main
image server is like a maze, and our web pages for downloading are
also confusing.
</blockquote>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010855/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010853/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (gcc-toolset-14-gcc, nodejs:18, and nodejs:22), <b>Fedora</b> (bootc), <b>Gentoo</b> (OpenSSH), <b>Oracle</b> (doxygen, libxml2, mingw-glib2, and NetworkManager), <b>Red Hat</b> (bind, bind9.16, bind9.18, kernel, kernel-rt, mysql, and mysql:8.0), <b>Slackware</b> (openssh), <b>SUSE</b> (buildah, emacs, glibc, google-osconfig-agent, grub2, java-11-openj9, kernel, netty, netty-tcnative, openssh, openvswitch, podman, and ucode-intel), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (atril, libsndfile, libtasn1-6, openssh, python-virtualenv, and symfony).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010853/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Pi-hole v6 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010682/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://pi-hole.net/">Pi-hole</a> v6 has been <a
href="https://pi-hole.net/blog/2025/02/18/introducing-pi-hole-v6/#page-content">released</a>. The
latest version of the popular ad-blocking software sports a redesigned
user interface, has support for subscribing to allowlists, and brings
a new REST API and embedded web server. Its Docker/OCI image is now
based on <a href="https://www.alpinelinux.org/">Alpine Linux</a>
rather than <a href="https://debian.org/">Debian</a> to reduce image
size. See the announcement for guidance on upgrading existing Pi-hole
installations.</p>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010682/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 19:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A milestone for reproducible openSUSE</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010629/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Reproducible-openSUSE project has <a
href="https://news.opensuse.org/2025/02/18/rbos-project-hits-milestone/">announced</a>
that it has created a usable version of openSUSE with 100% reproducible
packages.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	[Bernhard] Wiedemann took on this 4-month-long project to create a
	fork of openSUSE that has 100% bit-reproducible packages. So far
	ring0 (aka bootstrap) and ring1 with 3,300 software packages have
	all successfully been patched and tested.
</blockquote>
<p>
This build is not yet recommended for production use, though.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010629/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 14:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Stable kernel 6.12.15</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010624/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1010623/">6.12.15</a> stable kernel update has been
fast-tracked to release.  It seems that its predecessor contains <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/CAJMi0nTbyi6VGTmmZ43wYWwJWur0XPtuswZ_5UaXB+S6Z=Mo6A@mail.gmail.com">a
regression in the XFS filesystem</a> that can lead to kernel crashes.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010624/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 14:43:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010621/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (gnutls28, openssh, and pam-pkcs11), <b>Mageia</b> (microcode and python-cryptography), <b>Oracle</b> (nodejs:18, nodejs:20, and rsync), <b>Red Hat</b> (gcc, nodejs:20, and nodejs:22), <b>SUSE</b> (emacs, kernel, openvswitch, and ucode-intel), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (Docker).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010621/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 14:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Three stable kernels under the sky</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010352/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Greg Kroah-Hartman has released three more stable kernels:
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1010354/">6.13.3</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1010356/">6.12.14</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1010357/">6.6.78</a>.
There was a bit of confusion that resulted in the patch for
<a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord/?id=CVE-2025-21687">CVE 2025-21687</a>
getting applied twice — but that doesn't result in any problems for users of the
kernel, just a bit of extra noise in the CVE database, so Kroah-Hartman has
decided to leave the releases as-is instead of rushing another point release.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010352/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 14:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010328/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (container-tools:rhel8, gcc, libxml2, nodejs:18, and nodejs:20), <b>Debian</b> (freerdp2, golang-glog, trafficserver, and tryton-client), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, krb5, libheif, microcode_ctl, nginx, nginx-mod-fancyindex, nginx-mod-modsecurity, nginx-mod-naxsi, nginx-mod-vts, and webkitgtk), <b>Mageia</b> (ffmpeg, golang, postgresql13 and postgresql15, and python-zipp), <b>Oracle</b> (container-tools:ol8, gcc, gcc-toolset-13-gcc, gcc-toolset-14-gcc, kernel, libxml2, and nodejs:20), <b>Red Hat</b> (gcc, idm:DL1, and ipa), <b>SUSE</b> (buildah, chromium, glibc, kernel, kernel-firmware-all-20250206, libecpg6, postgresql15, python, python3, python311, and ruby3.4-rubygem-rack), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (intel-microcode).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010328/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 12:35:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.14-rc3</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010232/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1010231/">6.14-rc3</a> kernel prepatch is out for
testing; the announcement, for unknown reasons, went only to the
linux-btrfs list.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	So the first few weeks of the 6.14 release development were
	smaller-than-usual, but rc3 is actually right in line with normal
	releases at this point. Probably just timing of pull requests, and
	we'll see how next week goes. But nothing looks worrisome.
</blockquote>
<p>
Along with the usual stream of fixes, this release includes the "<a
href="https://git.kernel.org/linus/35fa2d88ca94">faux bus</a>", designed
for simple drivers that just need some sort of virtual bus to be associated
with; this bus come with <a
href="https://git.kernel.org/linus/78418f300d3">Rust bindings</a> from the
outset.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010232/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 23:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>