<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 19:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 5 Dec 2024 19:24:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Let&apos;s Encrypt sets date for ending OSCP support</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000941/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In July, Let's Encrypt <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/982965/">announced</a> it was ending
support "<q>as soon as possible</q>" for the <a
href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_Certificate_Status_Protocol">Online
Certificate Status Protocol</a> (OCSP) in favor of <a
href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Certificate_revocation_list">Certificate
Revocation Lists</a> (CRLs) due to privacy concerns. The organization
has now <a
href="https://letsencrypt.org/2024/12/05/ending-ocsp/">announced</a>
that it has set a timeline, and will be turning off its OCSP
responders on August&nbsp;6, 2025. There is additional action required
for Let's Encrypt users who use the OSCP Must Staple Extension:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>As of January 30, 2025, issuance requests that include the OCSP
Must Staple extension will fail, unless the requesting account has
previously issued a certificate containing the OCSP Must Staple
extension.</p>

<p>As of May 7, all issuance requests that include the OCSP Must
Staple extension will fail, including renewals. Please change your
ACME client configuration to not request the extension.</p>
</blockquote>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000941/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 19:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>‘Tis the Season for COSMIC Alpha 4! (System76 Blog)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000927/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>System76 has <a
href="https://blog.system76.com/post/cosmic-alpha-4">announced</a> the
fourth alpha release of its Rust-based <a
href="https://system76.com/cosmic/">COSMIC desktop</a>. New features
in this version include the ability to set default applications,
region and language settings, a new Accessibility applet, as well as
<a href="https://github.com/pop-os/cosmic-comp/issues/510">support for
variable refresh rate</a> (VRR) in the cosmic-comp compositor and the
display settings tool. See the blog post for a full list of fixes and
performance improvements. LWN <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/984638/">covered</a> the first alpha
release in August.</p>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000927/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mozilla&apos;s new branding strategy</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000880/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Mozilla <a
href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/mozilla-brand-next-era-of-tech/">would
appear to have concluded</a> that the solution to its problems is an
extensive rebranding effort:
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	We teamed up with global branding powerhouse Jones Knowles Ritchie
	(JKR) to revamp our brand and revitalize our intentions across our
	entire ecosystem. At the heart of this transformation is making
	sure people know Mozilla for its broader impact, as well as
	Firefox. Our new brand strategy and expression embody our role as a
	leader in digital rights and innovation, putting people over
	profits through privacy-preserving products, open-source developer
	tools, and community-building efforts.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000880/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Stable kernels 6.12.2, 6.11.11, and 4.19.325</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000871/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Greg Kroah-Hartman has released the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1000872/">6.12.2</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1000873/">6.11.11</a>, and <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1000874/">4.19.325</a> stable kernels.  Note that both
6.11.11 and 4.19.325 are the last kernels in those series, "<q>please move
off to a newer kernel version</q>".  In the 4.19.325 release notice, he has
a rather longer-than-usual message, including:

<blockquote class="bq">
As a "fun" proof that this one is finished (and that any company saying
they care about it really should have their statements validated with
facts), I looked at the "unfixed" CVEs from this kernel release.
Currently it is a list 983 CVEs long, too long to list here.
<p>
You can verify it yourself by cloning the vulns.git repo at
git.kernel.org and running:
<pre>
	./scripts/strak v4.19.325
</pre>
Note, this does NOT count the hardware CVEs which kernel.org does not
track, and many are sill unfixed in this kernel branch.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000871/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 14:20:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000870/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (thunderbird, tuned, and webkitgtk), <b>Mageia</b> (python-aiohttp and qemu), <b>Oracle</b> (container-tools:ol8, firefox, java-1.8.0-openjdk, java-11-openjdk, kernel, kernel:4.18.0, krb5, pam, postgresql:16, python-tornado, python3:3.6.8, thunderbird, tigervnc, tuned, and webkit2gtk3), <b>Red Hat</b> (bzip2, postgresql, postgresql:13, postgresql:15, postgresql:16, python-tornado, and ruby:3.1), <b>Slackware</b> (python3), <b>SUSE</b> (postgresql, postgresql16, postgresql17, postgresql13, postgresql14, postgresql15, python-python-multipart, and python3), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (python-django and recutils).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000870/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 14:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for November 21, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998144/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for November 21, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998144/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] RVKMS and Rust KMS bindings</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/997850/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[At the <a
href="https://indico.freedesktop.org/event/6/">2024 X.Org Developers
Conference</a> (XDC), Lyude Paul gave a talk on the work she has been doing
as part of the <a href="https://gitlab.freedesktop.org/drm/nova">Nova
project</a>, which is an <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/990736/">effort build an NVIDIA
GPU driver in Rust</a>.  She wanted to provide an introduction to <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20240930233257.1189730-36-lyude@redhat.com/">RVKMS</a>, which
is being used to develop Rust kernel mode setting (KMS)
bindings; RVKMS is a port of the <a href="https://docs.kernel.org/gpu/vkms.html">virtual KMS</a> (VKMS)
driver to Rust.  In addition, she wanted to give her opinion on Rust, and why she
thinks it is
a "<q>game-changer for the kernel</q>", noting that the reasons are not
related to the oft-mentioned, "headline" feature of the language: memory
safety.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/997850/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 15:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Book review: Run Your Own Mail Server</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998153/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The most common piece of advice given to users who ask about
running their own mail server is <em><a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/987566/">don't</a></em>. Setting up
and securing a mail server in&nbsp;2024 is not for the faint of heart, nor
for anyone without copious spare time. Spammers want to flood inboxes
with ads for questionable supplements, attackers want to abuse servers
to send spam (or worse), and getting the big providers to accept mail
from small servers is a constant uphill battle. Michael W. Lucas,
however, encourages users to thumb their nose at the "<q>Email
Empire</q>", and declare email independence. His self-published book,
<em><a href="https://mwl.io/nonfiction/tools#ryoms">Run Your Own Mail
Server</a></em>, provides a manual (and manifesto) for users who are
interested in the challenge.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998153/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 19:19:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Development statistics for 6.12</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/997959/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/CAHk-=wgtGkHshfvaAe_O2ntnFBH3EprNk1juieLmjcF2HBwBgQ@mail.gmail.com/">released
the 6.12 kernel</a> on November&nbsp;17, as expected.  This development
cycle, the last for 2024, brought 13,344 non-merge changesets into the
mainline kernel; that made it a relatively slow cycle from this
perspective, but 6.12 includes a long list of significant new features.
The time has come to look at where those changes came from, and to look at
the year-long LTS cycle as well.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/997959/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 16:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Two approaches to tightening restrictions on loadable modules</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998221/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The kernel's loadable-module facility allows code to be loaded into (and
sometimes removed from) a running kernel.  Among other things, loadable
modules make it possible to run a kernel with only the subsystems needed
for the system's hardware and workload.  Loadable modules can also make it
easy for out-of-tree code to access parts of the kernel that developers
would prefer to keep private; this has led to <a
href="https://lwn.net/Kernel/Index/#Modules-Exported_symbols">many discussions</a> in the
past.  The topic has returned to the kernel's mailing lists with two
different patch sets aimed at further tightening the restrictions applied
to loadable modules.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998221/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 18:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Fedora KDE gets a promotion</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/997559/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Fedora Project is set to welcome a second desktop edition to its
lineup after months (or years, depending when one starts the clock)
of discussions. The project recently decided to allow a new working group to
move forward with a KDE&nbsp;Plasma&nbsp;Desktop edition that will sit
alongside the existing GNOME-based Fedora&nbsp;Workstation
edition. This puts KDE on a more equal footing within the project,
which, it is hoped, will bring more contributors and users interested
in KDE to adopt Fedora as their Linux distribution of choice.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/997559/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Dancing the DMA two-step</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/997563/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Direct memory access (DMA) I/O is simple in concept: a peripheral device
moves data directly to or from memory while the CPU is busy doing other
things.  As is so often the case, DMA is rather more complicated in
practice, and the kernel has developed a complicated internal API to
support it.  It turns out that the DMA API, as it exists now, can affect
the performance of some high-bandwidth devices.  In an effort to address
that problem, Leon Romanovsky is making the API even more complex with <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/cover.1731244445.git.leon@kernel.org">this patch series</a>
adding a new two-step mapping API.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/997563/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 15:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Fedora moves towards Forgejo (Fedora Magazine)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000751/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Fedora Project Leader Matthew Miller <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/fedora-moves-towards-forgejo-a-unified-decision/">reports</a>
that the project's search to replace <a
href="https://pagure.io/">Pagure</a> as its <a
href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Forge_(software)">git forge</a> is
almost complete, with the Fedora Council strongly in favor of <a
href="https://forgejo.org/">Forgejo</a>:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
The Council, currently, has a clear preference for Forgejo. This is a
big decision and we don't want it to feel rushed. Therefore, we're
opening this up one last time to everyone's comments. After two weeks,
we'll take our formal vote — and then get on with the work!
</blockquote>

<p>LWN <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/963095/">looked at
Forgejo</a> in February.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000751/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 17:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Walleij: New ARM32 Security Features in v6.10</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000727/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus Walleij <a
href="https://people.kernel.org/linusw/new-arm32-security-features-in-v6-10">writes
about a pair of security features for 32-bit Arm systems</a>; these landed
in 6.10, but, he says, have now stabilized to the point that distributors
may want to enable them.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	PAN is an abbreviation for the somewhat grammatically incorrect
	Privileged Access Never. [...]
<p>
	For modern ARM32 systems with large memories configured to use LPAE
	nothing like PAN was available: this version of the MMU simply did
	not implement a PAN option.
<p>
	As of the patch originally developed by Catalin Marinas, we deploy
	a scheme that will use the fact that LPAE has two separate
	translation table base registers (TTBR:s): one for userspace
	(TTBR0) and one for kernelspace (TTBR1).
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000727/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 16:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hurl 6.0.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000726/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://hurl.dev/blog/2024/12/04/announcing-hurl-6.0.0.html">Version
6.0.0</a> of the <a href="https://hurl.dev/">Hurl</a> command-line tool has been released. Hurl is
curl-powered utility that runs HTTP requests and tests defined in a
plain-text <a href="https://hurl.dev/docs/hurl-file.html">Hurl
file</a>. Notable features in this release include the ability to
generate dynamic values with functions, shorter syntax, and an option
to export Hurl files to a list of curl commands. See the <a
href="https://github.com/Orange-OpenSource/hurl/releases/tag/6.0.0">release
notes</a> for a full list of changes and downloads.</p>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000726/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 15:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000721/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Red Hat</b> (go-toolset:rhel8, grafana, kernel, kernel-rt, kernel:4.18.0, pam, pam:1.5.1, pcs, postgresql:12, postgresql:15, postgresql:16, python3:3.6.8, qemu-kvm, rhc, rhc-worker-playbook, and virt:rhel and virt-devel:rhel) and <b>SUSE</b> (ansible-10, ansible-core, avahi, bpftool, python, python3, python36, webkit2gtk3, and xen).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000721/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 14:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000591/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (container-tools:rhel8, kernel, kernel-rt:4.18.0, kernel:4.18.0, pam, pam:1.5.1, perl-App-cpanminus, perl-App-cpanminus:1.7044, python-tornado, tigervnc, tuned, and webkit2gtk3), <b>Debian</b> (needrestart and webkit2gtk), <b>Mageia</b> (firefox, glib2.0, krb5, and thunderbird), <b>Red Hat</b> (firefox, postgresql, postgresql:12, postgresql:13, postgresql:15, postgresql:16, and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (editorconfig-core-c, kernel, php7, php8, python, python-tornado6, python3-virtualenv, python310, python39, thunderbird, wget, and wireshark), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (firefox and haproxy).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000591/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 14:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>NixOS 24.11 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000469/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The most recent version of <a href="https://nixos.org/">NixOS</a>,&nbsp;24.11,
was <a
href="https://nixos.org/blog/announcements/2024/nixos-2411/">released</a>
on November&nbsp;30.  It contains GNOME&nbsp;47, Plasma&nbsp;6.2, LLVM&nbsp;19, and lots more:
<blockquote class="bq">
The 24.11 release was made possible due to the efforts of <b>2669</b>&nbsp;contributors, who authored <b>49079</b>&nbsp;commits since the previous release. Our thanks go the contributors who also take care of the continued stability and security of our stable release.
<p>
NixOS is already known as <a href="https://repology.org/repositories/statistics/newest">the most up to date distribution</a> while also being <a href="https://repology.org/repositories/statistics/total">the distribution with the most packages</a>. This release saw <b>8141&nbsp;new</b> packages and <b>20975&nbsp;updated</b> packages in Nixpkgs. We also <b>removed&nbsp;3970</b> packages in an effort to keep the package set maintainable and secure. 
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000469/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 17:26:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000465/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (dnsmasq, editorconfig-core, lemonldap-ng, proftpd-dfsg, python3.9, simplesamlphp, tgt, and xfpt), <b>Fedora</b> (qbittorrent, webkitgtk, and wireshark), <b>Mageia</b> (libsoup3 &amp; libsoup), <b>Red Hat</b> (buildah, grafana, grafana-pcp, and podman), <b>SUSE</b> (gimp, kernel, postgresql14, python, webkit2gtk3, xen, and zabbix), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (ansible and postgresql-12, postgresql-14, postgresql-16).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000465/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/999597/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (ansible, chromium, ghostscript, glib2.0, intel-microcode, and kernel), <b>Fedora</b> (dotnet9.0, needrestart, php, and python3.6), <b>Oracle</b> (cups, kernel, osbuild-composer, podman, python3.12-urllib3, squid, and xerces-c), <b>Red Hat</b> (buildah, edk2, gnome-shell, haproxy, kernel, kernel-rt, libvpx, pam, python3.11-urllib3, python3.12-urllib3, qemu-kvm, rhc-worker-script, squid:4, and tigervnc), <b>Slackware</b> (php), <b>SUSE</b> (chromedriver, chromium, dcmtk, govulncheck-vulndb, iptraf-ng, and traefik2), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-oracle and openjdk-23).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/999597/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 14:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.13-rc1</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000379/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has released <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1000378/">6.13-rc1</a> and closed the
merge window for this release.  "<q>And for once - possibly the first time
ever - it looks like the release cycle doesn't clash horribly up with
the holiday season, and we'll have time both to stabilize this release,
_and_ the work for 6.14 won't be starting until well into January.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000379/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 23:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rust 1.83.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000273/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2024/11/28/Rust-1.83.0.html">Version
1.83.0</a> of the Rust language has been released.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	This release includes several large extensions to what code running
	in <tt>const</tt> contexts can do. This refers to all code that the
	compiler has to evaluate at compile-time: the initial value of
	<tt>const</tt> and <tt>static</tt> items, array lengths, enum
	discriminant values, const generic arguments, and functions
	callable from such contexts (<tt>const fn</tt>).
</blockquote>
<p>
There are also quite a few new stabilized APIs.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000273/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 15:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The OpenWrt One router is now shipping</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000272/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The OpenWrt One router, which <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/994961/">was reviewed
here</a> recently, <a
href="https://sfconservancy.org/news/2024/nov/29/openwrt-one-wireless-router-now-ships-black-friday/">is
now generally available</a>.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	 This is the first wireless Internet router designed and built with
	 your software freedom and right to repair in mind. The OpenWrt One
	 will never be locked down and is forever unbrickable. This device
	 services your needs as its owner and user. Everyone deserves
	 control of their computing. The OpenWrt One takes a great first
	 step toward bringing software rights to your home: you can control
	 your own network with the software of your choice, and ensure your
	 right to change, modify, and repair it as you like.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000272/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 15:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A kernel code of conduct enforcement action</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/999197/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The <a href="https://wiki.linuxfoundation.org/tab/start">Linux Foundation Technical
Advisory Board</a> (TAB) has <a href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-kernel/6740fc3aabec0_5eb129497@dwillia2-xfh.jf.intel.com.notmuch/">decided</a> to "<q>restrict Kent Overstreet's
participation in the kernel development process during the Linux 6.13
kernel development cycle</q>" based on a recommendation from the <a
href="https://kernel.org/code-of-conduct.html">Code of Conduct
committee</a>.  In particular, the scope of the restriction will be to "<q>decline all pull
requests from Kent Overstreet</q>" during the development cycle.
Overstreet is the creator and maintainer of the <a
href="https://bcachefs.org/">bcachefs</a> filesystem.

<p>
This
action stems from a <a 
href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-kernel/citv2v6f33hoidq75xd2spaqxf7nl5wbmmzma4wgmrwpoqidhj@k453tmq7vdrk/">message</a>
Overstreet posted back in early September that was abusive toward another
kernel developer; there is a fair amount of back-and-forth about the
incident and the committee's attempts to extract a public apology from
Overstreet in that thread.  Overstreet has published a <a
href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/116412665">lengthy blog post</a>
describing his side of the story.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/999197/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 01:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Four Friday stable kernel updates</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/999107/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/999108/">6.12.1</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/999109/">6.11.10</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/999110/">6.6.63</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/999111/">6.1.119</a> stable kernel updates have been released.
As always, they contain important fixes.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/999107/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 15:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/999102/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (postgresql-13, postgresql-15, and webkit2gtk), <b>Fedora</b> (libsndfile, microcode_ctl, and trafficserver), <b>Mageia</b> (kanboard, kernel, kmod-xtables-addons, kmod-virtualbox, and bluez, kernel-linus, opendmarc, and radare2), <b>Oracle</b> (.NET 9.0, bubblewrap and flatpak, buildah, expat, firefox, grafana, grafana-pcp, kernel, krb5, libsoup, libvpx, NetworkManager-libreswan, openexr, pcp, python3.11, python3.11-urllib3, python3.12, python3.9, squid, thunderbird, tigervnc, and webkit2gtk3), <b>Red Hat</b> (.NET 9.0, binutils, expat, grafana-pcp, kernel, libsoup, NetworkManager-libreswan, openexr, python3.11, python3.12, python39:3.9, squid, tigervnc, and webkit2gtk3), <b>SUSE</b> (chromedriver, cobbler, govulncheck-vulndb, and icinga2), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-6.8, python2.7, and zbar).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/999102/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000185/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (firefox-esr, redis, twisted, and tzdata), <b>Fedora</b> (firefox, nss, pam, rust-rustls, rust-zlib-rs, thunderbird, tuned, and xen), and <b>SUSE</b> (cobbler, kernel, libjxl-devel, libuv, postgresql12, postgresql14, postgresql15, python-waitress, seamonkey, tomcat, and tomcat10).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000185/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 14:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>PHP 8.4.1 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/999004/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.php.net/archive/2024.php#2024-11-21-4">Version
8.4.1</a> of the PHP language has been released.  See <a
href="https://www.php.net/releases/8.4/en.php">this page</a> for details on
the new features in this release.  "<q>PHP 8.4 is a major update of the PHP
language.  It contains many new features, such as property hooks,
asymmetric visibility, an updated DOM API, performance improvements, bug
fixes, and general cleanup.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/999004/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 23:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Giving thanks for the LWN community</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000097/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Earlier today, one of our subscribers, anselm, posted the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1000000/">one millionth</a> item in our database during a discussion in the comments about the GPL. One million articles and comments is a big milestone — one representing twenty two years of work by both the editors of LWN and the community. I think reaching this milestone on Thanksgiving is a lovely coincidental reminder of how far LWN has come, and how that wouldn't have been possible without your support. So thank you for reading.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000097/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 21:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/999597/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (ansible, chromium, ghostscript, glib2.0, intel-microcode, and kernel), <b>Fedora</b> (dotnet9.0, needrestart, php, and python3.6), <b>Oracle</b> (cups, kernel, osbuild-composer, podman, python3.12-urllib3, squid, and xerces-c), <b>Red Hat</b> (buildah, edk2, gnome-shell, haproxy, kernel, kernel-rt, libvpx, pam, python3.11-urllib3, python3.12-urllib3, qemu-kvm, rhc-worker-script, squid:4, and tigervnc), <b>Slackware</b> (php), <b>SUSE</b> (chromedriver, chromium, dcmtk, govulncheck-vulndb, iptraf-ng, and traefik2), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-oracle and openjdk-23).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/999597/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 14:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A kernel code of conduct enforcement action</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/999197/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The <a href="https://wiki.linuxfoundation.org/tab/start">Linux Foundation Technical
Advisory Board</a> (TAB) has <a href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-kernel/6740fc3aabec0_5eb129497@dwillia2-xfh.jf.intel.com.notmuch/">decided</a> to "<q>restrict Kent Overstreet's
participation in the kernel development process during the Linux 6.13
kernel development cycle</q>" based on a recommendation from the <a
href="https://kernel.org/code-of-conduct.html">Code of Conduct
committee</a>.  In particular, the scope of the restriction will be to "<q>decline all pull
requests from Kent Overstreet</q>" during the development cycle.
Overstreet is the creator and maintainer of the <a
href="https://bcachefs.org/">bcachefs</a> filesystem.

<p>
This
action stems from a <a 
href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-kernel/citv2v6f33hoidq75xd2spaqxf7nl5wbmmzma4wgmrwpoqidhj@k453tmq7vdrk/">message</a>
Overstreet posted back in early September that was abusive toward another
kernel developer; there is a fair amount of back-and-forth about the
incident and the committee's attempts to extract a public apology from
Overstreet in that thread.  Overstreet has published a <a
href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/116412665">lengthy blog post</a>
describing his side of the story.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/999197/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 01:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Four Friday stable kernel updates</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/999107/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/999108/">6.12.1</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/999109/">6.11.10</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/999110/">6.6.63</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/999111/">6.1.119</a> stable kernel updates have been released.
As always, they contain important fixes.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/999107/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 15:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/999102/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (postgresql-13, postgresql-15, and webkit2gtk), <b>Fedora</b> (libsndfile, microcode_ctl, and trafficserver), <b>Mageia</b> (kanboard, kernel, kmod-xtables-addons, kmod-virtualbox, and bluez, kernel-linus, opendmarc, and radare2), <b>Oracle</b> (.NET 9.0, bubblewrap and flatpak, buildah, expat, firefox, grafana, grafana-pcp, kernel, krb5, libsoup, libvpx, NetworkManager-libreswan, openexr, pcp, python3.11, python3.11-urllib3, python3.12, python3.9, squid, thunderbird, tigervnc, and webkit2gtk3), <b>Red Hat</b> (.NET 9.0, binutils, expat, grafana-pcp, kernel, libsoup, NetworkManager-libreswan, openexr, python3.11, python3.12, python39:3.9, squid, tigervnc, and webkit2gtk3), <b>SUSE</b> (chromedriver, cobbler, govulncheck-vulndb, and icinga2), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-6.8, python2.7, and zbar).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/999102/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>PHP 8.4.1 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/999004/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.php.net/archive/2024.php#2024-11-21-4">Version
8.4.1</a> of the PHP language has been released.  See <a
href="https://www.php.net/releases/8.4/en.php">this page</a> for details on
the new features in this release.  "<q>PHP 8.4 is a major update of the PHP
language.  It contains many new features, such as property hooks,
asymmetric visibility, an updated DOM API, performance improvements, bug
fixes, and general cleanup.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/999004/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 23:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>