<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 14:43:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 5 Nov 2024 14:48:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/997030/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (firefox, openexr, and thunderbird), <b>Fedora</b> (llama-cpp and python-quart), <b>Oracle</b> (firefox, openexr, thunderbird, and xorg-x11-server and xorg-x11-server-Xwayland), <b>SUSE</b> (chromium, govulncheck-vulndb, openssl-1_1, python311, and python312), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-azure, linux-bluefield, linux-azure, linux-gcp, linux-ibm, openjpeg2, and ruby3.0, ruby3.2, ruby3.3).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/997030/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 14:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The BPF instruction set architecture is now RFC 9669</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/997002/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[After a couple of years of effort, the BPF instruction set architecture has
been accepted as <a href="https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc9669.html">RFC
9669</a>, giving it a standard outside of the in-kernel implementation.  <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20241105035101.GD41004@maniforge">This message from David
Vernet</a> (who also contributed <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/926882/">an article on
the standardization process</a> last year) describes the process and why it
is important:
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Though some vendors have already implemented BPF offloading
	capabilities without having a standardized ISA, others are not
	quite as risk tolerant. As Christoph [Hellwig] discussed at LSFMM
	2022, certain NVMe vendors have expressed an interest in building
	BPF offloading capabilities for various use cases such as eXpress
	Resubmission Path (XRP), but they simply can't fund such a project
	without certain components of BPF being standardized. Hence, the
	effort to standardize BPF was born.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/997002/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 14:43:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996908/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (firefox, grafana, kernel, and mod_http2), <b>Debian</b> (chromium, openssl, and thunderbird), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, krb5, mysql8.0, polkit, python-single-version, and webkitgtk), <b>Mageia</b> (bind, buildah, podman, skopeo, kernel, kmod-xtables-addons. kmod-virtualbox, kernel-firmware &amp; kernel-firmware-nonfree radeon-firmware, and kernel-linus), <b>SUSE</b> (apache2, chromedriver, cups-filters, docker-stable, firefox, gama, govulncheck-vulndb, java-11-openjdk, java-17-openjdk, java-23-openjdk, libnss_slurm2, openssl-1_1, openssl-3, python-waitress, python3, python310-waitress, ruby2.5, rubygem-actionmailer-5_1, rubygem-actionpack-5_1, rubygem-bundler, webkit2gtk3, and xorg-x11-server), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-azure-6.8).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996908/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 14:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.12-rc6</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996828/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/996829/">6.12-rc6</a> kernel prepatch is out for
testing.  Linus says: "<q>Another week, another rc. Nothing odd or special
seems to be going on - this may be a bit on the bigger side for an rc6, but
not hugely so, and nothing stands out.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996828/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:41:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Four Friday stable kernel updates</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996687/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Greg Kroah-Hartman has released another four stable Linux kernel updates:
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/996688/">6.11.6</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/996689/">6.6.59</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/996690/">6.1.115</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/996691/">5.15.170</a>.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996687/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 14:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996679/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (firefox-esr), <b>Fedora</b> (xorg-x11-server-Xwayland), <b>Oracle</b> (buildah, e2fsprogs, grafana, kernel, and mod_http2), <b>Red Hat</b> (buildah, container-tools:rhel8, firefox, grafana, grafana:7.3.6, podman, and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (alloy, cargo-audit-advisory-db-20241030, chromedriver, corepack22, netty, openvpn, python310-Werkzeug, thunderbird, uwsgi, and xsd), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux, linux-azure-6.8, linux-gcp-6.8, linux-hwe-6.8 and linux, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.4, linux-gkeop, linux-hwe-5.4, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.4).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996679/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 12:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>October project goals update (Rust Blog)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996585/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Rust blog has an <a
href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2024/10/31/project-goals-oct-update.html">update</a>
on its progress on some of its <a
href="https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-project-goals/2024h2/goals.html">project
goals</a>. One of the project's <a
href="https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-project-goals/2024h2/goals.html#flagship-goals">flagship
goals</a> is to <a
href="https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-project-goals/2024h2/rfl_stable.html">resolve
the biggest blockers to Linux building on stable Rust</a>:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Finally, we have been finding an increasing number of stabilization
requests at the compiler level, and so @wesleywiser and @davidtwco
from the compiler team have started attending meetings to create a
faster response. One of the results of that collaboration is <a
href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/3716">RFC #3716</a>,
authored by Alice Ryhl, which proposes a method to manage compiler
flags that modify the target ABI. Our previous approach has been to
create distinct targets for each combination of flags, but the number
of flags needed by the kernel make that impractical. Authoring the RFC
revealed more such flags than previously recognized, including those
that modify LLVM behavior.
</blockquote>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996585/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 21:26:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996526/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (firefox-esr and openssl), <b>Fedora</b> (firefox, libarchive, micropython, NetworkManager-libreswan, and xorg-x11-server-Xwayland), <b>Red Hat</b> (nano), <b>Slackware</b> (mozilla-firefox, mozilla-thunderbird, tigervnc, and xorg), <b>SUSE</b> (389-ds, Botan, go1.21-openssl, govulncheck-vulndb, java-11-openjdk, lxc, python-Werkzeug, and uwsgi), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (firefox, libarchive, linux-azure-fde, linux-azure-fde-5.15, python-pip, and xorg-server, xorg-server-hwe-16.04, xorg-server-hwe-18.04).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996526/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 14:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for October 24, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994575/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for October 24, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994575/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:42:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Toward safe transmutation in Rust</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994334/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Currently in Rust, there is no efficient and safe way to turn an array of bytes
into a structure that corresponds to the array. Changing that was the topic of
Jack Wrenn's talk this year at
<a href="https://rustconf.com">
RustConf</a>:
<a href="https://jack.wrenn.fyi/blog/safety-goggles-for-alchemists/">
"Safety Goggles for Alchemists"</a>. The goal is to be able to "transmute" —
Rust's name for this kind of conversion — values into arbitrary user-defined
types in a safer way. Wrenn justified the approach that the project has taken to
accomplish this, and spoke about the future work required to stabilize it.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994334/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 17:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Free-software foundations face fundraising problems</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993665/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In July, at the GNOME <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983203/">annual general meeting</a> (AGM),
held at <a
href="https://foundation.gnome.org/2023/12/20/guadec-2024-in-denver-colorado/">GUADEC
2024</a>,
the message from the GNOME Foundation board was that all was well,
financially speaking. Not <em>great</em>, but the foundation was on a
break-even budget and expected to go into its next fiscal year with a
similar budget and headcount. On October&nbsp;7, however, the board <a
href="https://foundation.gnome.org/2024/10/07/update-from-the-board-2024-10/">announced</a>
that it had had to make some cuts, including reducing its staff by
two people. This is not, however, strictly a GNOME problem: similar
organizations, such as the Python Software Foundation (PSF), KDE&nbsp;e.V., 
and the Free Software Foundation Europe (FSFE) are seeing declines in
fundraising while also being affected by inflation.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993665/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 14:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A report from the 2024 Image-Based Linux Summit</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994704/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The Image-Based Linux Summit has by now established itself as a yearly event.
Following on from <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/946526/">last year's edition</a>,
the third edition was held in Berlin on September&nbsp;24, the
day before
<a href="https://all-systems-go.io">
All Systems Go!&nbsp;2024</a> (ASG). The purpose of this event is to gather
stakeholders from various engineering groups and hold friendly but lively
discussions around the topic of image-based Linux — that is, Linux distributions
based around immutable images, instead of mutable root filesystems.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994704/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 19:20:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Python PGP proposal poses packaging puzzles</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993787/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://docs.sigstore.dev/">Sigstore</a> is a 
project that is meant to simplify and improve the process of signing,
verifying, and protecting software. It is a relatively new project, <a
href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/sigstore-announces-general-availability-at-sigstorecon-301657741.html">declared</a>
"generally available" in 2022. Python is an early adopter of sigstore; it started <a
href="https://www.python.org/downloads/metadata/sigstore/">providing
signatures for CPython artifacts</a> with <a
href="https://www.python.org/downloads/release/python-3110/">Python&nbsp;3.11</a>
in&nbsp;2022. This is in addition to the <a
href="https://www.openpgp.org/">OpenPGP</a> signatures it has been
providing <a href="https://peps.python.org/pep-0101/">since at
least&nbsp;2001</a>. Now, Seth&nbsp;Michael&nbsp;Larson&mdash;the <a
href="https://www.python.org/psf-landing/">Python Software
Foundation</a> (PSF) <a
href="https://pyfound.blogspot.com/2023/06/announcing-our-new-security-developer.html">security
developer-in-residence</a>&mdash;would like to deprecate the PGP
signature and move to sigstore exclusively by next year. If that
happens, it will involve some changes in the way that Linux
distributions verify Python releases, since none of the major
distributions have processes for working with sigstore.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993787/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 15:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The long road to lazy preemption</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994322/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The kernel's CPU scheduler currently offers several preemption modes that
implement a range of tradeoffs between system throughput and response time.
Back in September 2023, a <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/944686/">discussion
on scheduling</a> led to the concept of "lazy preemption", which could
simplify scheduling in the kernel while providing better results.  Things
went quiet for a while, but lazy preemption has returned in the form of <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20241007074609.447006177@infradead.org">this patch series</a>
from Peter Zijlstra.  While the concept appears to work well, there is
still a fair amount of work to be done.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994322/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 14:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A look at the aerc mail client</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993498/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Email has become somewhat unfashionable as a collaboration tool for
open-source projects, but there are still a number of projects—such as
PostgreSQL and the Linux kernel—that expect contributors to send and
review patches via email. The <a href="https://aerc-mail.org/">aerc</a>
mail client is aimed at developers looking for a text-based, efficient, and
extensible client that is meant to be used for working with Git and
email. It uses Vim-style keybindings by default, and has an interface
inspired by <a href="https://github.com/tmux/tmux/wiki">tmux</a> that
lets users manage multiple accounts, mails, and embedded terminals at once.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993498/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 15:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Ravier: What&apos;s new for Fedora Atomic Desktops in Fedora 41</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996337/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Timothée Ravier has written <a
href="https://tim.siosm.fr/blog/2024/10/30/fedora-atomic-desktops-41/">a
blog post</a> about changes in the <a
href="https://fedoraproject.org/atomic-desktops/">Fedora Atomic
Desktops</a> for Fedora&nbsp;Linux&nbsp;41. Some of the notable new
features for Atomic Desktops include bootloader updates enabled by
default for UEFI systems, first steps towards using <a
href="https://containers.github.io/bootable/">bootable containers</a>,
and more.</p>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996337/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 17:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A new release of Raspberry Pi OS</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996332/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Raspberry Pi project has <a
href="https://www.raspberrypi.com/news/a-new-release-of-raspberry-pi-os/">announced</a>
a new version of Raspberry Pi OS. It includes a number of
significant changes, the most notable of which is that the Raspberry
Pi Desktop now uses Wayland by default for all Pi models using the
<a href="https://labwc.github.io/">labwc</a> compositor:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
For most of this year, we have been working on porting labwc to the
Raspberry Pi Desktop. This has very much been a collaborative process
with the developers of both labwc and wlroots: both have helped us
immensely with their support as we contribute features and
optimisations needed for our desktop.
</blockquote>

<p>This release also features Linux 6.6.51, improved touchscreen support, a new
screen configuration tool called <tt>raindrop</tt>, and more. See the
<a
href="https://downloads.raspberrypi.com/raspios_armhf/release_notes.txt">release
notes</a> for a full list of changes.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996332/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 16:41:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Thunderbird for Android now available</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996326/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://blog.thunderbird.net/2024/10/thunderbird-for-android-8-0-takes-flight/">first stable release</a> of the Thunderbird mail client for Android is now available:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Just over two years ago, we <a
href="https://blog.thunderbird.net/2022/06/revealed-thunderbird-on-android-plans-k9/">announced
our plans</a> to bring Thunderbird to Android by taking K-9 Mail under
our wing. The journey took a <a
href="https://blog.thunderbird.net/2023/12/when-will-thunderbird-for-android-be-released/">little
longer than we had originally anticipated</a> and there was a lot to
learn along the way, but the wait is finally over! For all of you who
have ever asked "when is Thunderbird for Android coming out?", the
answer is – today!
</blockquote>

<p>It is immediately available on the <a
href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.thunderbird.android">Google
Play Store</a>, via <a
href="https://github.com/thunderbird/thunderbird-android/releases/tag/THUNDERBIRD_8_0">GitHub
Releases</a>, or from the <a
href="https://thunderbird.net/mobile/">Thunderbird web site</a>, and
it will be "<q>coming soon</q>" to the <a
href="https://f-droid.org/en/">F-Droid</a> repository for FOSS Android
applications. See the <a
href="https://github.com/thunderbird/thunderbird-android/releases/tag/THUNDERBIRD_8_0">release
notes</a> for detailed information about Thunderbird&nbsp;8.0 for
Android.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996326/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 15:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996310/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (buildah), <b>Debian</b> (python-git, texlive-bin, and xorg-server), <b>Mageia</b> (chromium-browser-stable), <b>Red Hat</b> (kernel), <b>SUSE</b> (Botan, go1.22-openssl, go1.23-openssl, grafana, libgsf, pcp, pgadmin4, python310-pytest-html, python313, xorg-x11-server, and xwayland), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (nano, python-urllib3, and xorg-server, xwayland).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996310/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 13:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Firefox version 132.0 is now available</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996216/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Mozilla has
<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/132.0/releasenotes/">announced</a> the release of a new version of Firefox. This version has the usual mix of 
<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/security/advisories/mfsa2024-55/">
security fixes</a> and new features, as well as a handful of deprecations. The release removes support for HTTP/2 Push, but adds hardware acceleration for SVGs, support for wide color gamuts on more platforms, and restores support for remote debugging via USB.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996216/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 17:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Fedora 41 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996214/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Fedora Linux 41 <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/announcing-fedora-linux-41/">has been
released</a>. See the "what's new" pages for <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/whats-new-fedora-workstation-41/">Fedora
Workstation</a> and <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/whats-new-in-fedora-kde-41/">Fedora
KDE</a>, to learn more about the latest in those editions. There is
also a new <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/spins/miraclewm">Fedora
Miracle Window Manager Spin</a> that offers the <a
href="https://miracle-wm.org/">Miracle</a> tiling window manager for
Wayland.</p>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996214/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 17:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>