<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 04:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 04:33:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Inkscape 1.4 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994098/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://inkscape.org/news/2024/10/13/inkscape-launches-version-14-powerful-new-accessib/">Version
1.4</a> of the <a href="https://inkscape.org/">Inkscape</a>
open-source vector-graphics editor has been released. Highlights of
this release include a filter gallery, import for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affinity_Designer">Affinity Designer</a>
files, internal links in exported PDFs, and more. See the <a
href="https://inkscape.org/doc/release_notes/1.4/Inkscape_1.4.html">release
notes</a> for all of the new features. LWN <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/991732/">previewed</a> the 1.4 release
in early October.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994098/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 18:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994080/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (docker.io, libreoffice, node-dompurify, python-reportlab, and thunderbird), <b>Fedora</b> (buildah, chromium, kernel, kernel-headers, libgsf, mosquitto, p7zip, podman, python-cramjam, python-virtualenv, redis, rust-async-compression, rust-brotli, rust-brotli-decompressor, rust-libcramjam, rust-libcramjam0.2, rust-nu-command, rust-nu-protocol, rust-redlib, rust-tower-http, thunderbird, and webkit2gtk4.0), <b>Oracle</b> (.NET 6.0, .NET 8.0, e2fsprogs, firefox, golang, openssl, python3-setuptools, systemd, and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (chromium, firefox, java-jwt, libmozjs-128-0, libwireshark18, ntpd-rs, OpenIPMI, thunderbird, and wireshark), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (firefox, python2.7, python3.5, thunderbird, and ubuntu-advantage-desktop-daemon).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994080/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 14:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.12-rc3</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993956/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/993955/">6.12-rc3</a> kernel prepatch is out for
testing.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	So the diffstat looks a bit odd, because one of the fixes here
	caused the UTF tables to be regenerated, and an effective one-liner
	change turned into 6703 lines of diff.
	<p>
	But if you ignore that effect, everything looks normal.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993956/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 22:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993778/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (.NET 6.0, .NET 8.0, and openssl), <b>Debian</b> (firefox-esr), <b>Fedora</b> (firefox), <b>Mageia</b> (php, quictls, and vim), <b>Red Hat</b> (buildah, container-tools:rhel8, containernetworking-plugins, firefox, podman, skopeo, and tomcat), <b>Slackware</b> (mozilla), <b>SUSE</b> (apache-commons-io, kernel, and xen), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (golang-1.17, libgsf, and linux-aws-6.8, linux-oracle-6.8).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993778/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 13:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Ubuntu 24.10 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993660/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://canonical.com/blog/canonical-releases-ubuntu-24-10-oracular-oriole">Version
24.10</a> of the Ubuntu distribution is out. This release includes GNOME&nbsp;47, Linux 6.11,
security enhancements for managing Personal Package Archives (PPAs),
experimental security controls for Snap packages, and more.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993660/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 16:46:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Updating Firefox is highly recommended</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993608/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Mozilla has released Firefox versions 131.0.2, ESR 128.3.1, and ESR
115.16.1.  These updates address <a
href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/security/advisories/mfsa2024-51/">a
severe, remotely exploitable code-execution vulnerability</a> that is
evidently already being exploited.  Updating to a fixed release seems like
a wise thing to do.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993608/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 12:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New stable kernels released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993596/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Greg Kroah-Hartman has announced the release of the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/993597/">6.11.3</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/993598/">6.10.14</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/993599/">6.6.55</a>, and <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/993600/">6.6.56</a> stable kernels.  The 6.6.56 release
fixes a problem with building perf in 6.6.55; "<q>If you do not use the
perf tool in the 6.6.y tree, there is no need to upgrade.</q>".  Meanwhile,
6.10.14 is the last of the 6.10.y series, so users should now be moving to
6.11.y. Other than 6.6.56, they contain the usual long list of important
fixes throughout the kernel tree.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993596/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 11:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993595/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (chromium), <b>Fedora</b> (firefox, koji, unbound, webkit2gtk4.0, and xen), <b>Red Hat</b> (glibc, net-snmp, and tomcat), <b>Slackware</b> (mozilla), <b>SUSE</b> (apache-commons-io, buildah, cups-filters, liboath-devel, libreoffice, libunbound8, podman, and redis), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (cups-browsed, cups-filters, edk2, linux-raspi-5.4, and oath-toolkit).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993595/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 11:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for October 3, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991771/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for October 3, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991771/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 01:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Inkscape 1.4 coming soon</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991732/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The open-source vector-graphics editor, <a
href="https://inkscape.org/">Inkscape</a>, is expected to release <a
href="https://wiki.inkscape.org/wiki/Release_notes/1.4">version&nbsp;1.4</a>
in October. The release represents an evolutionary step for the program, which
brings new features, user-interface improvements, new and improved
file-format support, and important changes to the code base. The changes in
this release should improve the user experience for both casual and
professional designers, and make Inkscape more compatible with proprietary
vector-graphics software, including Adobe Illustrator and Affinity
Designer.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991732/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 17:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] BTF, Rust, and the kernel toolchain</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991719/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
<a href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/latest/bpf/btf.html">
BPF Type Format</a> (BTF),
BPF's debugging information format, has undergone rapid evolution to match
the evolving needs of BPF programs. José Marchesi spoke at Kangrejos about some
of that work — and how it could impact Rust, specifically. He discussed debug
information, kernel-specific relocations, and the planned changes to kernel
stack unwinding. Each of these will require some amount of work to fully
support in Rust, but preliminary signs look promising.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991719/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 14:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] An update on gccrs development</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991199/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[One concern that has often been expressed about the Rust language is that
there is only one compiler for it.  That makes it hard to say what the
standard version of the language is and restricts the architectures that
can be targeted by Rust code to those that the available compiler supports.
Adding a Rust frontend to GCC would do much to address those concerns; at
the <a href="https://gcc.gnu.org/wiki/cauldron2024">2024 GNU Tools
Cauldron</a>, Pierre-Emmanuel Patry gave an update on the state of that
work and what its objectives are.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991199/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 12:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Coccinelle for Rust</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991399/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Tathagata Roy has been working to make the
<a href="https://coccinelle.gitlabpages.inria.fr/website/">
Coccinelle</a> tool that is used (among other things)
to automate the refactoring of C code work on Rust
code as well. Roy gave a
presentation at <a href="https://kangrejos.com/">Kangrejos</a> about that work,
including the creative approaches necessary to work with Rust's more complicated
control flow and syntax.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991399/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 19:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The rest of the 6.12 merge window</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991301/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/CAHk-=wiwVOCZsC6a4dLdb1UjL2fS_CnLNjrPL0XGFbDd9C26Cg@mail.gmail.com/">released
6.12-rc1</a> and closed the 6.12 merge window on September&nbsp;29; at that
point, 11,260 non-merge change sets had been pulled into the mainline for
the 6.12 release.  That is the lowest number of merge-window changes since
5.17-rc1 in January 2022, which brought in 11,068 changesets.  Nonetheless,
6.12 brings a number of interesting changes, many of which were included in
the roughly 4,500 changes merged since <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/990750/">the
summary of the first half of the 6.12 merge window</a> was written.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991301/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The WordPress mess</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991906/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://wordpress.org/">WordPress</a> is the <a href="https://w3techs.com/technologies/history_overview/content_management">world's most
popular</a> open&#8209;source blogging and content&#8209;management platform. In its
20&#8209;plus years of existence, WordPress has been something of a poster
child for open source, similar to Linux and Firefox. It introduced the
concept of open source to millions of bloggers, small&#8209;business owners,
and others who have deployed WordPress to support their web&#8209;publishing
needs. Unfortunately, it is now in the spotlight due to an increasingly
ugly dispute between two companies, <a
href="https://automattic.com/">Automattic</a> and <a
href="https://wpengine.com/">WP&nbsp;Engine</a>, that has spilled over into
the WordPress community.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991906/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Debian changes OpenSSH packaging</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991088/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In the wake of the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/967866/">XZ
backdoor</a>, the Debian project has revisited some of the
patches included in its <a href="https://www.openssh.com/">OpenSSH</a>
packages to improve security. The outcome of this is that the project
will be splitting out support for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kerberos_(protocol)">Kerberos</a> key exchange into a
separate set of packages, though not until after the Debian&nbsp;13
("trixie") release expected next year. The impact on Debian users
should be minimal, but it is an interesting look into the changes
Linux distributions make to upstream software as well as some of the
long-term consequences of those choices.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991088/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 14:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Getting PCI driver abstractions upstream</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990918/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Danilo Krummrich gave a talk at Kangrejos 2024 focusing on the question of how
the Rust-for-Linux project could improve at getting device and driver
abstractions upstream. As a case study, he used some of his recent work that
attempts to make it possible to write a PCI driver entirely in Rust. There
wasn't time to go into as much detail as he would have liked, but he did
demonstrate that it is possible to interface with the kernel's module loader in
a way that is much harder to
screw up than the current standard approach in C.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990918/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 17:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Sched_ext at LPC 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991205/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/922405/">extensible scheduler class (sched_ext)</a>
enables the implementation of CPU schedulers as a set of BPF programs
loaded from user space; it first hit the mailing lists in late 2022.
Sched_ext has engendered its share of controversy since, but is currently
slated to be part of the 6.12 kernel release.  At the 2024 <a
href="https://lpc.events/">Linux Plumbers Conference</a>, the growing
sched_ext community held one of its first public gatherings; sched_ext
would appear to have launched a new burst of creativity in scheduler
design.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991205/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 14:51:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Julia v1.11.0 has been released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993436/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The Julia project has
<a href="https://discourse.julialang.org/t/julia-v1-11-0-has-been-released-and-v1-10-is-now-lts/121064">
released</a> version 1.11.0. A separate
<a href="https://julialang.org/blog/2024/10/julia-1.11-highlights/">
blog post</a> covers some of the highlights. The release includes a number of helpful features.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
In previous Julia versions, there was no "programmatic way" of knowing if an unexported name was considered part of the public API or not. Instead, the guideline was basically that if it was not in the manual then it was not public which was a bit underwhelming. To remedy that, there is now a <tt>public</tt> keyword in Julia that can be used to indicate that an unexported name is part of the public API.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993436/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 14:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993433/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (firefox, mod_jk, and thunderbird), <b>Debian</b> (apache2 and firefox-esr), <b>Fedora</b> (crosswords, logiops, p7zip, and perl-App-cpanminus), <b>Red Hat</b> (.NET 6.0, firefox, git, kernel, kernel-rt, openssl, and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (buildah, json-lib, kernel, Mesa, mozjs78, pgadmin4, podman, podofo, qatlib, redis7, roundcubemail, rusty_v8, and seamonkey), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (dotnet6, dotnet8, nginx, and ruby-webrick).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993433/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 13:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993276/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (kernel), <b>Fedora</b> (webkitgtk), <b>Mageia</b> (cups), <b>Oracle</b> (e2fsprogs, kernel, and kernel-container), <b>Red Hat</b> (buildah, container-tools:rhel8, containernetworking-plugins, git-lfs, go-toolset:rhel8, golang, grafana-pcp, podman, and skopeo), <b>SUSE</b> (Mesa, mozjs115, podofo, and redis7), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (cups and cups-filters).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993276/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 13:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>