<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 04:54:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 06:10:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.9-rc5</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970667/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/970666/">released 6.9-rc5</a> for testing.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	But if you ignore those oddities, it all looks pretty normal and
	things appear fairly calm. Which is just as well, since the first
	part of the week I was on a quick trip to Seattle, and the second
	part of the week I've been doing a passable imitation of the
	Fontana di Trevi, except my medium is mucus.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970667/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 21:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970508/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (gnutls, java-17-openjdk, mod_http2, and squid), <b>Debian</b> (firefox-esr), <b>Fedora</b> (editorconfig, perl-Clipboard, php, rust, and wordpress), <b>Mageia</b> (less, libreswan, puppet, and x11-server, x11-server-xwayland, and tigervnc), <b>Slackware</b> (aaa_glibc), and <b>SUSE</b> (firefox, graphviz, kernel, nodejs12, pgadmin4, tomcat, and wireshark).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970508/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 13:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970324/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (firefox-esr, jetty9, libdatetime-timezone-perl, tomcat10, and tzdata), <b>Fedora</b> (cockpit, filezilla, and libfilezilla), <b>Red Hat</b> (firefox, gnutls, java-1.8.0-openjdk, java-17-openjdk, kernel, kernel-rt, less, mod_http2, nodejs:18, rhc-worker-script, and shim), <b>Slackware</b> (mozilla), <b>SUSE</b> (kernel), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (apache2, glibc, and linux-xilinx-zynqmp).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970324/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 14:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The first Linaro Forum for Arm Linux kernel topics</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/969031/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On February 20, <a href="https://linaro.org/">Linaro</a> held the initial
get-together for what is intended to be a regular Linux Kernel Forum for
the Arm-focused kernel community. This gathering aims to convene
approximately a few weeks prior to the merge window opening and prior to
the release of the current kernel version under development.  Topics
covered in the first gathering include preparing 64-bit Arm kernels for
low-end embedded systems, memory errors and <a
href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Compute_Express_Link">Compute Express
Link (CXL)</a>, devlink objectives, and scheduler integration.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/969031/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 14:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Continued attacks on HTTP/2</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/968600/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
On April 3 security researcher Bartek Nowotarski
<a href="https://nowotarski.info/http2-continuation-flood-technical-details/">
published</a> the details of a new denial-of-service (DoS)
attack, called a "continuation flood", against many
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP/2">HTTP/2</a>-capable web
servers. While the attack is not terribly complex, it affects many independent
implementations of the HTTP/2 protocol, even though multiple
similar vulnerabilities over the years have given implementers plenty of warning.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/968600/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 13:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Book review: Practical Julia</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/966684/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[A recent book by <a
href="https://lwn.net/Archives/GuestIndex/#Phillips_Lee">LWN guest 
author Lee Phillips</a> provides a nice introduction to the <a
href="https://julialang.org/">Julia</a> programming language.
<a href="https://nostarch.com/practical-julia"><i>Practical Julia</i></a>
does more than that, however.  As its subtitle ("A Hands-On Introduction
for Scientific Minds") implies, the book focuses on bringing Julia to
scientists, rather than programmers, which gives it something of a
different feel from most other books of this sort.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/966684/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 14:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for April 11, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/968375/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for April 11, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/968375/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:47:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Four more stable kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970086/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The 
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/970171/">6.8.7</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/970172/">6.6.28</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/970173/">6.1.87</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/970174/">5.15.156</a> stable kernel updates have all been
released.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970086/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 12:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970169/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (apache2 and cockpit), <b>Fedora</b> (firefox, kernel, mbedtls, python-cbor2, wireshark, and yyjson), <b>Mageia</b> (nghttp2), <b>Red Hat</b> (kernel, kernel-rt, opencryptoki, pcs, shim, squid, and squid:4), <b>Slackware</b> (firefox), <b>SUSE</b> (emacs, firefox, and kernel), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-aws, linux-aws-5.15, linux-aws-6.5, linux-raspi, and linux-iot).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970169/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 12:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>PuTTY 0.81 security release</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970045/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/">Version
0.81</a> of the PuTTY SSH client is out with a fix for <a
href="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2024-31497">CVE-2024-31497</a>;
some users will want to update and generate new keys:
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	 PuTTY 0.81, released today, fixes a critical vulnerability
	 CVE-2024-31497 in the use of 521-bit ECDSA keys
	 (ecdsa-sha2-nistp521). If you have used a 521-bit ECDSA private
	 key with any previous version of PuTTY, consider the private key
	 compromised: remove the public key from authorized_keys files, and
	 generate a new key pair.
<p>
	 However, this only affects that one algorithm and key size. No
	 other size of ECDSA key is affected, and no other key type is
	 affected.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970045/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 15:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970036/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (php7.4 and php8.2), <b>Fedora</b> (c-ares), <b>Mageia</b> (python-pillow and upx), <b>Oracle</b> (bind and dhcp, bind9.16, httpd:2.4/mod_http2, kernel, rear, and unbound), <b>SUSE</b> (eclipse, maven-surefire, tycho, emacs, kubevirt, virt-api-container, virt-controller-container, virt-exportproxy-container, virt-exportserver-container, virt-handler-container, virt-launcher-container, virt-libguestfs-t, nodejs16, nodejs18, nodejs20, texlive, vim, webkit2gtk3, and xen), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (gnutls28, klibc, libvirt, nodejs, and webkit2gtk).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970036/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 14:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>OpenSSF and OpenJS warn about social-engineering attacks</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/969919/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Open Source Security Foundation and the OpenJS Foundation have jointly
posted <a
href="https://openssf.org/blog/2024/04/15/open-source-security-openssf-and-openjs-foundations-issue-alert-for-social-engineering-takeovers-of-open-source-projects/">a
warning about XZ-like social-engineering attacks</a> after OpenJS was
seemingly targeted.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	The OpenJS Foundation Cross Project Council received a suspicious
	series of emails with similar messages, bearing different names and
	overlapping GitHub-associated emails. These emails implored OpenJS
	to take action to update one of its popular JavaScript projects to
	"address any critical vulnerabilities," yet cited no specifics. The
	email author(s) wanted OpenJS to designate them as a new maintainer
	of the project despite having little prior involvement.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/969919/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 16:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/969873/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (bind, bind and dhcp, bind9.16, gnutls, httpd:2.4/mod_http2, squid:4, and unbound), <b>Debian</b> (kernel, trafficserver, and xorg-server), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, kernel, libopenmpt, and rust-h2), <b>Mageia</b> (apache-mod_jk, golang, indent, openssl, perl-HTTP-Body, php, rear, ruby-rack, squid, varnish, and xfig), <b>Oracle</b> (bind, squid, unbound, and X.Org server), <b>Red Hat</b> (bind and dhcp and unbound), <b>Slackware</b> (less and php), <b>SUSE</b> (gnutls, python-Pillow, webkit2gtk3, xen, xorg-x11-server, and xwayland), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (yard).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/969873/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 13:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>