<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:29:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Bootc 1.1.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994962/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/containers/bootc/releases/tag/v1.1.0">Version 1.1.0</a> of the <a
href="https://containers.github.io/bootc/">bootc</a> utility for
performing transactional, in-place operating system updates using <a
href="https://opencontainers.org/">Open Container Initative</a> (OCI)
images, has been released. This release "<q>officially stabilizes all
APIs</q>" for bootc and includes a number of bug fixes. LWN <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/979182/">covered bootc</a> in June.</p>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994962/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 16:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994941/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (asterisk, chromium, php-horde-mime-viewer, and php-horde-turba), <b>Fedora</b> (apache-commons-io, buildah, chromium, containers-common, libarchive, libdigidocpp, oath-toolkit, podman, rust-hyper-rustls, rust-reqwest, rust-rustls-native-certs, rust-rustls-native-certs0.7, rust-tonic, rust-tonic-build, rust-tonic-types, rust-tower, rust-tower-http, rust-tower-http0.5, rust-tower0.4, thunderbird, and unbound), <b>SUSE</b> (buildah, chromedriver, chromium, element-desktop, element-web, jetty-annotations, nodejs-electron, php7, php74, php8, podman, python3-virtualbox, qemu, thunderbird, and valkey), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (amd64-microcode).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994941/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 14:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A vulnerability in the Guix build system</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994865/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The 
<a href="https://guix.gnu.org/">
Guix</a> project has
<a href="https://guix.gnu.org/blog/2024/build-user-takeover-vulnerability/">
disclosed</a> a security vulnerability in the build daemon that the distribution uses to build and install software locally. The vulnerability allows an existing unprivileged user to get access to a 
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Setuid">
setuid</a> binary, and from there potentially interfere with any other software built or installed on the computer. The project recommends upgrading the guix daemon now, to avoid the issue.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
This exploit requires the ability to start a derivation build and the
ability to run arbitrary code with access to the store in the root PID
namespace on the machine the build occurs on. As such, this represents
an increased risk primarily to multi-user systems and systems using
dedicated privilege-separation users for various daemons: without
special sandboxing measures, any process of theirs can take advantage
of this vulnerability.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994865/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 13:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.12-rc4</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994843/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has released <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/994842/">6.12-rc4</a> for testing.
"<q>I'm not happy with how big this is - it's probably far from the biggest
rc4 ever, but it _is_ the biggest rc4 we've had in the 6.x series at least
in number of commits.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994843/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 22:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994703/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (java-1.8.0-openjdk, java-11-openjdk, java-17-openjdk, java-21-openjdk, and webkit2gtk3), <b>Debian</b> (apache2), <b>Red Hat</b> (expat), <b>SUSE</b> (cups-filters, jetty-minimal, OpenIPMI, and python-starlette), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-azure, linux-azure, linux-azure-5.15, linux-azure, linux-azure-5.4, and oath-toolkit).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994703/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 13:25:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rust 1.82.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994654/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2024/10/17/Rust-1.82.0.html">Version
1.82.0</a> of the Rust language has been released.  There are a lot of new
features this time, including a <tt>cargo info</tt> command, tier-1 support
for 64-bit Apple Arm systems, a new native syntax (<tt>&amp;raw</tt>) to create
raw pointers, changes to <tt>unsafe extern</tt>, unsafe attributes,
standardized rules around the handling of floating-point not-a-number
values, and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994654/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 18:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Five new stable kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994632/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Greg Kroah-Hartman has announced the release of the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/994633/">6.11.4</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/994634/">6.6.57</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/994635/">6.1.113</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/994636/">5.15.168</a>, and <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/994637/">5.10.227</a> stable kernels.  As usual, this set
of updates contains a long list of important fixes throughout the kernel
tree.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994632/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 15:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994630/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (python-cryptography), <b>Fedora</b> (dnsdist and python-virtualenv), <b>Red Hat</b> (java-1.8.0-openjdk, java-11-openjdk, java-17-openjdk, and java-21-openjdk), <b>Slackware</b> (libssh2 and mozilla), <b>SUSE</b> (haproxy, keepalived, libarchive, libnss_slurm2, php8, and python310-pytest-html), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.15, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.15, linux-gkeop,
 linux-gkeop-5.15, linux-hwe-5.15, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.15,
 linux-intel-iotg, linux-intel-iotg-5.15, linux-kvm, linux-lowlatency,
 linux-lowlatency-hwe-5.15, linux-nvidia, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-5.15,
 linux-raspi, linux-xilinx-zynqmp, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.4, linux-bluefield, linux-gcp,
 linux-gcp-5.4, linux-gkeop, linux-hwe-5.4, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.4,
 linux-kvm, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-5.4, linux-raspi, linux-raspi-5.4,
 linux-xilinx-zynqmp, and linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-6.8, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-6.8, linux-hwe-6.8,
 linux-ibm, linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-6.8, linux-nvidia,
 linux-nvidia-6.8, linux-nvidia-lowlatency, linux-oem-6.8, linux-oracle,
 linux-oracle-6.8, linux-raspi).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994630/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 15:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for October 10, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992718/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for October 10, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992718/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 01:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Improving bindgen for the kernel</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992693/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
<a href="https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-bindgen/">
Bindgen</a> is a widely used tool that automatically generates Rust bindings from C
headers. The
<a href="https://rust-for-linux.com/">
Rust-for-Linux</a> project uses it to create some of
the bindings between Rust code and the rest of the kernel. John Baublitz
presented at Kangrejos about the improvements that he has made to the tool in
order to make the generated bindings easier to use, including improved support
for macros, bitfields, and enums.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992693/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 17:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The Open Source Pledge: peer pressure to pay maintainers</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993073/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In the early days of open source, it was a struggle to get companies
to accept the concept and trust its development model.
Now, companies have few qualms about using it, but do tend to <a
href="https://www.goodtechthings.com/oss-sos/">take open source and
those who maintain it for granted</a>. The struggle now is to find ways
to compensate producers of the software, sustain the open&#8209;source
commons, and avoid burning out maintainers. The <a
href="https://opensourcepledge.com/">Open Source Pledge</a> project is
an effort to persuade companies to pay maintainers by making it a social
norm. On October&nbsp;8, the project is launching a marketing campaign to raise
awareness and try to get a larger conversation started around paying
maintainers.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993073/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 20:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Efficient Rust tracepoints</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992455/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Alice Ryhl has been working to enable
<a href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/latest/trace/tracepoints.html">
tracepoints</a> — which are widely used
throughout the kernel — to be seamlessly placed in Rust code as well. She spoke
about her approach at Kangrejos. Her
<a href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20241001-tracepoint-v9-0-1ad3b7d78acb@google.com/">
patch set</a>
enables efficient use of static
tracepoints, but supporting dynamic tracepoints will take some additional effort.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992455/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 13:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] ClassicPress: WordPress without the block editor</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992219/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/991906/">recent WordPress
controversy</a> is not the first time there's been tension between the
<a
href="https://wordpress.org/">WordPress</a> community, the interests of <a
href="https://automattic.com/">Automattic</a> as a business, and Matt
Mullenweg's leadership as WordPress's benevolent dictator for
life (BDFL). In particular, Mullenweg's focus on pushing WordPress to use a new
"editing experience" called <a
href="https://wordpress.org/gutenberg/">Gutenberg</a> caused significant
friction&mdash;and led to the <a
href="https://www.classicpress.net/">ClassicPress</a> fork. Users who
want to preserve the "classic" WordPress experience without straying
too far from the WordPress fold may want to look into ClassicPress.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992219/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 17:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] In search of the AOSP community</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992992/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The core of the Android operating system, as represented by the <a
href="https://source.android.com/">Android Open Source Project</a> (AOSP),
can only be considered one of the most successful open-source initiatives
ever created; its user count is measured in the billions.  But few would
consider it to be a truly community-oriented project.  At the 2024 <a
href="https://lpc.events/">Linux Plumbers Conference</a>, Chris Simmonds
asked why the AOSP community is so hard to find, and what might be done
about the situation.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992992/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 16:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Smart pointers for the kernel</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992055/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Rust has a plethora of smart-pointer types, including reference-counted
pointers, which have special support in the compiler to make them
easier to use. The Rust-for-Linux project would like to reap those same benefits
for its smart pointers, which need to be written by hand to conform to
the
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/718628/">
Linux kernel
memory model</a>. Xiangfei Ding
presented at Kangrejos about the work to enable custom
smart pointers to function the same as built-in smart pointers.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992055/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 16:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Coping with complex cameras</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992411/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Cameras were never the simplest of devices for Linux to support; they have
a wide range of operating parameters and can generate high rates of data.
In recent years, though, they have become increasingly complex, stressing
the ability of the kernel's <a
href="https://docs.kernel.org/userspace-api/media/index.html">media
subsystem</a> to manage them.  At the 2024 <a
href="https://lpc.events/">Linux Plumbers Conference</a>, developers from
that subsystem and beyond gathered to discuss the state of affairs and how
complex camera devices should be supported in the future.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992411/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 12:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Forgejo 9.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994515/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://forgejo.org/2024-10-release-v9-0/">Version 9.0</a> of the
Forgejo software forge system has been released.  Changes include a switch
to the GPLv3 license, the beginning of a quota system, the removal of
go-git support, and a lot of fixes.
(LWN <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/963095/">looked at Forgejo</a> in February).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994515/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 18:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994436/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (buildah, containernetworking-plugins, and skopeo), <b>Fedora</b> (pdns-recursor and valkey), <b>Mageia</b> (unbound), <b>Red Hat</b> (fence-agents, firefox, java-11-openjdk, python-setuptools, python3-setuptools, resource-agents, and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (etcd-for-k8s, libsonivox3, rubygem-puma, and unbound), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (apr, libarchive, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-hwe, linux-azure-4.15, linux-gcp,
 linux-gcp-4.15, linux-hwe, linux-kvm, linux-oracle, nano, and vim).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994436/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 13:24:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>LibreSSL 4.0.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994320/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://ftp.openbsd.org/pub/OpenBSD/LibreSSL/libressl-4.0.0-relnotes.txt">Version 4.0.0</a> of the <a
href="https://www.libressl.org/">LibreSSL</a> TLS/cryptography stack
has been released. Changes include a cleanup of the MD4 and MD5
implementations, removal of unused DSA methods, changes in libtls
protocol parsing to ignore unsupported TLSv1.1 and TLSv1.0 protocols,
and many more internal changes and bug fixes.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994320/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994268/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (container-tools:rhel8, firefox, OpenIPMI, podman, and thunderbird), <b>Debian</b> (libapache-mod-jk, php7.4, and webkit2gtk), <b>Fedora</b> (edk2, koji, libgsf, rust-hyper-rustls, rust-reqwest, rust-rustls-native-certs, rust-rustls-native-certs0.7, rust-tonic, rust-tonic-build, rust-tonic-types, rust-tower, rust-tower-http, rust-tower-http0.5, and rust-tower0.4), <b>Mageia</b> (packages and thunderbird), <b>Oracle</b> (bind, container-tools:ol8, kernel, kernel-container, OpenIPMI, podman, and thunderbird), <b>Red Hat</b> (container-tools:rhel8, containernetworking-plugins, podman, and skopeo), <b>SUSE</b> (argocd-cli, bsdtar, keepalived, kernel, kyverno, libmozjs-115-0, libmozjs-128-0, libmozjs-78-0, OpenIPMI, opensc, php8, thunderbird, and xen), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (configobj, haproxy, imagemagick, nginx, and postgresql-10, postgresql-9.3).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994268/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 13:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Inkscape 1.4 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/994098/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://inkscape.org/news/2024/10/13/inkscape-launches-version-14-powerful-new-accessib/">Version
1.4</a> of the <a href="https://inkscape.org/">Inkscape</a>
open-source vector-graphics editor has been released. Highlights of
this release include a filter gallery, import for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affinity_Designer">Affinity Designer</a>
files, internal links in exported PDFs, and more. See the <a
href="https://inkscape.org/doc/release_notes/1.4/Inkscape_1.4.html">release
notes</a> for all of the new features. LWN <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/991732/">previewed</a> the 1.4 release
in early October.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/994098/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 18:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>