<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 04:52:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 05:10:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003381/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (containernetworking-plugins, edk2:20240524, gstreamer1-plugins-base, gstreamer1-plugins-good, kernel, libsndfile:1.0.31, mpg123:1.32.9, pam, php:8.1, php:8.2, python3.11, python3.11-urllib3, python3.12, python3.9:3.9.21, skopeo, and unbound:1.16.2), <b>Debian</b> (intel-microcode), <b>Fedora</b> (python3-docs and python3.12), <b>Mageia</b> (emacs), <b>Red Hat</b> (podman), and <b>SUSE</b> (gdb, govulncheck-vulndb, libparaview5_12, mozjs115, mozjs78, and vhostmd).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003381/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 15:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Fedora Linux 41 election results</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003303/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Fedora Project has <a
href="https://communityblog.fedoraproject.org/f41-election-results/">announced</a>
the results of the Fedora Linux 41 election cycle. Five seats were
open on the <a
href="https://docs.fedoraproject.org/en-US/fesco/">Fedora Engineering
Steering Committee</a> (FESCo), and the <a
href="https://elections.fedoraproject.org/about/f41%20fesco%20election">winners</a>
are Kevin Fenzi, Zbigniew Jędrzejewski-Szmek, David Cantrell, Tomáš
Hrčka, and Fabio Alessandro Locati. One seat was open on the <a
href="https://docs.fedoraproject.org/en-US/mindshare-committee/">Mindshare
Committee</a> and that went to Luis Bazan as the only eligible
candidate nominated in this period.</p>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003303/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:56:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003287/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (gst-plugins-base1.0, libxstream-java, php-laravel-framework, python-urllib3, and sqlparse), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, libcomps, libdnf, mingw-directxmath, mingw-gstreamer1, mingw-gstreamer1-plugins-bad-free, mingw-gstreamer1-plugins-base, mingw-gstreamer1-plugins-good, mingw-orc, ofono, prometheus-podman-exporter, python3-docs, python3.13, and webkitgtk), <b>Mageia</b> (mozjs78, thunderbird, and tomcat, tomcat packages), <b>SUSE</b> (aalto-xml, flatten-maven-plugin, jctools, moditect, netty, netty-tcnative, chromedriver, govulncheck-vulndb, grpc, kernel, python-aiohttp, python-python-sql, and vim), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux, linux-gkeop, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.15, linux-kvm,
 linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-5.15, linux-oracle-5.15 and linux-aws, linux-aws-5.4, linux-bluefield, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.4,
 linux-oracle, linux-oracle-5.4, linux-xilinx-zynqmp).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003287/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.13-rc4</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003223/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has released <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1003222/">6.13-rc4</a> for testing.
"<q>So this definitely is looking a bit smaller than most rc4s, and I
expect (and hope) that rc5 will be absolutely tiny because you should
all already be relaxing over the xmas holidays.

But hey, if somebody is out there keeping the lights on, please do
keep testing.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003223/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 22:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Darktable 5.0.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003200/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://www.darktable.org/2024/12/darktable-5.0.0-released/">Version
5.0.0</a> of the <a href="https://www.darktable.org/">darktable</a>
photography workflow application has been released. Major changes in
this release include user-interface/user-experience (UI/UX)
improvements, speed improvements for bulk operations, and the addition
of a <tt>inter-script-communication</tt> event to allow a running
script to send messages to another running script. LWN last <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/881853/">looked at darktable</a> in
2022.</p>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003200/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 15:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Stenberg: Dropping hyper</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003161/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Curl maintainer Daniel Stenberg <a
href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2024/12/21/dropping-hyper/">announces</a>
that the curl project will be dropping hyper, its experimental HTTP backend
written in Rust, due to lack of developer interest.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	While the experiment itself is deemed a failure, I think we learned
	from it and improved curl in the process. We had to rethink and
	reassess several implementation details when we aligned HTTP
	behavior with hyper. libcurl parses and handles HTTP stricter
	now. Better.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003161/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Grml 2024.12 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003048/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blog.grml.org/archives/418-Grml-new-stable-release-2024.12-available.html">Version 2024.12</a> of the Debian-based <a href="https://grml.org/">Grml</a> live Linux system for system administrators has been released. Grml 2024.12 uses packages from the upcoming Debian 13 ("trixie") release. It drops support for 32-bit x86 PCs and gains support for 64-bit ARM CPUs. See the <a href="https://grml.org/changelogs/README-grml-2024.12/">release notes</a> for a full list of changes and new features.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003048/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:38:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003019/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (chromium and gunicorn), <b>Fedora</b> (jupyterlab), <b>Oracle</b> (bluez, containernetworking-plugins, edk2:20220126gitbb1bba3d77, edk2:20240524, gstreamer1-plugins-base, gstreamer1-plugins-good, kernel, libsndfile, libsndfile:1.0.31, mpg123, mpg123:1.32.9, pam, python3.11-urllib3, skopeo, tuned, and unbound:1.16.2), <b>SUSE</b> (avahi, docker, emacs, govulncheck-vulndb, haproxy, kernel, libmozjs-128-0, python-grpcio, python310-xhtml2pdf, sudo, and tailscale), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (dpdk, linux-hwe-5.15, and linux-iot).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003019/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A new set of stable kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002917/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1002918/">6.12.6</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1002919/">6.6.67</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1002920/">6.1.121</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1002921/">5.15.175</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1002922/">5.10.232</a>, and <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1002923/">5.4.288</a> stable kernels have been released.
As usual, they contain important fixes throughout the kernel tree.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002917/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 18:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002903/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (bluez, edk2:20220126gitbb1bba3d77, gstreamer1-plugins-base, gstreamer1-plugins-good, kernel, kernel-rt, mpg123, php:8.2, python3.11-urllib3, and tuned), <b>Fedora</b> (ColPack, glibc, golang-github-chainguard-dev-git-urls, golang-github-task, icecat, python-nbdime, python3.13, and python3.14), <b>Mageia</b> (kernel, kmod-xtables-addons, kmod-virtualbox, dwarves and kernel-linus), <b>Red Hat</b> (gstreamer1-plugins-base and gstreamer1-plugins-good), <b>SUSE</b> (curl, emacs, git-bug, glib2, helm, kernel, and traefik2), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (gst-plugins-base1.0, gst-plugins-good1.0, gstreamer1.0, libvpx, linux-gcp, phpunit, and yara).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002903/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Fish shell announces 4.0 release</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002820/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
<tt>fish</tt> is a shell with a custom language and several affordances not available out of the box in other shells, such as directory-sensitive command completion. Although the project does not normally make beta releases, the 
<a href="https://fishshell.com/blog/fish-4b/">
newly announced 4.0 release</a>
will have one in order to ensure that no problems were introduced
<a href="https://github.com/fish-shell/fish-shell/discussions/10123">
after a major effort to switch the code base from C++ to Rust</a>.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>
fish is a smart and user-friendly command line shell with clever features that just work, without needing an advanced degree in bash scriptology. Today we are announcing an open beta, inviting all users to try out the upcoming 4.0 release.
</p>

<p>
fish 4.0 is a big upgrade. It's got lots of new features to make using the command line easier and more enjoyable, such as more natural key binding and expanded history search. And under the hood, we've rebuilt the foundation in Rust to embrace modern computing.
</p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002820/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 14:24:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for December 12, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000812/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for December 12, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000812/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A look at CentOS Stream 10</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986792/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a
href="https://docs.redhat.com/en/documentation/red_hat_enterprise_linux/10-beta/html/10.0_beta_release_notes/index">Red
Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) 10 beta</a> was released in mid-November
and, if all goes according to plan, <a
href="https://www.centos.org/centos-stream/">CentOS&nbsp;Stream</a>&nbsp;10
should be released before the end of the year. While nothing is etched
in stone just yet, it is a good time for anyone using or targeting
RHEL (and its clones) to start taking a look at how Stream&nbsp;10,
and the corresponding <a
href="https://docs.fedoraproject.org/en-US/epel/epel-about/">EPEL</a>
repository, is shaping up. This is not only important to RHEL and
Stream users, but anyone deploying and supporting software on
enterprise Linux (EL) derivatives like AlmaLinux, Oracle&nbsp;Linux,
and Rocky&nbsp;Linux as well.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986792/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 19:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Auto-tuning the kernel</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998576/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The Linux kernel has many tunable parameters. While there is much advice
available on the internet about how to set them, few people have the time to
weed through the (often contradictory) explanations and choose appropriate
values. One possible way to address this is
<a href="https://blogs.oracle.com/linux/post/introducing-bpftune">
a project called bpftune</a>, a
program that uses BPF to track various metrics about a running system and
adjust the sysctl knobs appropriately. The program is developed by Oracle, and
is available under a GPLv2 license. Bpftune is currently mostly
focused on optimizing network settings, but the authors hope that the system is
flexible enough to be extended to cover other settings.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998576/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 14:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A Zephyr-based camera trap for seagrass monitoring</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998893/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In a session at
<a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/open-source-summit-europe/">Open Source Summit Europe</a>
(OSSEU) back in September, Alex Bucknall gave an overview of a camera "trap"—a
device to capture images in a non-intrusive way—that he helped develop 
which is being used to monitor <a
href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seagrass">seagrass</a>.  He works for
the <a href="https://arribada.org/">Arribada Initiative</a>, which is a
non-profit organization
focused on creating open-source technology for studying wildlife and ecosystems.
The camera system uses the <a href="https://zephyrproject.org/">Zephyr</a>
realtime operating system (RTOS) on an open platform that is designed to be
inexpensive and usable for multiple applications.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998893/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 16:38:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Finally continuing the discussion over continue in finally</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000635/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
In 2019, the Python community had a
<a href="https://discuss.python.org/t/pep-601-forbid-return-break-continue-breaking-out-of-finally/2239">
lengthy discussion</a> about changing the rules (that some find counterintuitive) on
using <tt>break</tt>, <tt>continue</tt>, or <tt>return</tt> statements in
<tt>finally</tt> blocks. These are all ways of jumping out of a <tt>finally</tt>
block, which can interrupt the handling of a raised exception.
At the time, the Python developers chose not to change
things, because the consensus was that the existing behavior was not a problem. Now, after
<a href="https://github.com/iritkatriel/finally/blob/main/README.md">a
report</a> put together by Irit Katriel, the project is once again considering
changing the language.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000635/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 15:33:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Freezing out the page reference count</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000654/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a
href="https://elixir.bootlin.com/linux/v6.12.1/source/include/linux/mm_types.h#L35"><tt>page</tt>
structure</a> sits at the core of the kernel's memory-management subsystem
(for now), and a key part of that structure is its reference count, stored
in <tt>refcount</tt>.  The page reference count tells the kernel how many
users a given page has and when it can be freed.  That count is not needed
for every page in the system, though.  Matthew Wilcox has recently <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20241125210149.2976098-1-willy@infradead.org">resurrected</a>
an <a href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-mm/20220809171854.3725722-1-willy@infradead.org/">old
patch set</a> that expands the concept of a "frozen" page — one that lacks a
meaningful reference count — to the immediate benefit of the slab allocator
but in the service of a longer-term goal as well.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000654/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 15:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Debian opens a can of username worms</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000485/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>It has long been said that <a
href="https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TwoHardThings.html">naming things
is one of the hard things to do in computer science</a>. That may be
so, but it pales in comparison to the challenge of handling
usernames properly in applications. This is especially true when multiple
applications are involved, and they are all supposed to agree on what
characters are, and are not, allowed. The Debian project is facing
that problem right now, as two user-creation utilities disagreed about
which names are allowable. A plan is in place to sort this out
before the release of Debian&nbsp;13 ("trixie") sometime next year.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1000485/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002703/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (libsndfile, php:7.4, python3.11, python3.12, and python36:3.6), <b>Debian</b> (dpdk), <b>Mageia</b> (curl and socat), <b>Oracle</b> (firefox and tuned), <b>Red Hat</b> (bluez, containernetworking-plugins, edk2, edk2:20220126gitbb1bba3d77, edk2:20240524, expat, gstreamer1-plugins-base, gstreamer1-plugins-base and gstreamer1-plugins-good, gstreamer1-plugins-good, kernel, libsndfile, libsndfile:1.0.31, mpg123, mpg123:1.32.9, pam, python3.11-urllib3, skopeo, tuned, unbound, and unbound:1.16.2), <b>SUSE</b> (cloudflared, curl, docker, firefox, gstreamer-plugins-good, kernel, libmozjs-115-0, libmozjs-128-0, libmozjs-78-0, libsoup, ovmf, python-urllib3_1, subversion, thunderbird, and traefik), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (editorconfig-core, libspring-java, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-6.8, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-6.8, linux-gke,
 linux-gkeop, linux-ibm, linux-nvidia, linux-nvidia-6.8,
 linux-nvidia-lowlatency, linux-oem-6.8, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-6.8,
 linux-raspi, linux, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.15, linux-gke, linux-gkeop, linux-ibm,
 linux-ibm-5.15, linux-kvm, linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-5.15,
 linux-nvidia, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-5.15, linux-raspi, linux, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.4, linux-hwe-5.4, linux-kvm, linux-raspi, linux, linux-lowlatency, linux-oracle, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.15, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.4, linux-bluefield, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-5.4, and linux-oem-6.11).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002703/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>