<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 19:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 20:22:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Ubuntu 24.04 LTS (Noble Numbat) released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971175/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Version 24.04 LTS of the Ubuntu distribution is out.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	This release continues Ubuntu's proud tradition of integrating the
	latest and greatest open source technologies into a high-quality,
	easy-to-use Linux distribution. The team has been hard at work
	through this cycle, together with the community and our partners,
	to introduce new features and fix bugs.
</blockquote>
<p>
The list of changes and enhancements is long; click below for some details.
More information can be found in <a
href="https://discourse.ubuntu.com/t/noble-numbat-release-notes/">the
release notes</a>;  see also <a
href="https://ubuntu.com/blog/whats-new-in-security-for-ubuntu-24-04-lts">this
page</a> for a summary of security-related changes.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971175/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 15:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971140/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (curl, filezilla, flatpak, kubernetes, libfilezilla, thunderbird, and xen), <b>Oracle</b> (go-toolset:ol8, kernel, libreswan, shim, and tigervnc), <b>Red Hat</b> (buildah, gnutls, libreswan, tigervnc, and unbound), <b>SUSE</b> (cockpit-wicked, nrpe, and python-idna), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (dnsmasq, freerdp2, linux-azure-6.5, and thunderbird).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971140/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 14:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for April 18, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/969442/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for April 18, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/969442/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Managing to-do lists on the command line with Taskwarrior</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/969904/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Managing to-do lists is something of a universal necessity. While some
people handle them mentally or on paper, others resort to a web-based tool or
a mobile 
application. For those preferring the command line, the MIT-licensed <a
href="https://taskwarrior.org">Taskwarrior</a> offers a flexible solution
with a healthy community and lots of extensions.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/969904/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 15:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Identifying dependencies used via dlopen()</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/969908/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/967180">
The recent XZ backdoor</a> has sparked a lot of discussion about how the open-source
community links and packages software. One possible
security improvement being discussed
is changing how
projects like systemd link to dynamic libraries that are only used for
optional functionality: using
<a href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man3/dlopen.3.html">
<tt>dlopen()</tt></a> to load those libraries only
when required. This could
shrink the attack surface exposed by dependencies, but the approach is not
without downsides — most prominently, it makes discovering which dynamic
libraries a program depends on harder.
On April 11, Lennart Poettering proposed one way to eliminate that problem
<a href="https://github.com/systemd/systemd/pull/32234">
in a systemd RFC on GitHub</a>.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/969908/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 19:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Fedora 40 firms up for release</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/969145/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Fedora&nbsp;40&nbsp;Beta was <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/announcing-fedora-linux-40-beta/">released</a>
on March&nbsp;26, and the final release is nearing completion. So far,
the release is coming together nicely with major
updates for GNOME, KDE&nbsp;Plasma, and the usual cavalcade of
smaller updates and enhancements. As part of the release, the project also scuttled <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Changes/Drop_Delta_RPMs">Delta
RPMs</a> and <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Changes/RemoveOpensslCompat">OpenSSL 1.1</a>.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/969145/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 16:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Cleaning up after BPF exceptions</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/969185/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Kumar Kartikeya Dwivedi has been working to add support for exceptions to BPF
since mid-2023. In July, Dwivedi posted
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/938435/">
the first patch set</a> in this effort, which adds support for basic stack unwinding.
In February 2024, he posted
<a href="https://lwn.net/ml/bpf/20240201042109.1150490-1-memxor@gmail.com/">
the second patch set</a>
aimed at letting the kernel release resources held by the BPF program when an
exception occurs. This makes exceptions usable in many more contexts.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/969185/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 14:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Completing the EEVDF scheduler</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/969062/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/925371/">Earliest Virtual Deadline First (EEVDF)
scheduler</a> was merged as an option for the 6.6 kernel.  It represents a
major change to how CPU scheduling is done on Linux systems, but the EEVDF
front has been relatively quiet since then.  Now, though, scheduler
developer Peter Zijlstra has returned from a long absence to post <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-kernel/20240405102754.435410987@infradead.org/">a patch
series</a> intended to finish the EEVDF work.  Beyond some fixes, this work
includes a significant behavioral change and a new feature intended to help
latency-sensitive tasks.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/969062/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 14:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A tale of two troublesome drivers</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/969383/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The kernel project merges dozens of drivers with every development cycle,
and almost every one of those drivers is entirely uncontroversial.
Occasionally, though, a driver submission raises wider questions, leading
to lengthy discussion and, perhaps, opposition.  That is currently the case
with two separate drivers, both with ties to the networking subsystem.  One
of them is hung up on questions of whether (and how) all device
functionality should be made available to user space, while the other has
run into turbulence because it drives a device that is unobtainable outside
of a single company.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/969383/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 14:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A new crash reporter for Firefox</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971006/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
On April 23, Mozilla
<a href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2024/04/porting-a-cross-platform-gui-application-to-rust/">
announced</a> that Firefox's crash reporter has been rewritten in Rust, allowing the
project to address a backlog of issues.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Even though it is important to properly handle main process crashes, the crash
reporter hasn't received significant development in a while (aside from
development to ensure that crash reports and telemetry continue to reliably be
delivered)! It has long been stuck in a local maximum of "good enough" and
"scary to maintain": it features 3 individual GUI implementations (for Windows,
GTK+ for Linux, and macOS), glue code abstracting a few things (mostly in C++,
and Objective-C for macOS), a binary blob produced by obsoleted Apple
development tools, and no test suite. Because of this, there is a backlog of
features and improvements which haven't been acted on.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971006/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 14:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>GitHub comments used to distribute malware (BleepingComputer)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971008/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
BleepingComputer
<a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/github-comments-abused-to-push-malware-via-microsoft-repo-urls/">
reported</a> on April 20 that some malware was being distributed via GitHub.
Uploading files as part of a comment gives them a URL that appears to be
associated with a repository, even if the comment is never posted.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>
A GitHub flaw, or possibly a design decision, is being abused by threat actors
to distribute malware using URLs associated with Microsoft repositories, making
the files appear trustworthy.
</p>

<p>
While most of the malware activity has been based around the Microsoft GitHub
URLs, this "flaw" could be abused with any public repository on GitHub, allowing
threat actors to create very convincing lures.
</p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971008/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 14:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>QEMU 9.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971007/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.qemu.org/2024/04/23/qemu-9-0-0/">Version 9.0</a> of
the QEMU emulator has been released.  "<q>This release contains 2700+
commits from 220 authors.</q>"  The list of improvements is long; see the
announcement and <a href="https://wiki.qemu.org/ChangeLog/9.0">the
changelog</a> for details.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971007/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 13:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971004/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (abseil-cpp, chromium, filezilla, libfilezilla, and xorg-x11-server-Xwayland), <b>Oracle</b> (firefox, gnutls, golang, java-1.8.0-openjdk, java-11-openjdk, java-17-openjdk, java-21-openjdk, kernel, libreswan, mod_http2, owO: thunderbird, and thunderbird), <b>Red Hat</b> (container-tools:rhel8, gnutls, grub2, kernel, kernel-rt, less, linux-firmware, opencryptoki, pcs, postgresql-jdbc, and thunderbird), <b>Slackware</b> (ruby), <b>SUSE</b> (kubernetes1.23, kubernetes1.24, and opensc), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (firefox, linux-azure, linux-lowlatency, linux-nvidia, and ruby-sanitize).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971004/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Fedora 40 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970893/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Fedora 40 distribution <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/announcing-fedora-linux-40/">has been
released</a>.  See the "what's new" pages for <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/whats-new-fedora-workstation-40/">Fedora
Workstation</a> and <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/whats-new-in-fedora-kde-40/">Fedora
KDE</a> to learn more about the desktop spins, along with <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/969145/">this LWN article</a>, for more information.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970893/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 14:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970889/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (glibc and samba), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, cjson, mingw-python-idna, and pgadmin4), <b>Mageia</b> (kernel, kmod-xtables-addons, kmod-virtualbox, kernel-linus, and perl-Clipboard), <b>Red Hat</b> (go-toolset:rhel8, golang, java-11-openjdk, kpatch-patch, and shim), <b>Slackware</b> (freerdp), <b>SUSE</b> (apache-commons-configuration, glibc, jasper, polkit, and qemu), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (google-guest-agent, google-osconfig-agent, linux-lowlatency-hwe-6.5, pillow, and squid).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970889/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 13:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Open Home Foundation launches</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970835/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Open Home Foundation has <a
href="https://www.openhomefoundation.org/blog/announcing-the-open-home-foundation/">announced
its existence</a> as a home and support resource for free home-automation
projects.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	 We created the Open Home Foundation to fight for the fundamental
	 principles of privacy, choice, and sustainability for smart
	 homes. And every person who lives in one.
<p>
	 Ahead of today, we've transferred over 240 projects, standards,
	 drivers, and libraries—Home Assistant, ESPHome, Zigpy, Piper,
	 Improv Wi-Fi, Wyoming, and so many more—to the Open Home
	 Foundation. This is all about looking into the future. We've done
	 this to create a bulwark against surveillance capitalism, the risk
	 of buyout, and open-source projects becoming abandonware. To an
	 extent, this protection extends even against our future selves—so
	 that smart home users can continue to benefit for years, if not
	 decades. No matter what comes.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970835/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 22:34:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Andreas Tille elected as Debian project leader</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970814/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Debian project leader

<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/970815/">election results are in</a> and Andreas Tille
<a href="https://www.debian.org/vote/2024/vote_001">has been elected</a>.
In a fairly competitive vote, Tille beat Sruthi Chandran to fill the
position for 
the coming year. We <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/967981/">looked at the election and the
candidates</a> a few weeks back.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970814/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 19:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970793/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (firefox and java-1.8.0-openjdk), <b>Debian</b> (chromium, flatpak, guix, openjdk-11, openjdk-17, thunderbird, and tomcat9), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, firefox, glibc, nghttp2, nodejs18, python-aiohttp, python-django3, python-pip, and uxplay), <b>Mageia</b> (putty &amp; filezilla), <b>Red Hat</b> (Firefox, firefox, java-1.8.0-openjdk, java-21-openjdk, nodejs:18, shim, and thunderbird), <b>Slackware</b> (freerdp), <b>SUSE</b> (apache-commons-configuration2, nodejs14, perl-CryptX, putty, shim, and wireshark), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.15, linux-azure-5.15, linux-azure-fde,
 linux-azure-fde-5.15, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.15, linux-gke, linux-gkeop,
 linux-gkeop-5.15, linux-hwe-5.15, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.15,
 linux-intel-iotg, linux-intel-iotg-5.15, linux-kvm,
 linux-lowlatency-hwe-5.15, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-5.15, linux-raspi, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.4, linux-azure, linux-azure-5.4,
 linux-bluefield, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.4, linux-gkeop, linux-hwe-5.4,
 linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.4, linux-iot, linux-kvm, linux-oracle,
 linux-oracle-5.4, linux-raspi, linux-raspi-5.4, linux-xilinx-zynqmp, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-6.5, linux-azure, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-6.5,
 linux-hwe-6.5, linux-laptop, linux-lowlatency, linux-nvidia-6.5,
 linux-oem-6.5, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-6.5, linux-raspi,
 linux-starfive, linux-starfive-6.5, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-hwe, linux-azure, linux-azure-4.15, linux-gcp,
 linux-gcp-4.15, linux-hwe, linux-kvm, linux-oracle, linux, linux-aws, linux-kvm, linux-lts-xenial, lxd, percona-xtrabackup, and pillow).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970793/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 14:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hutterer: udev-hid-bpf: quickstart tooling to fix your HID devices with eBPF</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970702/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Peter Hutterer <a
href="http://who-t.blogspot.com/2024/04/udev-hid-bpf-quickstart-tooling-to-fix.html">announces
udev-hid-bpf</a>, a tool to facilitate the loading of BPF programs that
make human-input devices work correctly.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	eBPF was originally written for network packet filters but as of
	kernel v6.3 and thanks to Benjamin, we have BPF in the HID
	subsystem. HID actually lends itself really well to BPF because,
	well, we have a byte array and to fix our devices we need to do
	complicated things like "toggle that bit to zero" or "swap those
	two values".
</blockquote>
<p>
See <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/909109/">this article</a> for more information on
the BPF-HID mechanism.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970702/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 14:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.9-rc5</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970667/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/970666/">released 6.9-rc5</a> for testing.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	But if you ignore those oddities, it all looks pretty normal and
	things appear fairly calm. Which is just as well, since the first
	part of the week I was on a quick trip to Seattle, and the second
	part of the week I've been doing a passable imitation of the
	Fontana di Trevi, except my medium is mucus.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970667/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 21:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970508/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (gnutls, java-17-openjdk, mod_http2, and squid), <b>Debian</b> (firefox-esr), <b>Fedora</b> (editorconfig, perl-Clipboard, php, rust, and wordpress), <b>Mageia</b> (less, libreswan, puppet, and x11-server, x11-server-xwayland, and tigervnc), <b>Slackware</b> (aaa_glibc), and <b>SUSE</b> (firefox, graphviz, kernel, nodejs12, pgadmin4, tomcat, and wireshark).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970508/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 13:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>