<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 19:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 19:09:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Mate 1.28 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978946/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://mate-desktop.org/blog/2024-02-27-mate-1-28-released/">Version
1.28</a> of the <a href="https://mate-desktop.org/">MATE Desktop</a>
has been released.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
MATE 1.28 has made significant strides in updating the codebase,
including the removal of deprecated libraries and ensuring
compatibility with the latest GTK versions. One of the most notable
improvements is the enhanced support for Wayland, bringing us closer
to a fully native MATE-Wayland experience. Several components have
been updated to work seamlessly with Wayland, ensuring a more
integrated and responsive desktop environment.
</blockquote>

<p>See <a
href="https://github.com/mate-desktop/python-caja/commits/master/">the changelog</a>
for a full list of improvements and bug fixes.</p>

<p> </p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978946/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 16:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Libgcrypt 1.11.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978939/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Version 1.11.0 of Libgcrypt, a general-purpose library of
cryptographic building blocks, has been released by the <a
href="https://gnupg.org/">GnuPG</a> project:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
This release starts a new stable branch of Libgcrypt with full API and
ABI compatibility to the 1.10 series.  Over the last years Jussi
Kivilinna put again a lot of work into speeding up the algorithms for
many commonly used CPUs.  Niibe-san implemented new APIs and algorithms
and also integrated quantum-resistant encryption algorithms.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978939/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 15:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978907/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (container-tools, firefox, and flatpak), <b>Debian</b> (composer, roundcube, and thunderbird), <b>Fedora</b> (kitty and webkitgtk), <b>Oracle</b> (container-tools and flatpak), <b>Red Hat</b> (flatpak and java-1.8.0-ibm), <b>SUSE</b> (gdcm, gdk-pixbuf, libarchive, libzypp, zypper, ntfs-3g_ntfsprogs, openssl-1_1, openssl-3, podman, python-Werkzeug, and thunderbird), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (git, linux-hwe-6.5, mariadb, mariadb-10.6, and thunderbird).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978907/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 13:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Plasma 6.1 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978806/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://kde.org/announcements/plasma/6/6.1.0/">Version 6.1</a> of
the Plasma desktop environment has been released.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Plasma 6 hits its stride with version 6.1. While Plasma 6.0 was all
	about getting the migration to the underlying Qt 6 frameworks
	correct (and what a massive job that was), 6.1 is where developers
	start implementing the features that will take you desktop to a new
	level.
</blockquote>
<p>
Enhancements include better remote-desktop support, improved customization,
persistent apps, smoother animation under Wayland, and more; see <a
href="https://kde.org/announcements/changelogs/plasma/6/6.0.5-6.1.0/">the
changelog</a> for the full list.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978806/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 13:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978804/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (php7.3), <b>Fedora</b> (galera, ghostscript, and mariadb), <b>Mageia</b> (cups, iperf, and libndp), <b>Oracle</b> (firefox and flatpak), <b>Red Hat</b> (container-tools:rhel8, Firefox, firefox, and flatpak), <b>SUSE</b> (booth, bouncycastle, firefox, ghostscript, less, libaom, openssl-1_1, openssl-3, podman, python-Authlib, python-requests, python-Werkzeug, webkit2gtk3, and xdg-desktop-portal), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (ghostscript, ruby-rack, ruby2.7, ruby3.0, ruby3.1, ruby3.2, and sssd).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978804/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 13:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>PostmarketOS v24.06 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978733/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://postmarketos.org/">PostmarketOS</a> is an Alpine Linux
derivative distribution aimed at mobile devices; the <a
href="https://postmarketos.org/blog/2024/06/16/v24.06-release/">v24.06
release</a> claims support for over 250 devices, though the level of that
support varies widely.  "<q>This release is geared mainly towards Linux
enthusiasts. We are working hard on stability improvements and automated
testing, but if you expect Android or iOS levels of polish, then this is
not for you yet.</q>"  Changes include an upgrade to Alpine Linux 3.20,
newer GNOME and KDE versions, and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978733/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 18:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978709/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (389-ds-base, buildah, c-ares, cockpit, containernetworking-plugins, fence-agents, gdk-pixbuf2, gvisor-tap-vsock, libreoffice, podman, python-idna, rpm-ostree, and ruby), <b>Debian</b> (atril, chromium, ffmpeg, libndp, libvpx, nano, plasma-workspace, pymongo, roundcube, sendmail, and thunderbird), <b>Fedora</b> (booth and thunderbird), <b>Mageia</b> (aom, atril, libvpx, nano, nss, firefox, and vte), <b>Red Hat</b> (linux-firmware), <b>SUSE</b> (bind, booth, mariadb, openssl-1_1, php7, php8, and webkit2gtk3), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-azure, linux-azure-fde, linux-azure, linux-gke, and linux-nvidia-6.5).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978709/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 14:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.10-rc4</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978629/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has released <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/978628/">6.10-rc4</a> for testing.
"<q>Apart from a rather unusual spike in the diffstat due to a parisc fix,
things look normal and pretty small.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978629/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 22:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Some weekend stable kernel updates</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978591/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/978592/">6.9.5</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/978593/">6.6.34</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/978594/">6.1.94</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/978595/">5.15.161</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/978596/">5.10.219</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/978597/">5.4.278</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/978598/">4.19.316</a>
stable kernels have all been released; each contains another set of
important fixes.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978591/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 19:10:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Reports from the Python Language Summit</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978541/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Python Software Foundation has published <a
href="https://pyfound.blogspot.com/2024/06/python-language-summit-2024.html">a
set of reports</a> from the 2024 Python Language summit.  Topics covered
include version numbering, the limited C API, a new default read-eval-print
loop, and Python's security model in light of the XZ backdoor:
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	For multiple reasons like being able to fix bugs and
	single-maintainer modules, CPython doesn't require reviewers on the
	pull requests of core developers. This can lead to "unilateral
	action", meaning that a change is introduced into CPython without
	the review of someone besides the author. Other situations like
	release managers backporting fixes to other branches without review
	are common.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978541/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 19:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Schaller: Fedora Workstation development update – AI edition</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978470/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Christian Schaller <a href="https://blogs.gnome.org/uraeus/2024/06/14/fedora-workstation-development-update-artificial-intelligence-edition/">writes about</a> AI and GPU-related features that are in flight and planned for Fedora 41.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Milan Crha has been working together with Alan Day and Jakub Steiner to come up with a <a href="https://gitlab.gnome.org/GNOME/gnome-software/-/merge_requests/2034">streamlined user experience in GNOME Software to let you install the binary NVIDIA driver and provide you with an integrated graphical user interface help to sign the kernel module</a> for use with secure boot. This is a bit different than what we for instance are doing in RHEL, where we are working with NVIDIA to provide pre-signed kernel modules, but that is a lot harder to do in Fedora due to the rapidly updating kernel versions and which most Fedora users appreciate as a big plus. So instead what we are for opting in Fedora is as I said to make it simple for you to self-sign the kernel module for use with secure boot. We are currently looking at when we can make this feature available, but no later than Fedora Workstation 41 for sure.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978470/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 19:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New Human Interface Guidelines for KDE</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978465/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>KDE developer Nate Graham has <a
href="https://pointieststick.com/2024/06/09/new-human-interface-guidelines/">announced</a>
a new set of <a href="https://develop.kde.org/hig/">KDE Human
Interface Guidelines</a> (HIG) for the <a
href="https://kde.org/">KDE</a> project. Graham says that the goals
for the new HIGs were to reflect how KDE designs software today, make
the content 100% actionable, improve navigation, and to improve the
guidelines so people feel comfortable contributing:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Like any rewrite, there are bound to be rough edges and omissions
compared to the old version. Maybe I missed a piece of useful
information in the old HIG that had been buried somewhere but retained
some value. Maybe there's low-hanging fruit for improvement. Help out
by <a href="https://develop.kde.org/hig/#contributing">contributing</a>!
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978465/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 17:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Driving forward in Android drivers (Project Zero)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978441/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a
href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2024/06/driving-forward-in-android-drivers.html">This
Project Zero article</a> looks at the exploitation of a few Android driver
bugs in great detail.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	As it becomes more difficult to find 0-days in core Android,
	third-party Linux kernel drivers continue to become a more and more
	attractive target for attackers. While the bulk of present-day
	detected ITW [in-the-wild] Android exploitation targets GPU
	drivers, it's equally important that other third-party drivers are
	encouraged towards the same security standards.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978441/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 14:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978418/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>CentOS</b> (389-ds-base, bind, bind-dyndb-ldap, and dhcp, firefox, glibc, ipa, less, libreoffice, and thunderbird), <b>Debian</b> (cups), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium and cyrus-imapd), <b>Mageia</b> (golang and poppler), <b>Oracle</b> (bind, bind-dyndb-ldap, and dhcp, gvisor-tap-vsock, python-idna, and ruby), <b>Red Hat</b> (dnsmasq and expat), <b>SUSE</b> (libaom, php8, podman, python-pymongo, python-scikit-learn, and tiff), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (h2database and vte2.91).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978418/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 13:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rust 1.79.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978323/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2024/06/13/Rust-1.79.0.html">Version
1.79.0</a> of the Rust language has been released.  Changes this time
include inline <tt>const</tt> expressions, the "associated item bounds
syntax", and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978323/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 14:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978291/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (firefox-esr), <b>Fedora</b> (nginx-mod-modsecurity, php, and tomcat), <b>Mageia</b> (strongswan), <b>Oracle</b> (389-ds-base, buildah, c-ares, cockpit, containernetworking-plugins, fence-agents, firefox, gdk-pixbuf2, idm:DL1, ipa, kernel, libreoffice, podman, rpm-ostree, and thunderbird), <b>Red Hat</b> (dnsmasq and nghttp2), <b>Slackware</b> (mozilla), <b>SUSE</b> (curl, firefox, kernel, kernel-firmware-nvidia-gspx-G06, nvidia-open- driver-G06-signed, openssl-3, and python-Pillow), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (libmatio, libndp, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.4, linux-azure, linux-azure-5.4, linux-gcp,
 linux-gcp-5.4, linux-gkeop, linux-hwe-5.4, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.4,
 linux-kvm, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-5.4, linux-raspi, linux-raspi-5.4,
 linux-xilinx-zynqmp, linux-oem-6.5, and virtuoso-opensource).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978291/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 14:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for June 6, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/975974/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for June 6, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/975974/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 01:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Measuring and improving buffered I/O</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/976856/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[There are two types of file I/O on Linux, buffered I/O, which goes through
the page cache, and direct I/O, which goes directly to the storage device.
The performance of buffered I/O was reported to be a lot worse than direct
I/O, especially for one specific test, in Luis Chamberlain's 
<a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-fsdevel/Zdkxfspq3urnrM6I@bombadil.infradead.org/">topic
proposal</a> for a session at the 2024 <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>.
The proposal resulted in a lengthy mailing-list discussion, 
which also came up in <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/974487/">Paul McKenney's RCU session</a> the next
day; Chamberlain led a 
combined storage and filesystem session to discuss those results with an
eye toward improving buffered I/O performance.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/976856/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 20:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Rethinking the PostgreSQL CommitFest model</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/976793/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Many years ago, the PostgreSQL project started holding regular <a href="https://wiki.postgresql.org/wiki/CommitFest">CommitFests</a> to
help tackle the work of reviewing and committing patches in a more
organized fashion. That has served the project well, but some in
the project are concerned that CommitFests are no longer meeting
the needs of PostgreSQL or its contributors. A lengthy discussion on the
pgsql-hackers mailing list turned up a number of complaints, a few
suggestions for improvement, but little consensus or momentum toward
a solution.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/976793/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 16:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Removing GFP_NOFS</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/976355/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <tt>GFP_NOFS</tt> flag is meant for kernel memory allocations that
should not cause a call into the filesystems to reclaim memory because there are
already locks held that can potentially cause a deadlock.  The "scoped
allocation" API is a better choice for filesystems to indicate that they
are holding a lock, so <tt>GFP_NOFS</tt> has <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/753078/">long been on the chopping block</a>, though
progress has been slow.  In a filesystem-track session at
the 2024 <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>, Matthew Wilcox wanted to
discuss how to move kernel filesystems away from the flag with the eventual
goal of removing it completely.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/976355/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 15:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Comparing BPF performance between implementations</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/976317/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Alan Jowett returned for a second remote presentation at the 2024
<a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a> to compare the performance of
different BPF runtimes. He showed the results of the MIT-licensed BPF
<a href="https://github.com/microsoft/bpf_performance">
microbenchmark suite</a> he has been working on.
The benchmark suite does not yet provide a good direct comparison between all
platforms, so the results should be
taken with a grain of salt. They do
seem to indicate that there is some significant variation between
implementations, especially for different types of BPF maps.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/976317/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 13:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Handling the NFS change attribute</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/975863/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The saga of the <tt>i_version</tt> field for inodes, which tracks the
occurrence of changes
to the data or metadata of a file, continued in a discussion at the 2024 <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>.  In a session led by
Jeff Layton, who has been doing a lot the work on <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/905931/">changing the semantics and functioning of
<tt>i_version</tt></a> over the years, he updated attendees on the status of the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/946394/">effort</a> since a <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/937247/">session at last year's summit</a>.  His summary
was that things are
"pretty much where we started last year", but the discussion this time
pointed to some possible ways forward.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/975863/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 15:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] An instruction-level BPF memory model</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/976071/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
There are few topics as arcane as memory models, so it was a pleasant surprise
when the double-length session on the BPF memory model at the
<a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a> turned out to be
understandable. Paul McKenney led the session, although he was clear that the
work he was presenting was also due to Puranjay Mohan, who unfortunately could
not attend the summit.
BPF does not actually have a formalized memory model yet;
instead it has relied on a history of talks like this one and a general informal understanding.
Unfortunately, ignoring memory models does not make them go away, and this has
already caused at least one BPF-related bug on weakly-ordered architectures.
Figuring out what a formal memory model for BPF should define was the focus of
McKenney's talk.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/976071/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 13:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Debian&apos;s /tmpest in a teapot</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/975565/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Debian had a major <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/499410/">discussion</a>
about mounting <tt>/tmp</tt> as a RAM-based tmpfs in 2012 but inertia
won out in the end. Debian systems have continued to
store temporary files on disk by default. Until now. A mere 
12 years later, the project will be switching to a RAM-based <tt>/tmp</tt> in the Debian
13 ("Trixie") release. Additionally, starting with Trixie, the
default will be to periodically clean up temporary files automatically in
<tt><nobr>/tmp</nobr></tt> and <tt><nobr>/var/tmp</nobr></tt>. Naturally, it involved a lengthy discussion first.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/975565/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 16:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] One more pidfdfs surprise</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/976125/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The "pidfdfs" virtual filesystem was added to the 6.9 kernel release as a
way to export better information about running processes to user space.  It
replaced a previous implementation in a way that was, on its surface, fully
compatible while adding a number of new capabilities.  This transition,
which was intended to be entirely invisible to existing applications,
already <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/963749/">ran into trouble</a> in March, when a
misunderstanding with SELinux caused systems with pidfdfs to fail to boot
properly.  That problem was quickly fixed, but it turns out that there was
one more surprise in store, showing just how hard ABI compatibility can be
at times.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/976125/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 18:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Standardizing the BPF ISA</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/975830/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
While BPF may be most famous for its use in the Linux kernel, there is actually
a growing effort to standardize BPF for use on other systems. These include
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/857215/">
eBPF for Windows</a>, but also
<a href="https://github.com/iovisor/ubpf">
uBPF</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/qmonnet/rbpf">
rBPF</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/rprinz08/hBPF">
hBPF</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/eunomia-bpf/bpftime">
bpftime</a>, and
others. Some hardware manufacturers are even
considering integrating BPF directly into networking hardware. Dave Thaler
led two sessions about all of the problems that cross-platform use inevitably
brings and the current status of the standardization work at the 2024
<a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/975830/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 20:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] New APIs for filesystems</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/975444/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[A discussion of extensions to the <a
href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man2/statx.2.html"><tt>statx()</tt></a>
system call comes up frequently at the <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>; this year's edition was
no exception.  Kent Overstreet led the first filesystem-only session at the
summit on querying information about filesystems that have subvolumes and
snapshots. While it was billed as a discussion on <tt>statx()</tt>
additions, it ranged more widely over new APIs needed for modern filesystems.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/975444/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 13:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>