<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 06:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 06:13:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Lix makes its second release</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/985484/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
<a href="https://lix.systems">Lix</a>, the fork of Nix that LWN <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/981124/">covered</a> in July, has <a href="https://lix.systems/blog/2024-08-12-lix-2.91-release/">made its second release</a> since forking. This one includes substantial changes to the backend code, including removing a dependency on Bison, and getting a change to the Nix language back upstream.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>
The general theme of Lix 2.91 is to perform another wave of
refactorings and design improvements in preparation for our evolution
plans.
</p>

<p>
Nevertheless, there are a few exciting user facing changes[.]
</p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/985484/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 14:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Incus 6.4 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/985482/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Version 6.4 of the Incus container manager is out.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	This release builds upon the recently added OCI support from Incus
	6.3, making it even easier to run application containers. It also
	adds a number of useful new features for clustered and larger
	environments with more control on the virtual CPU used when live
	migrating VMs and finer grained resource constraints within
	projects.
</blockquote>
<p>
See <a
href="https://discuss.linuxcontainers.org/t/incus-6-4-has-been-released/21323">this
announcement</a> for details.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/985482/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 13:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/985481/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (kernel and roundcube), <b>Fedora</b> (microcode_ctl, pypy, python2.7, and python3.6), <b>Oracle</b> (389-ds-base, httpd, kernel, kernel-container, and linux-firmware), <b>Red Hat</b> (kernel-rt), <b>SUSE</b> (firefox, kubernetes1.23, libqt5-qtbase, openssl-1_1, python-gunicorn, python-Twisted, python-urllib3, and qt6-base), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-aws-5.15, linux-gkeop-5.15, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.15, linux-raspi, linux-azure, linux-azure-5.15, linux-azure-fde, linux-azure-fde-5.15, linux-oem-6.8, linux-oracle-5.15, and qemu).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/985481/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 13:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Magit 4.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/985350/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Version 4.0 of the <a href="https://magit.vc/">Magit</a> text-based
Git user interface for Emacs has been <a href="https://emacsair
.me/2024/08/09/magit-4.0/">released</a>. Changes since the 3.3.0
release include the addition of context menus, a makeover for the
menu-bar menu, new menu commands, and many other new features and bug
fixes. See the <a
href="https://github.com/magit/magit/blob/main/docs/RelNotes/4.0.0.org">release
notes</a> for full details.</p>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/985350/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 16:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rust Project goals for 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/985296/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Rust project has <a
href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2024/08/12/Project-goals.html">developed a
set of goals</a> for the latter half of 2024.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	<a
	href="https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-project-goals/2024h2/rfl_stable.html"><strong>Rust
	for Linux.</strong></a> The <a
	href="https://rust-for-linux.com/">experimental support for Rust
	development in the Linux kernel</a> is a watershed moment for Rust,
	demonstrating to the world that Rust is indeed capable of targeting
	all manner of low-level systems applications. And yet today that
	support rests on a <a
	href="https://github.com/Rust-for-Linux/linux/issues/2">number of
	unstable features</a>, blocking the effort from ever going beyond
	experimental status. For 2024H2 we will work to close the <a
	href="https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-project-goals/2024h2/rfl_stable.html#the-next-six-months">largest
	gaps that block support</a>.
</blockquote>
<p>
Other goals include completing the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/958792/">2024 Rust
Edition</a> and improving the language's async support.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/985296/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 15:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/985336/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (httpd:2.4), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, firefox, frr, neatvnc, nss, python-setuptools, and python3.13), <b>Gentoo</b> (AFLplusplus, Bundler, dpkg, GnuPG, GPAC, libde265, matio, MuPDF, PHP, protobuf, protobuf-python, protobuf-c, rsyslog, Ruby on Rails, and runc), <b>Red Hat</b> (389-ds-base, container-tools:rhel8, and httpd:2.4), <b>SUSE</b> (bind and ca-certificates-mozilla), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-azure).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/985336/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 15:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.11-rc3</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/985233/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has released <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/985232/">6.11-rc3</a> right on
schedule.  "<q>Nothing particularly strange or interesting going on, things
look normal</q>".]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/985233/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 22:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Three weekend stable kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/985198/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/985199/">6.10.4</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/985200/">6.6.45</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/985201/">6.1.104</a>
stable kernel updates have been released; each contains another set of
important updates as usual.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/985198/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 14:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A new kernel-version policy for Ubuntu</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/985043/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Canonical Kernel Team has <a
href="https://discourse.ubuntu.com/t/kernel-version-selection-for-ubuntu-releases/47007">announced</a>
a new policy regarding the version of the kernel that will ship with each
Ubuntu release; the result will generally be the shipping of newer
releases.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	To provide users with the absolute latest in features and hardware
	support, Ubuntu will now ship the absolute latest available version
	of the upstream Linux kernel at the specified Ubuntu release freeze
	date, even if upstream is still in Release Candidate (RC) status.
</blockquote>
<p>
The post goes on to acknowledge that "<q>there are issues with this
approach</q>"; there are a lot of policy details that will apply depending
on just how raw the shipped kernel is.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/985043/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 19:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New attack against the SLUB allocator</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984984/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Researchers from Graz University of Technology have
<a href="https://www.stefangast.eu/papers/slubstick.pdf">published</a> details of a new attack
on the Linux kernel called SLUBstack. The attack uses timing information to turn an ability to trigger use-after-free or double-free bugs into the ability to overwrite page tables, and thence into the ability to read and write arbitrary areas of memory. The good news is that this attack does require an existing bug to be usable; the bad news is that the kernel regularly sees bugs of this kind.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
We assume that an unprivileged user has code execution. 
Additionally, we consider the presence of a heap vulnerability
in the Linux kernel. We assume that the Linux kernel 
incorporates all defense mechanisms available in version 6.4, the
most recent Linux kernel version when we started our work.
These mechanisms include features such as WˆX, KASLR,
SMAP, and kCFI. We do not assume any microarchitectural 
vulnerabilities, e.g., transient execution, fault
injection, or hardware side channels.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984984/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 15:08:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984966/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (httpd, kernel, kernel-rt, and libtiff), <b>Debian</b> (postgresql-13, postgresql-15, and thunderbird), <b>Fedora</b> (frr, thunderbird, vim, and xrdp), <b>Gentoo</b> (Librsvg, Nautilus, ncurses, Percona XtraBackup, QEMU, and re2c), <b>Red Hat</b> (httpd, kernel, kernel-rt, openssl, and python-setuptools), <b>SUSE</b> (bind, ffmpeg-4, kubernetes1.23, kubernetes1.24, python-Django, and python3-Twisted), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.4, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.4, linux-gkeop, linux-hwe-5.4, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.4, linux-iot, linux-kvm, linux-raspi, linux-xilinx-zynqmp, linux, linux-aws, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.15, linux-gke, linux-gkeop, linux-intel-iotg, linux-intel-iotg-5.15, linux-kvm, linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-5.15, linux-nvidia, linux, linux-aws, linux-gcp, linux-gke, linux-ibm, linux-nvidia, linux-nvidia-6.8, linux-oem-6.8, linux-nvidia-lowlatency, linux-oracle, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-5.4, and salt).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984966/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 13:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>0.0.0.0 Day: Exploiting Localhost APIs From the Browser (Oligo Security)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984838/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Oligo Security blog <a
href="https://www.oligo.security/blog/0-0-0-0-day-exploiting-localhost-apis-from-the-browser">discloses</a>
a web-browser vulnerability that has been named "0.0.0.0 day".  In short,
browsers will allow JavaScript code to open connections to the all-zeroes
IPv4 address; the result is that any port that is open on the local host
can be accessed by a remote site.  "<q>When services use localhost, they
assume a constrained environment. This assumption, which can (as in the
case of this vulnerability) be faulty, results in insecure server
implementations.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984838/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984807/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (freeradius and freeradius:3.0), <b>Debian</b> (chromium, odoo, and roundcube), <b>Fedora</b> (microcode_ctl, mingw-qt5-qtbase, mingw-qt6-qtbase, opentofu, orc, python-setuptools, and vim), <b>Gentoo</b> (Nokogiri), <b>Oracle</b> (kernel), <b>Red Hat</b> (go-toolset:rhel8, golang, kernel, krb5, libtiff, python-setuptools, and python39:3.9 and python39-devel:3.9), <b>SUSE</b> (python-Django), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (krb5).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984807/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 13:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for August 1, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983267/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for August 1, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983267/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 04:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Showing up for Python in GNOME</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983897/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>A few years ago, <a
href="https://pygobject.gnome.org/">PyGObject</a>&mdash;the Python
package that provides bindings for <a
href="https://www.gtk.org/">GTK</a> and <a
href="https://www.gnome.org/">GNOME</a> applications&mdash;was not
faring particularly well. Several maintainers had left the project and its
development was not keeping pace with changes in GTK. At this year's
GUADEC, Dan Yeaw presented a <a
href="https://events.gnome.org/event/209/contributions/757/">talk</a>
about the project's decline, improvements in the last year, and his
experience getting involved in an undermaintained project.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983897/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 17:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Pulling Linux up by its bootstraps</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983340/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
A <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/841797/">
bootstrappable build</a> is one that builds existing
software from scratch — for example, building GCC without relying on an existing
copy of GCC. In 2023, the Guix project
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/930650/">announced</a> that the project had reduced the size
of the binary bootstrap seed needed to build its operating system to just 357-bytes —
not counting the Linux kernel required to run the build process. Now, the
<a href="https://github.com/fosslinux/live-bootstrap">live-bootstrap</a> project
has gone a step further and removed the need for an existing kernel at all.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983340/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 13:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Famfs: a filesystem interface to shareable memory</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983105/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[At the 2024 <a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux
Storage, Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>, John Groves led
a session on famfs, which is a filesystem he has developed that uses the
kernel's <a
href="https://docs.kernel.org/filesystems/dax.html">direct-access (DAX)</a>
mechanism to access memory that is shareable between hosts.  The discussion
was aimed at whether a different approach should be taken and, in
particular, whether FUSE should be used instead of implementing as an
in-kernel filesystem.  As noted in the <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20240229002020.85535-1-john@groves.net/">thread</a> about his
proposal for an LSFMM+BPF session, and the mailing-list discussions on <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/cover.1708709155.git.john%40groves.net/">the first</a> and <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-fsdevel/cover.1714409084.git.john@groves.net/">second
version</a> of his patch set, there is some skepticism that a new in-kernel
filesystem is warranted for the use case.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983105/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 21:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Report from the annual general meeting at GUADEC</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983203/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>At <a
href="https://foundation.gnome.org/2023/12/20/guadec-2024-in-denver-colorado/">GUADEC</a>
in Denver, Colorado on July&nbsp;21, the GNOME Foundation held its <a
href="https://events.gnome.org/event/209/contributions/778/">annual
general meeting</a> (AGM) to provide updates from the <a
href="https://wiki.gnome.org/FoundationBoard">foundation's board</a> and committees.
Topics included work accomplished in the past year, challenges
facing the GNOME Foundation–including fundraising and finding a new
executive director–and some insight into plans for the next year. And
last, but not least, the awarding of the <a
href="https://wiki.gnome.org/Pants">Pants of Thanks</a>.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983203/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The rest of the 6.11 merge window</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982605/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The release of <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/CAHk-=wiyNokz0d3b=GRORij=mGvwoYHy=+bv6m2Hu_VqNdg66g@mail.gmail.com/">6.11-rc1</a>
marked the end of the 6.11 merge window on July&nbsp;28.  By that time,
12,102 non-merge changesets had been pulled into the mainline repository;
about 8,000 of those came in after <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/982034/">the
first-half summary</a> was written.  Quite a few significant changes were
to be found in those changesets; there is also one big change that did not
make it.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982605/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 13:54:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] May the FOLL_FORCE not be with you</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983169/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[One of the simplest hardening concepts to understand is that memory should
never be both writable and executable, otherwise an attacker can use it to
load and run arbitrary code.  That rule is generally followed in Linux
systems, but there is a glaring loophole that is exploitable from user
space to inject code into a running process.  Attackers have duly exploited
it.  A new effort to close the hole ran into trouble early in the merge
window, but a solution may yet be found in time for the 6.11 kernel
release.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983169/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] What became of getrandom() in the vDSO</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983186/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/980447/">the previous episode</a> of the
<tt>vgetrandom()</tt> story, Jason Donenfeld had put together a version of
the <a
href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man2/getrandom.2.html"><tt>getrandom()</tt></a>
system call that ran in user space, significantly improving performance for
applications that need a lot of random data while retaining all of the
guarantees provided by the system call.  At that time, it seemed that a
consensus had built around the implementation and that it was headed toward
the mainline in that form.  A few milliseconds after that article was
posted, though, a Linus-Torvalds-shaped obstacle appeared in its path.
That obstacle has been overcome and this work has now been merged for the
6.11 kernel, but its form has changed somewhat.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983186/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 16:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] More informative kernel panics for Fedora</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982398/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
On July 12, Jocelyn Falempe
<a href="https://discussion.fedoraproject.org/t/f42-change-proposal-enable-drm-panic-system-wide/125542">
proposed</a> a change to the configuration options that Fedora sets for its
kernels, in order to make kernel panics easier to report.
Falempe would like to enable the kernel's recently added
DRM-panic feature, which adds
a graphical crash screen that is reminiscent of the infamous
Windows "blue screen of death" for kernel panics. The feature introduces a few
tradeoffs, including currently limited driver support, so the proposal spawned a
good deal of discussion.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982398/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 15:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Firefox support added to Puppeteer</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984733/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Mozilla has <a href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2024/08/puppeteer-support-for-firefox/">announced</a> that <a href="https://pptr.dev/">Puppeteer</a>, a browser automation and testing library, now has first-class support for Firefox using the
<a href="https://w3c.github.io/webdriver-bidi/">WebDriver BiDi</a> protocol. Puppeteer can be used to drive headless browser instances, and is commonly used for automated end-to-end web site tests.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Whilst the features offered by Puppeteer won't be a surprise,
bringing support to multiple browsers has been a significant
undertaking. The Firefox support is not based on a Firefox-specific
automation protocol, but on WebDriver BiDi, a cross browser protocol
that's undergoing standardization at the W3C, and currently has
implementation in both Gecko and Chromium. This use of a
cross-browser protocol should make it much easier to support many
different browsers going forward.  
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984733/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 19:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984702/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (firefox-esr, openjdk-17, and wpa), <b>Gentoo</b> (aiohttp, Bitcoin, Cairo, Go, json-c, Levenshtein, libXpm, nghttp2, PostgreSQL, and Redis), <b>Red Hat</b> (kernel, kernel-rt, python-setuptools, python-urllib3, python3.11-setuptools, and wget), <b>Slackware</b> (mozilla), <b>SUSE</b> (bind, curl, docker, ffmpeg, ffmpeg-4, kernel, kernel-firmware, libnbd, patch, shadow, and thunderbird), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (python-django and wpa).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984702/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 13:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>