<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 13:01:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>A kernel code of conduct enforcement action</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/999197/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The <a href="https://wiki.linuxfoundation.org/tab/start">Linux Foundation Technical
Advisory Board</a> (TAB) has <a href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-kernel/6740fc3aabec0_5eb129497@dwillia2-xfh.jf.intel.com.notmuch/">decided</a> to "<q>restrict Kent Overstreet's
participation in the kernel development process during the Linux 6.13
kernel development cycle</q>" based on a recommendation from the <a
href="https://kernel.org/code-of-conduct.html">Code of Conduct
committee</a>.  In particular, the scope of the restriction will be to "<q>decline all pull
requests from Kent Overstreet</q>" during the development cycle.
Overstreet is the creator and maintainer of the <a
href="https://bcachefs.org/">bcachefs</a> filesystem.

<p>
This
action stems from a <a 
href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-kernel/citv2v6f33hoidq75xd2spaqxf7nl5wbmmzma4wgmrwpoqidhj@k453tmq7vdrk/">message</a>
Overstreet posted back in early September that was abusive toward another
kernel developer; there is a fair amount of back-and-forth about the
incident and the committee's attempts to extract a public apology from
Overstreet in that thread.  Overstreet has published a <a
href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/116412665">lengthy blog post</a>
describing his side of the story.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/999197/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 01:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Four Friday stable kernel updates</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/999107/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/999108/">6.12.1</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/999109/">6.11.10</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/999110/">6.6.63</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/999111/">6.1.119</a> stable kernel updates have been released.
As always, they contain important fixes.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/999107/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 15:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/999102/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (postgresql-13, postgresql-15, and webkit2gtk), <b>Fedora</b> (libsndfile, microcode_ctl, and trafficserver), <b>Mageia</b> (kanboard, kernel, kmod-xtables-addons, kmod-virtualbox, and bluez, kernel-linus, opendmarc, and radare2), <b>Oracle</b> (.NET 9.0, bubblewrap and flatpak, buildah, expat, firefox, grafana, grafana-pcp, kernel, krb5, libsoup, libvpx, NetworkManager-libreswan, openexr, pcp, python3.11, python3.11-urllib3, python3.12, python3.9, squid, thunderbird, tigervnc, and webkit2gtk3), <b>Red Hat</b> (.NET 9.0, binutils, expat, grafana-pcp, kernel, libsoup, NetworkManager-libreswan, openexr, python3.11, python3.12, python39:3.9, squid, tigervnc, and webkit2gtk3), <b>SUSE</b> (chromedriver, cobbler, govulncheck-vulndb, and icinga2), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-6.8, python2.7, and zbar).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/999102/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>PHP 8.4.1 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/999004/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.php.net/archive/2024.php#2024-11-21-4">Version
8.4.1</a> of the PHP language has been released.  See <a
href="https://www.php.net/releases/8.4/en.php">this page</a> for details on
the new features in this release.  "<q>PHP 8.4 is a major update of the PHP
language.  It contains many new features, such as property hooks,
asymmetric visibility, an updated DOM API, performance improvements, bug
fixes, and general cleanup.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/999004/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 23:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998949/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (kernel, NetworkManager-libreswan, and openssl), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium and llvm-test-suite), <b>Mageia</b> (thunderbird), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-aws-6.8, linux-azure, linux-azure-6.8, linux-oracle-6.8,, linux-azure, and ruby2.7).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998949/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 14:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for November 14, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/997293/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for November 14, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/997293/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Truly portable C applications</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/997238/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Programming language polyglots are files that are valid
programs in multiple languages, and do different things in each. While polyglots are normally
nothing more than a curiosity, the
<a href="https://justine.lol/cosmopolitan/index.html">
Cosmopolitan Libc</a> project has been trying
to put them to a novel use: producing native, multi-platform binaries that
run directly on several operating systems and architectures. There are still
some rough edges with the project's approach, but it is generally possible to
build C programs into a polyglot format with with minimal
tweaking.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/997238/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Progress on toolchain security features</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996344/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Over the years, there has been steady progress in adding security features to
compilers and other tools to assist with hardening the Linux kernel (and, of course, other
programs).  In something of a tradition in the <a
href="https://lpc.events/event/18/sessions/180/#20240918">toolchains
track</a> at the <a
href="https://linuxplumbersconf.org">Linux
Plumbers Conference</a>, Kees Cook and Qing Zhao have led a session on that progress and
further plans; this year, they were joined by Justin Stitt  (<a
href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=68PZz_9cPms">YouTube video</a>).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996344/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 20:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The top open-source security events in 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996955/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[What have been the most significant security-related incidents for the
open-source community in 2024 (so far)?  Marta Rybczyńska recently ran a
poll and got some interesting results.  At the 2024 <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/open-source-summit-japan/">Open
Source Summit Japan</a>, she presented those results along with some
commentary of her own.  The events in question are unlikely to be a
surprise to LWN readers, but the overall picture that was presented was
worth a look.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996955/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 15:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Back In Time back from the dead</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996720/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
<a href="https://github.com/bit-team/backintime?tab=readme-ov-file#back-in-time">
Back In Time</a> is a GPL-2.0-licensed backup tool based on
<a href="https://rsync.samba.org/">
rsync</a> and written in Python. It has both graphical and command-line interfaces, and
supports backups to local disks or over SSH.
Back In Time was originally written by
Oprea Dan and released in 2009. The tool has been
through some rough patches over the years, and is currently on its third set of
maintainers. Christian Buhtz, one of the current maintainers, explained to me
how he and his co-maintainers had revived the project, as well as why he thought
Back In Time stood out from all of the existing backup solutions.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996720/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 18:49:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Pondering systemd-homed for Fedora</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/995915/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Fedora Linux, as a rule, handles version upgrades reasonably
well. However, there are times when users may want to do a fresh
installation rather than an upgrade <em>but</em> preserve existing
users and data under <tt>/home</tt>. This is a scenario that the
Fedora installer, currently, does not address. Users can maintain a
separate <tt>/home</tt> partition, of course, but the installer does
not incorporate existing users into the new install&mdash;that is an
exercise left to the user to handle. One solution might be to use <a
href="https://systemd.io/HOME_DIRECTORY/">systemd-homed</a>, a systemd
service for managing users and home directories. However, a discussion
proposing the use systemd-homed as part of Fedora installation
uncovered some hurdles, such as trying to blend its approach to
managing users with tools that centralize user management.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/995915/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 16:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The trouble with struct sockaddr&apos;s fake flexible array</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/997094/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Flexible arrays — arrays that are declared as the final member of a
structure and which have a size determined at run time — have long drawn
the attention of developers seeking to harden the kernel against
buffer-overflow vulnerabilities.  These arrays have reliably been a source
of bugs, so anything that can be done to ensure that operations on them
stay within bounds is a welcome improvement.  While many improvements,
including the recent <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/936728/">counted-by work</a>, have
been made, one of the most difficult cases remains.  Now, however,
developers who are interested in using recent compiler bounds-checking
features are trying to get a handle on <tt>struct sockaddr</tt>.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/997094/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 16:34:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Blender 4.3 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998863/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.blender.org/download/releases/4-3/">Version 4.3</a> of
the Blender animation system has been released.  "<q>Brush assets, faster
sculpting, a revolutionized Grease Pencil, and more. Blender 4.3 got you
covered.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998863/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 15:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Plans for CHICKEN 6</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998856/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
<a href="https://www.call-cc.org/">
CHICKEN Scheme</a>, a portable Scheme compiler, is gearing up for its next major release. Maintainer Felix Winkelmann has
shared
<a href="https://www.more-magic.net/posts/chicken-6.html">
an article</a> about what changes to expect in version 6 of the language, including better Unicode support and support for the
<a href="https://r7rs.org/">
R7RS</a> Scheme standard.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Every major release is a chance of fixing long-standing problems with the codebase and address bad design decisions. CHICKEN is now nearly 25 years old and we had many major overhauls of the system. Sometimes these caused a lot of pain, but still we always try to improve things and hopefully make it more enjoyable and practical for our users. There are places in the code that are messy, too complex, or that require cleanup or rewrite, always sitting there waiting to be addressed. On the other hand CHICKEN has been relatively stable compared to many other language implementations and has a priceless community of users that help us improving it. Our users never stop reminding us of what could be better, where the shortcomings are, where things are hard to use or inefficient.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998856/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 14:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998854/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (guix, libmodule-scandeps-perl, needrestart, and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (gh), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (kernel, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-hwe, linux-azure, linux-azure-4.15, linux-gcp,
 linux-gcp-4.15, linux-hwe, linux-kvm, linux-oracle, linux, linux-aws, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-6.8, linux-gke, linux-hwe-6.8,
 linux-ibm, linux-nvidia, linux-nvidia-6.8, linux-nvidia-lowlatency,
 linux-oem-6.8, linux-oracle, linux-raspi, linux-iot, linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-6.8, needrestart, python2.7, python3.10, python3.12, python3.8, and Waitress).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998854/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 13:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>FreeCAD 1.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998807/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[It took more than 20 years, but the FreeCAD computer-aided design project
has just <a
href="https://blog.freecad.org/2024/11/19/freecad-version-1-0-released/">made
its 1.0 release</a>.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Since the very beginnings, the FreeCAD community had a clear view
	of what 1.0 represented for us. What we wanted in it. FreeCAD
	matured over the years, and that list narrowed down to just two
	major remaining pieces: fixing the toponaming problem, and having a
	built-in assembly module.
<p>
	Well, I'm very proud to say those two issues are now solved.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998807/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 23:59:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rocky Linux 9.5 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998809/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://rockylinux.org/news/rocky-linux-9-5-ga-release">Version
9.5</a> of the Rocky Linux distribution is out.  As with the AlmaLinux 9.5
release, Rocky Linux 9.5 tracks the changes in upstream RHEL 9.5. See <a
href="https://docs.rockylinux.org/release_notes/9_5/">the release notes</a>
for details.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998809/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998755/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (.NET 9.0, bcc, bluez, bpftrace, bubblewrap, flatpak, buildah, cockpit, containernetworking-plugins, cups, cyrus-imapd, edk2, expat, firefox, fontforge, gnome-shell, gnome-shell-extensions, grafana, grafana-pcp, gtk3, httpd, iperf3, jose, krb5, libgcrypt, libsoup, libvirt, libvpx, lldpd, microcode_ctl, mingw-glib2, mod_auth_openidc, nano, NetworkManager, oci-seccomp-bpf-hook, openexr, osbuild-composer, pcp, podman, poppler, postfix, python-dns, python-jinja2, python-jwcrypto, python3.11, python3.11-PyMySQL, python3.11-urllib3, python3.12, python3.12-PyMySQL, python3.12-urllib3, python3.9, qemu-kvm, runc, skopeo, squid, thunderbird, toolbox, tpm2-tools, vim, webkit2gtk3, xorg-x11-server, and xorg-x11-server-Xwayland), <b>Fedora</b> (lemonldap-ng and mingw-expat), <b>SUSE</b> (bea-stax, xstream, expat, httpcomponents-client, httpcomponents-core, kernel, SUSE Manager Client Tools, SUSE Manager Proxy, Retail Branch Server 4.3, SUSE Manager Salt Bundle, SUSE Manager Server 4.3, and SUSE Manager Server 5.0), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (curl, glib2.0, and webkit2gtk).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998755/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 14:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Incus 6.7 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998756/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Version 6.7 of the Incus container-management system (forked from LXD) has
been released.  "<q>This is another one of those pretty well rounded
releases with new features and improvements for everyone</q>".  New
features include automatic cluster rebalancing, DHCP improvements, and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998756/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 14:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>AlmaLinux 9.5 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998637/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Version 9.5 of the AlmaLinux enterprise-oriented distribution has been
released.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	AlmaLinux 9.5 aims to improve performance, development tooling, and
	security. Updated module streams offer better support for web
	applications.  New versions of compilers provide access to the
	latest features and optimizations that improve performance and
	enable better code generation.  The release also introduces
	improvements to system performance monitoring, visualization, and
	system performance data collecting.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998637/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>FreeBSD Foundation releases Bhyve and Capsicum security audit</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998615/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The FreeBSD Foundation has <a
href="https://freebsdfoundation.org/blog/strengthening-freebsd-addressing-vulnerabilities-through-synacktivs-code-audit/">announced</a>
the release of a <a
href="https://freebsdfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/2024_Code_Audit_Capsicum_Bhyve_FreeBSD_Foundation.pdf">security
audit report</a> conducted by security firm <a
href="https://www.synacktiv.com/en">Synacktiv</a>. The audit uncovered
a number of vulnerabilities:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>Most of these vulnerabilities have been addressed through <a
href="https://www.freebsd.org/security/advisories/">official FreeBSD
Project security advisories</a>, which offer detailed information
about each vulnerability, its impact, and the measures implemented to
improve the security of FreeBSD systems. [...]</p>

<p>The audit uncovered 27 vulnerabilities and issues within various
FreeBSD subsystems. 7 issues were not exploitable and were robustness
or code quality improvements rather than immediate security concerns.</p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998615/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 20:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/998570/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (binutils, libsoup, squid:4, tigervnc, and webkit2gtk3), <b>Debian</b> (icinga2, postgresql-13, postgresql-15, smarty3, symfony, thunderbird, and waitress), <b>Fedora</b> (dotnet9.0, ghostscript, microcode_ctl, php-bartlett-PHP-CompatInfo, python-waitress, and webkitgtk), <b>Gentoo</b> (Perl, Pillow, and X.Org X server, XWayland), <b>Oracle</b> (binutils, cups-filters, giflib, squid, and webkit2gtk3), <b>Red Hat</b> (webkit2gtk3), <b>SUSE</b> (ansible-core, apache2, gio-branding-upstream, icinga2, kernel-devel, libnghttp2-14, libsoup-2_4-1, libsoup-3_0-0, libvirt, nodejs-electron, postgresql13, postgresql16, python39, rclone, thunderbird, ucode-intel-20241112, and wget), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (python-asyncssh and tomcat9).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/998570/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 13:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>