<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:24:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:30:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990731/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (pcs), <b>Debian</b> (expat, galera-4, libreoffice, mariadb-10.5, and php-twig), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium), <b>Red Hat</b> (ghostscript and git), <b>SUSE</b> (gstreamer-plugins-bad, gstreamer-plugins-bad, libvpl, python-dnspython, python3, and python36), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (expat, frr, libxmltok, linux-xilinx-zynqmp, openssl, and quagga).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990731/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>LLVM 16.1.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990706/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://discourse.llvm.org/t/llvm-19-1-0-released/81285">Version
16.1.0</a> of the LLVM compiler suite has been released:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
This is the first release in the LLVM 19.x series and represents 6
months of work the LLVM community. During this period 1502 unique
authors contributed 18925 commits (3605729 lines added and 1665792
lines removed) to LLVM.
</blockquote>

<p>As usual, there is a long list of changes; see the release notes
for <a
href="https://releases.llvm.org/19.1.0/docs/ReleaseNotes.html">LLVM</a>,
<a href="https://releases.llvm.org/19.1.0/projects/libcxx/docs/ReleaseNotes.html">Libc++</a>,
<a
href="https://releases.llvm.org/19.1.0/tools/lld/docs/ReleaseNotes.html">lld</a>,
<a
href="https://releases.llvm.org/19.1.0/tools/clang/docs/ReleaseNotes.html">Clang</a>,
and <a
href="https://releases.llvm.org/19.1.0/tools/clang/tools/extra/docs/ReleaseNotes.html">Extra
Clang Tools</a> for changes to each.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990706/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security proof for Linux&apos;s random number generator</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990596/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Four researchers have <a href="https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/1421.pdf">published</a> a formal proof that Linux's new deterministic random bit generator (DRBG) is secure in a particular sense — specifically, that the number of queries that would need to be made to it to uncover its internal state depends on the quality of the entropy it can collect from different sources. As long as it can gather enough entropy, it produces secure random numbers.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Since the significant structural changes in Linux 4 and Linux 5.17, there has
been no research on the provable security of Linux-DRBG. For the first time (to
the best of our knowledge), we formally model the Linux-DRBG in Linux 6.4.8
and prove its security in the seedless robustness model
</blockquote>

<p>
Thanks to Jason Donenfeld for bringing the paper to our attention.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990596/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990588/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (php-twig and pymongo), <b>Fedora</b> (linux-firmware, microcode_ctl, and python3.13), <b>Mageia</b> (clamav, microcode, postgresql13 and postgresql15, python3-webob, suricata, tcpreplay, tgt, and wireshark), <b>Oracle</b> (httpd, kernel, and linux-kernel), <b>Red Hat</b> (firefox, kernel, kernel-rt, pcs, and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (389-ds, chromium, golang-github-prometheus-prometheus, htmldoc, kernel, SUSE Manager Client Tools, and wireshark), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (clamav, curl, dcmtk, dovecot, nginx, openssh, and python3.10, python3.12, python3.8).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990588/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 11:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Linux Foundation announces OpenSearch Software Foundation</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990517/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Linux Foundation has <a
href="https://www.linuxfoundation.org/press/linux-foundation-announces-opensearch-software-foundation-to-foster-open-collaboration-in-search-and-analytics">announced</a>
the creation of the <a
href="https://foundation.opensearch.org/">OpenSearch Software
Foundation</a> as a vendor&#8209;neutral home for the <a
href="https://opensearch.org">OpenSearch</a> search and observability
software:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Established in 2021 and previously hosted by Amazon Web Services
(AWS), OpenSearch has recorded more than 700 million software
downloads and participation from thousands of contributors and more
than 200 project maintainers.
</blockquote>

<p>AWS <a
href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/opensource/introducing-opensearch/">created</a>
the OpenSearch project as an open-source fork of ElasticSearch and
Kibana in 2021 after Elastic <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/843274/">moved those projects to
non-free licenses</a>. Elastic <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/987850/">announced</a> in August that it would
relicense the projects under the Affero GPL (AGPL).</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990517/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 21:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Valkey 8.0.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990490/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://valkey.io/blog/valkey-8-ga/">Version 8.0.0</a> of
the <a href="https://valkey.io">Valkey</a> open-source in-memory data
store is now available. This is the first major release of Valkey
since the project <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/966631/">forked</a> from <a
href="https://redis.io">Redis</a> in March of this year:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
While this is a major version, Valkey takes command set compatibility
seriously: Valkey 8.0.0 makes no backwards incompatible changes to the
existing command syntax or their responses. Your existing tools and
custom software will be able to immediately take advantage of Valkey
8.0.0. Since Valkey 8.0.0 does make some small changes to previously
undefined behaviors, it's wise to <a
href="https://github.com/valkey-io/valkey/blob/8.0.0/00-RELEASENOTES">read
the release notes</a>. Additionally, because this version makes changes in how the
software uses threading, you may want to re-evaluate your cluster's
infrastructure to achieve the highest performance.
</blockquote>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990490/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 15:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990455/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (git, nodejs, and ring), <b>Fedora</b> (apr, bubblewrap, chromium, clamav, flatpak, mingw-expat, python3-docs, python3.12, and thunderbird), <b>Mageia</b> (assimp, botan2, python-tqdm, and radare2), <b>Slackware</b> (libarchive), and <b>SUSE</b> (curl).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990455/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 09:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The 6.11 kernel has been released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990307/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/990403/">released the 6.11 kernel</a>.
"<q>I'm once again on the road and not in my normal timezone, but it's
Sunday afternoon here in Vienna, and 6.11 is out.</q>"
Significant changes in this release include
new io_uring operations for <tt>bind()</tt> and <tt>listen()</tt>,
the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/978189/">nested bottom-half locking</a> patches,
the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/866493/">ability</a> to write to busy executable
files,
support for writing block drivers in Rust,
support for <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/974578/">atomic write operations</a> in the
block layer,
the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/965837/">dedicated bucket slab allocator</a>,
the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/980447/">vDSO implementation of <tt>getrandom()</tt></a>,
and more.  See the LWN merge-window summaries
(<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/982034/">part&nbsp;1</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/982605/">part&nbsp;2</a>) for more information.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990307/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 15:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>GNOME Foundation opens search for new Executive Director</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990270/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://foundation.gnome.org">GNOME Foundation</a> has <a
href="https://foundation.gnome.org/2024/09/13/search-for-new-executive-director/">announced</a>
that it is looking for a new Executive Director following the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/981850/">departure</a> of Holly Million
in July:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
As the cornerstone of our leadership team, the Executive Director will
play a critical role in shaping the strategic direction of the
Foundation, working closely with staff, community members, and
partners to expand our reach and impact. The ideal candidate will have
professional experience working with nonprofits, a strong passion for
open-source software, a deep commitment to our community values, and
the vision to drive the next phase of GNOME's growth and development.
</blockquote>

<p>The window of opportunity for the job is closing quickly,
applications are due by September 20.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990270/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 19:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Sovereign Tech Fund (STF) to invest in Samba improvements</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990264/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Germany's <a href="https://www.sovereigntechfund.de/">Sovereign
Tech Fund</a> (STF) has agreed to <a
href="https://www.sovereigntechfund.de/tech/samba">invest €688,800</a>
to improve the security, stability, and functionality of <a
href="https://www.samba.org/">Samba</a>. The investment will take
place over three years and will be managed by <a href="https://samba.plus/about-sernet">SerNet</a>, a company that
employs several Samba core developers and offers support for
Samba. According to its <a
href="https://samba.plus/blog/detail/sernet-secures-funding-for-samba-project-from-sovereign-tech-fund">announcement</a>,
work has already begun and is expected to complete in 2026:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
The project's focus is on areas like transparent failover, SMB3 UNIX
extensions, and modern security protocols such as SMB over QUIC. These
improvements are designed to ensure that Samba remains a robust and
secure solution for organizations that rely on a sovereign IT
infrastructure that is as independent as possible of proprietary
software regimes, but including optimal interoperability.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990264/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 17:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990202/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (haproxy, osc, and python3.11), <b>Oracle</b> (389-ds:1.4), <b>Red Hat</b> (kernel), <b>SUSE</b> (clamav, colord, kernel, postgresql16, and qemu), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.15, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.15, linux-gke, linux-gkeop, linux-gkeop-5.15, linux-hwe-5.15, linux-ibm, linux-intel-iotg, linux-intel-iotg-5.15, linux-kvm, linux-nvidia, linux-oracle, linux-raspi, linux-azure, linux-azure-5.15, linux-azure-fde, linux-lowlatency-hwe-6.8, linux-nvidia-6.8, and linux-xilinx-zynqmp).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990202/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 13:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>VirtualBox 7.1.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990125/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Changelog-7.1#v00">Version
7.1.0</a> of the <a href="https://www.virtualbox.org/">VirtualBox</a> virtualization system has been
released. Changes include a major GUI update, a new Network Address
Translation (NAT) engine with IPv6 support, shared clipboard support on Wayland, and more.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990125/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 21:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New stable kernels released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990043/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Greg Kroah-Hartman has announced the release of seven new stable kernels:
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/990044/">6.10.10</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/990045/">6.6.51</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/990046/">6.1.110</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/990047/">5.15.167</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/990048/">5.10.226</a> <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/990049/">5.4.284</a>, and <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/990050/">4.19.322</a>.  As usual, they all contain lots of
important fixes throughout the kernel tree.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990043/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 15:25:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990040/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (chromium and redis), <b>Fedora</b> (nextcloud, python3.10, python3.13, python3.6, vim, and wolfssl), <b>Mageia</b> (expat, libpcap, and microcode), <b>Oracle</b> (dovecot, kernel, and kernel-container), <b>Red Hat</b> (kernel and krb5), <b>SUSE</b> (389-ds, colord, containerd, curl, expat, glib2, go1.22, go1.23, kernel, libpcap, postgresql16, and runc), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (expat, libxmltok, linux, linux-aws, linux-azure, linux-bluefield, linux-gcp, linux-gkeop, linux-ibm, linux-kvm, linux-oracle, linux, linux-aws, linux-gcp, linux-gke, linux-ibm, linux-lowlatency, linux-oem-6.8, linux-oracle, linux-aws-5.4, linux-azure-5.4, linux-gcp-5.4, linux-hwe-5.4, linux-ibm-5.4, linux-oracle-5.4, linux-raspi-5.4, linux-azure, linux-iot, linux-nvidia, linux-nvidia-lowlatency, python-setuptools, setuptools, tiff, and unbound).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990040/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 15:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for September 5, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987605/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for September 5, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987605/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Whither the Apple AGX graphics driver?</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/988438/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Much of the early Rust code for the kernel has taken the form of
reimplementations of existing drivers as a proof of concept.  One project,
though, is entirely new: the driver for Apple GPUs written by Asahi Lina.
This driver has shipped with <a href="https://asahilinux.org/">Asahi
Linux</a> for some time and, by many accounts, is stable, usable, and a
shining example of how Rust can be used in a complex kernel subsystem.
That driver remains outside of the mainline kernel, though, and merging
currently looks like a distant prospect.  The reasons for that state of
affairs highlight some of the difficulties inherent in integrating a new
language (and its associated development style) into the Linux kernel.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/988438/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 13:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Transcribing audio with AI using Speech Note</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987315/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>One of the joys of writing about technology is the opportunity to
cover interesting talks on open&#8209;source and free&#8209;software topics. One
of the pains is creating transcriptions of said talks, or continually
referring back to a recording, to be able to write about
them. <a href="https://github.com/mkiol/dsnote">Speech Note</a> is an
open-source application that uses machine-learning models, running locally, to
translate speech to text and take the pain out of transcription. It
also handles text to speech, and language translations. While not
perfect, its transcriptions are better than one might expect, even when
handling jargon, accents, and less-than-perfect audio.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987315/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 15:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Advances in font technology and GTK text rendering</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987176/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>At this year's <a href="https://events.gnome.org/event/209/">GUADEC</a> in Denver, Colorado, Behdad Esfahbod and Matthias Clasen
presented a <a href="https://events.gnome.org/event/209/contributions/749/">two-part talk</a> on a topic that's deeply important to desktop
environments: fonts. Esfahbod covered advances in font
technology that are making their way to becoming standards, and Clasen briefly
discussed improvements in GTK text rendering. The talk presented some
fascinating insights into the problems around accurately rendering
writing systems on the desktop, and where font technologies may be
going in the near future.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987176/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 15:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A SpamAssassin surprise</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987566/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Here is a piece of advice for anybody wanting an easy and frustration-free
life: do not run your own email system.  While there numerous advantages to
keeping some control over your communications, there is also a long list of
things that can go wrong.  A recent failure of spam filtering on the LWN
email system illustrated one of those ways, as well as shining a light on
how even a seemingly independent email system is tied to other services
across the net.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987566/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 14:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Plasma Mobile for highly configurable Linux phones</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986899/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://plasma-mobile.org">Plasma Mobile</a> is an open-source
user interface for mobile devices, developed by the KDE community. It's
built on the same foundations as <a
href="https://kde.org/plasma-desktop/">Plasma Desktop</a>, including <a
href="https://develop.kde.org/products/frameworks/">KDE Frameworks</a> and the <a
href="https://invent.kde.org/plasma/kwin#kwin">KWin</a> window
manager. Much like its desktop counterpart, Plasma Mobile caters to
advanced users by offering extensive customizability. It is offered as an
option on phones with <a href="https://plasma-mobile.org/get/">various mobile Linux
distributions</a>.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986899/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 15:11:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>