<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 06:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 3 Aug 2024 07:33:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984370/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (chromium), <b>SUSE</b> (docker and patch), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (bind9, gross, linux-azure, linux-azure-4.15, linux-lowlatency-hwe-6.5, and tomcat8, tomcat9).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984370/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 13:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Sovereign Tech Fund introduces fellowship pilot program</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984266/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Sovereign Tech Fund (STF) has <a
href="https://www.sovereigntechfund.de/news/introducing-the-fellowship-for-maintainers">announced</a>
a fellowship program to support "<q>the dedicated individuals who keep
our digital infrastructure running</q>":</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Over the past two years, STF has successfully contracted over 40 FOSS
projects, enhancing their technical sustainability through targeted
milestones. However, the activities of maintainers, who often work on
multiple FOSS projects, are hard to quantify for funding applications,
as the demands and challenges vary and can change quickly. This is
where the fellowship for maintainers comes into play.
</blockquote>

<p>According to the <a
href="https://www.sovereigntechfund.de/programs/fellowship">fellowship
page</a> the STF plans to fund five fellowships, beginning in the
fourth quarter of this year, for a period of 12 months.</p>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984266/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 15:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mel Chua RIP</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984213/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We have received <a
href="https://www.caringbridge.org/site/f77db139-e97b-36cf-adb4-dd01e0c4d617/post/ebea2584-bf4c-414f-aa12-b652157771cb">the
sad news</a> that Dr. Mel Chua has passed away. Mel was probably best
known in the free-software community as a contributor to the Fedora
Project in its early days. The Fedora Community blog <a
href="https://communityblog.fedoraproject.org/mel-chua/">honored
Mel</a> recently after she had moved to hospice care with tributes
from several Fedorans. Stephen Jacobs wrote:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
I can't find the words to express how much of a positive impact Mel
has had on my work, our shared work, my family, the experiences of my
students, and the world of FOSS writ large. Nor can I find the words
to convey just how much I will miss her.
</blockquote>

<p>Mel will be greatly missed.</p>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984213/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 13:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984212/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (chromium), <b>Fedora</b> (kernel, obs-cef, and xen), <b>Mageia</b> (emacs), <b>Oracle</b> (freeradius, freeradius:3.0, and kernel), <b>Red Hat</b> (emacs, httpd, and kpatch-patch-4_18_0-305_120_1), <b>Slackware</b> (curl), <b>SUSE</b> (apache2, cockpit-wicked, glibc, gnutls, gvfs, less, nghttp2, opensc, python-idna, python-requests, qemu, rpm, tpm2-0-tss, tpm2.0-tools, and unbound), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (clickhouse, exim4, libcommons-collections3-java, linux, linux-aws, linux-kvm, linux-lts-xenial, mysql-8.0, openssl, php-cas, prometheus-alertmanager, and snapd).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984212/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for July 25, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982336/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for July 25, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982336/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 02:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Large folios, swap, and FS-Cache</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982887/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[David Howells wanted to discuss swap handling in light of multi-page folios
in a combined storage, filesystem, and memory-management session at
the 2024 <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>.  Swapping has always been
done with a one-to-one mapping of memory pages to swap slots, he said, but
swapping multi-page folios breaks that assumption.  He wondered if it would
make sense to use filesystem techniques to track swapped-out folios.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982887/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 15:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Lessons from the death and rebirth of Thunderbird</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982610/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Ryan Sipes told the audience during his keynote at
<a href="https://events.gnome.org/event/209/">GUADEC&nbsp;2024</a> in Denver, Colorado that the <a
href="https://thunderbird.net/">Thunderbird</a> mail client 
"probably shouldn't still be alive". Thunderbird, however, is not only
<em>alive</em>&mdash;it is arguably in better shape than ever
before. According to Sipes, the project's turnaround is a result of
governance, storytelling, and learning to be comfortable asking users
for money. He would also like it quite a bit if Linux distributions stopped
turning off telemetry.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982610/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 14:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Imitation, not artificial, intelligence</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982289/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Simon Willison, co-creator of the popular <a
href="https://www.djangoproject.com/">Django web framework</a> for Python,
gave a keynote presentation at <a
href="https://us.pycon.org/2024/">PyCon&nbsp;2024</a> on topic that is
unrelated to that work: large language models (LLMs).
The topic grew out of some other work that he is doing on <a
href="https://datasette.io/">Datasette</a>, which is a Python-based
"<q>tool for exploring and publishing data</q>".  The talk was a look
beyond the hype to try to discover what useful things you can actually do
today using these models.  Unsurprisingly, there were some
cautionary notes from Willison, as well.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982289/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 20:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A look inside the BPF verifier</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982077/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
LWN has covered BPF
<a href="https://lwn.net/1998/0212/#kernel">
since its initial introduction to Linux</a>, usually through the lens of the newest
developments; this can make it hard to view the whole picture. BPF provides
a way to extend a running kernel, without having to recompile and reboot.
It does this in a safe way, so that malicious BPF
programs cannot crash a running kernel, thanks to the BPF verifier. So how does
the verifier actually work, what are its limits, and how has it changed since
the early days of BPF?
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982077/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 14:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] &quot;Opt-in&quot; metrics planned for Fedora Workstation 42</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/980598/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Red Hat, through members of the <a
href="https://docs.fedoraproject.org/en-US/workstation-working-group/">Fedora
Workstation Working Group</a>, has taken another
swing at persuading the Fedora Project to allow metrics related to
the real-world use of the Workstation edition to be collected. The <a
href="https://discussion.fedoraproject.org/t/f40-change-request-privacy-preserving-telemetry-for-fedora-workstation-system-wide/">first
proposal</a>, aimed for Fedora&nbsp;40, was withdrawn to be reworked
based on <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/937528/">feedback</a>. This time around, the proponents have shifted from
asking for opt-out telemetry to opt-in metrics, with more detail about
what would be collected and the policies that would govern data collection. The
change seems to be on its way to approval by the <a
href="https://docs.fedoraproject.org/en-US/fesco/">Fedora Engineering
Steering Council</a> (FESCo) and is set to take effect for
Fedora&nbsp;42.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/980598/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 13:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A new major version of NumPy</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981663/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The <a href="https://numpy.org/">
NumPy</a> project <a href="https://numpy.org/doc/stable/release/2.0.0-notes.html">
released</a> version 2.0.0 on
June 16, the first major release of the widely
used Python-based numeric-computing library since 2006. The release has been planned for some
time, as an opportunity to clean up NumPy's API. As with most NumPy updates,
there are performance improvements to several individual functions. There are only a few new
features, but several backward-incompatible changes, including a change to
NumPy's numeric-promotion rules. Changes to the Python API require relatively minor changes to
Python code using the library, but the changes to the C API may be more
difficult to adapt to. In
both cases, the official
<a href="https://numpy.org/doc/stable/numpy_2_0_migration_guide.html">
migration guide</a> describes what needs to be adapted to the new version.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981663/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 16:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Restricting execution of scripts — the third approach</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982085/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The kernel will not consent to execute just any file that happens to be
sitting in a filesystem; there are formalities, such as the checking of
execute permission and consulting security policies, to get through first.
On some systems, security policies have been established to limit execution
to specifically approved programs.  But there are files that are not
executed directly by the kernel; these include scripts fed to language
interpreters like Python, Perl, or a shell.  An attacker who is able to get
an interpreter to execute a file may be able to bypass a system's security
policies.  Mickaël Salaün has been working on closing this hole for years;
the <a href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20240704190137.696169-1-mic@digikod.net">latest
attempt</a> takes the form of a new flag to the <a
href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man2/execveat.2.html"><tt>execveat()</tt></a>
system call.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982085/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 14:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Filesystem testing for stable kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982099/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Leah Rumancik led a filesystem-track session at
the 2024 <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a> on the testing needed to
qualify 
XFS patches for the stable kernels.  At last year's summit,
Rumancik, Amir Goldstein, and Chandan Babu Rajendra <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/934941/">presented</a> on their efforts to test and
backport fixes for the XFS filesystem to three separate stable kernels.
There has been some longstanding <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/838819/">unhappiness in
the XFS-development community
with the stable-kernel process</a>, which led to
backports ceasing for that filesystem until Goldstein <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/896523/">started working on XFS testing</a> for the stable
trees a few years ago.  In this year's session, Rumancik updated
attendees on how things had gone over the last year and wanted to discuss some
remaining pain points for the process.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982099/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 14:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The first half of the 6.11 merge window</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982034/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The merge window for the 6.11 kernel release opened on July&nbsp;14; as of
this writing, 4,072 non-merge changesets have been pulled into the mainline
repository since then.  This merge window, in other words, is just now
beginning.  Still, there has been enough time for a number of interesting
changes to land for the next kernel release; read on for a summary of what
has been merged so far.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982034/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 14:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A deprecation timeline for older Arm CPUs</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984143/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Arnd Bergmann has posted <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/2831c5a6-cfbf-4fe0-b51c-0396e5b0aeb7@app.fastmail.com">a
detailed timeline</a> for the deprecation of support for old Arm CPUs in
both the kernel and the compiler toolchain.  Anybody who is working with
that hardware will likely want to review this list and let the relevant
developers know if any of that support is still needed.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984143/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 20:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Vanilla OS 2 &quot;Orchid&quot; released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984117/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Version 2.0 of the <a href="https://vanillaos.org/">Vanilla OS</a> image-based Linux distribution has
been <a
href="https://vanillaos.org/blog/article/2024-07-28/vanilla-os-2-orchid---stable-release">released</a>. Dubbed
"Orchid", Vanilla OS is now based on Debian Sid (prior versions were Ubuntu-based),
allows <a
href="https://vanillaos.org/blog/article/2024-07-11/discover-apx-v2-the-new-essential-tool-for-developers-and-creators-on-vanilla-os-orchid">creation
of customized Linux environments</a>, support for running Android
applications using Waydroid, and many other improvements.</p>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984117/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 18:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Forgejo v8.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984116/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Version 8.0 of the <a href="https://forgejo.org/">Forgejo</a>
software-development platform has been <a
href="https://forgejo.org/2024-07-release-v8-0/">released</a>. Notable
changes include the <a
href="https://forgejo.org/2024-07-non-free-dependency-found/">removal</a>
of non-free software found in the codebase, improved stability, and a
<a
href="https://forgejo.org/2024-07-release-v8-0/#a-new-approach-to-ui-and-ux">reduction</a>
in "<q>seemingly random User Interface changes</q>":</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
A gentle way of describing Forgejo User eXperience is that it is an
acquired taste: it grew over the years, driven by the inspiration of
the person with the keyboard in their hand. Once implemented it almost
never changed. A user who started with Forgejo in 2022 can only see
minor changes in 2024 and not all of them make intuitive sense. The
solution to this problem is simple and was identified early on: User
Research. But only in the making of Forgejo v8.0 did it get some
momentum.
</blockquote>

<p>See the <a
href="https://codeberg.org/forgejo/forgejo/src/branch/forgejo/RELEASE-NOTES.md#8-0-0">release
notes</a> for a full list of changes.</p>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984116/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 15:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984080/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (xdg-desktop-portal-hyprland), <b>Red Hat</b> (freeradius, freeradius:3.0, git-lfs, httpd, kernel, openssh, and varnish:6), <b>SUSE</b> (cdi-apiserver-container, cdi-cloner-container, cdi- controller-container, cdi-importer-container, cdi-operator-container, cdi- uploadproxy-container, cdi-uploadserver-container, cont, git, gtk2, gtk3, kubevirt, virt-api-container, virt-controller-container, virt-exportproxy-container, virt-exportserver-container, virt-handler-container, virt-launcher-container, virt-libguestfs-t, orc, postgresql14, python-dnspython, python-urllib3, shadow, and xen), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (openjdk-17, openjdk-21, openjdk-8, openjdk-lts, and python3.10, python3.8).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984080/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 13:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Funtoo Linux is being discontinued</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983977/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Daniel Robbins, founder of the <a href="https://www.gentoo.org/">Gentoo Linux</a> distribution and its
spinoff <a href="https://www.funtoo.org/Welcome">Funtoo Linux</a>, has
<a
href="https://forums.funtoo.org/topic/5182-all-good-things-must-come-to-an-end/">announced</a>
that he has decided to end the Funtoo project:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Funtoo started as a philosophy to create a fun
community of contributors building something great together. For me,
it's no longer that so I need to move on to other things. There is not
a successor BDFL for Funtoo nor am I interested in trying to find one,
or hand the project off to someone else. You can expect the project to
wind down through August. If you have a <a
href="https://www.funtoo.org/Funtoo:User_Services/Containers">Funtoo
container</a>, it will continue to be online through the end of August
so you have time to find another hosting solution if you need one.
</blockquote>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983977/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 17:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983935/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (curl), <b>Mageia</b> (virtualbox), <b>Oracle</b> (squid), <b>Red Hat</b> (kernel), <b>SUSE</b> (apache2, bind, cdi-apiserver-container, cdi-cloner-container, cdi- controller-container, cdi-importer-container, cdi-operator-container, cdi- uploadproxy-container, cdi-uploadserver-container, devscripts, espeak-ng, freerdp, ghostscript, gnome-shell, gtk2, gtk3, java-11-openjdk, java-17-openjdk, kubevirt, libgit2, openssl-3, orc, p7zip, python-dnspython, and shadow), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (kernel, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-hwe, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-4.15, linux-hwe, linux-kvm, linux-oracle, linux, linux-aws, linux-gcp, linux-gke, linux-ibm, linux-nvidia, linux-oem-6.8, linux-raspi, linux, linux-azure, linux-azure-5.4, linux-bluefield, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.4, linux-gkeop, linux-hwe-5.4, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.4, linux-iot, linux-kvm, linux-raspi, linux-xilinx-zynqmp, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.4, linux-aws-5.15, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.15, linux-raspi, linux-gcp-5.15, and linux-lowlatency).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983935/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:49:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Git 2.46.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983850/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/xmqqzfq0i0qa.fsf@gitster.g">Version 2.46.0</a> of the Git
source-code management system has been released.  This release seems to
consist of a long list of interface and performance improvements rather
than big new features; see the announcement for the details.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983850/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 17:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983816/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (java-11-openjdk), <b>Debian</b> (bind9), <b>Fedora</b> (darkhttpd, mod_http2, and python-scrapy), <b>Red Hat</b> (python3.11, rhc-worker-script, and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (assimp, gh, opera, python-Django, and python-nltk), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (edk2, linux, linux-aws, linux-gcp, linux-gke, linux-gkeop, linux-gkeop-5.15, linux-hwe-5.15, linux-intel-iotg, linux-intel-iotg-5.15, linux-kvm, linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-5.15, linux-nvidia, linux-oracle, linux-azure, linux-azure-5.15, linux-azure-fde, linux-azure-fde-5.15, linux-nvidia-6.5, linux-oracle, linux-raspi, and lua5.4).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983816/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 13:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.11-rc1</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983760/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983759/">released 6.11-rc1</a> and closed the
merge window for this development cycle.  "<q>The merge window felt pretty
normal, and the stats all look pretty normal too. I was expecting things to
be quieter because of summer vacations, but that (still) doesn't actually
seem to have been the case.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983760/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 22:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Stable kernel updates for Saturday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983652/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983653/">6.10.2</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983654/">6.9.12</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983655/">6.6.43</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983656/">6.1.102</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983657/">5.15.164</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983658/">5.10.223</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983659/">5.4.281</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983660/">4.19.319</a>
stable kernel updates have all been released; each contains a relatively
small set of important fixes, <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-kernel/20240723-fs-lock-recover-compatfix-v1-1-148096719529@google.com/">at
least one of which</a> appears to close a security hole.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983652/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>