<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 07:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 11:07:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>FSF Europe condemns Apple&apos;s DMA noncompliance</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/980003/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The Free Software Foundation Europe has
<a href="https://fsfe.org/news/2024/news-20240627-01.en.html">
submitted</a> a joint position to the European Commission (EC), claiming that Apple
has failed to comply with the EU's Digital Markets Act (DMA). This is the law
that requires Apple to support alternative application stores on the devices it
makes.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Apple's unfair behaviour against Free Software highlights the critical need to
monitor the implementation of the DMA. The FSFE collaborated with F-Droid, the
AppFair project, and other interoperability experts to scrutinize Apple's DMA
compliance, and it's impact on Free Software. Since then, we coordinated several
expert workshops with stakeholders,
<a href="https://fsfe.org/news/2024/news-20240318-02.en.html">
discussed with regulators in FOSDEM</a>, had
<a href="https://fsfe.org/news/nl/nl-202406.en.html#interoperability-apple">
official meetings with the EC's DMA team</a>, and submitted a
<a href="https://download.fsfe.org/device-neutrality/202404-FSFE-apple-report-EC.pdf">
comprehensive position</a>
to the EC detailing several problematic elements in the Apple compliance that
will harm the Free Software.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/980003/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 14:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979999/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (pki-core), <b>Debian</b> (dlt-daemon and plasma-workspace), <b>Fedora</b> (emacs and kernel), <b>Mageia</b> (erofs-utils, libheif, libopenmpt, and wget), <b>Red Hat</b> (pki-core and python3), <b>SUSE</b> (frr), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (fontforge, sqlite3, and squid3).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979999/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 12:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Highlights from the FreeBSD Developer Summit</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979935/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The FreeBSD Foundation has published
<a
href="https://freebsdfoundation.org/blog/highlights-from-the-freebsd-developer-summit-2024-innovations-and-future-directions/">a
set of reports</a> from the <a
href="https://freebsdfoundation.org/news-and-events/event-calendar/may-2024-freebsd-developer-summit/">May
2024 FreeBSD Developer Summit</a> held in Ottawa, Canada. The topics
include FreeBSD Core Team updates, FreeBSD 15 release planning,
Integration with Rust, and <a
href="https://freebsdfoundation.org/blog/2024-freebsd-developer-summit-oci-containers-on-freebsd/">OCI
containers on FreeBSD</a>:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Doug Rabson began by providing an overview of the current state of
FreeBSD support for OCI containers, noting that while FreeBSD has long
supported containers through its jail and vnet features, the ecosystem
around OCI containers requires further development. "FreeBSD has been
able to do containers for a long time, but we need to align better
with OCI standards to make our containers more compatible and easier
to use," Rabson remarked​​.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979935/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 20:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mourning Daniel Bristot de Oliveira</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979912/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The academic and the Linux real-time and scheduling community mourns the
premature death of <a href="https://bristot.me/about/">Daniel Bristot de
Oliveira</a>. Daniel died at the age of 37 on Monday, June 24, 2024.
Juri Lelli, Tommaso Cucinotta, Steve Rostedt, Kate Stewart, and Thomas
Gleixner have come together to share their thoughts on his life and what he
has left behind]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979912/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 18:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Free Software Foundation adds three board members</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979918/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Free Software Foundation (FSF) has <a
href="https://www.fsf.org/news/fsf-adds-3-highly-qualified-board-members">announced</a>
the addition of three new members to its board: John Gilmore,
Christina Haralanova, and Maria Chiara Pievatolo. This is part of FSF
governance changes <a
href="https://www.fsf.org/about/staff-and-board/board/board-process-graph">announced</a>
in January 2023. The next step is a review of current board
members:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
These three new members of the FSF's board of directors are the first
to be appointed since 2020, when Odile Bénassy joined. Given the
importance of the FSF to the free software movement, and the
importance of its board to ensure preservation of the software freedom
definition, the board has not taken its task lightly. Next, the FSF
will evaluate current board members with the FSF's associate members
in August, after which the <a
href="https://www.fsf.org/news/fsf-board-frequently-asked-questions-faq#BoardvsVoting">voting
members</a> will review the feedback
received and decide if each current board member should remain.
</blockquote>

<p>More information on the process, and a short biography of each new
board member, is available in the full announcement.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979918/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 18:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Three Thursday stable kernel updates</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979849/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/979848/">6.9.7</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/979850/">6.6.36</a>, and <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/979851/">6.1.96</a> stable kernel updates have been
released; each contains an important set of fixes.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979849/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 13:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979847/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (ffmpeg, kernel, libvpx, and linux-5.10), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, firefox, freeipa, moodle, and openvpn), <b>Oracle</b> (git), <b>Red Hat</b> (golang and java-1.8.0-ibm), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-oracle-6.5, netplan.io, openssl, plasma-workspace, ruby2.7, ruby3.0, ruby3.1, sqlite3, and wget).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979847/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 13:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for June 20, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978238/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for June 20, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978238/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 03:42:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] How free software hijacked Philip Hazel&apos;s life</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978463/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Philip Hazel was 51 when he began the <a
href="https://www.exim.org/">Exim</a> message transfer agent (MTA)
project in 1995, which
led to the <a
href="https://github.com/PCRE2Project/pcre2">Perl-Compatible Regular
Expressions</a> (PRCE) project in 1998. At 80,
he's maintained PCRE, and its successor PCRE2, for more than 27
years. For those doing the math, that's a year longer than LWN has
been in publication. Exim maintenance was handed off around the time
of his retirement in 2007. Now, he is ready to hand off PCRE2 as well,
if a successor can be found.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978463/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 18:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Capturing stack traces asynchronously with BPF</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978736/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Andrii Nakryiko led a session at
the 2024
<a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a> giving
a look into the APIs for capturing stack traces
using BPF, and how the APIs could be made more useful. BPF programs can capture the
current stack trace of a running process, including the portion in the kernel
during execution of a system call, which can be useful for diagnosing
performance problems, among other things. But there are substantial problems with
the existing API.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978736/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 14:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] How kernel CVE numbers are assigned</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978711/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[It has been four months since <a
href="http://www.kroah.com/log/blog/2024/02/13/linux-is-a-cna/">Greg
Kroah-Hartman</a> and <a
href="https://www.cve.org/Media/News/item/news/2024/02/13/kernel-org-Added-as-CNA">MITRE</a>
announced that the Linux kernel project had become its own CVE Numbering
Authority (CNA).  Since then, the Linux CNA Team has developed workflows
and mechanisms to help manage the various tasks associated with this
challenge.  There does however, appear to be a lack of understanding among
community members of the processes and rules the team have been working
within.  The principal aim of this article, written by a member of the
Linux kernel CNA team, is to clarify how the team works and how kernel CVE
numbers are assigned.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978711/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 13:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Adding a JIT compiler to CPython</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977855/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[One of the big-ticket items for the upcoming Python&nbsp;3.13 release is an experimental <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/970397/">just-in-time (JIT) compiler</a> for the language;
the other is, of course, the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/947138/">removal of the 
global interpreter lock (GIL)</a>, which is also an experiment.  Brandt
Bucher is a member of the <a 
href="https://github.com/faster-cpython">Faster CPython project</a>, which is
working on making the reference implementation of the language faster via a
variety of techniques.  Last year at PyCon, he gave a <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/930705/">talk about the specializing adaptive
interpreter</a>; at <a href="https://us.pycon.org/2024/">PyCon&nbsp;2024</a> in Pittsburgh, he described the work he and others have been doing
to <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/957239/">add a copy-and-patch JIT compiler</a> to CPython.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977855/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 17:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] BPF tracing performance</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978335/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
On the final day of the 2024
<a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>, the BPF track
opened with a series of sessions on improving the performance and
flexibility of probes and other performance-monitoring tools, in the kernel and in
user space. Jiri Olsa led two sessions about different aspects of probes:
making the API for BPF programs attached to a probe more flexible, and making
user-space probes more efficient.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978335/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 13:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Static keys for BPF</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977993/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The kernel has a lot of code paths that are normally disabled: debugging print
statements, tracepoints, etc. To support these efficiently, there
is a common mechanism called
<a href="https://docs.kernel.org/staging/static-keys.html">
static keys</a> that provides a way to enable or disable a
code path at run time, with effectively no overhead for disabled
branches. BPF programs have not been able to take advantage of static keys so far,
because they aren't compiled into the kernel.
Now, it looks like BPF may be getting support for a similar mechanism —
and the design could also provide one of the components needed to support
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Branch_table">
jump tables</a>, another missing feature.
Anton Protopovov presented his plans to add static keys to BPF at the 2024
<a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977993/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 19:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Nested bottom-half locking for realtime kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978189/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Software-interrupt handlers (also called "bottom halves") have a long
history in the Linux kernel; for much of that history, developers have
wished that they could go away.  One of their unfortunate characteristics
is that they can add unexpected latency to the execution of unrelated
processes; this problem is felt especially acutely in the
realtime-preemption community.  The solution adopted there has created
problems of its own, though; in response Sebastian Andrzej Siewior is <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20240607070427.1379327-1-bigeasy@linutronix.de">proposing</a>
a new locking mechanism for realtime builds of the kernel that may have
benefits for non-realtime users as well.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978189/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 14:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Aeon: openSUSE for lazy developers</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977987/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The openSUSE project recently <a
href="https://news.opensuse.org/2024/05/28/aeon-desktop-brings-new-features-in-rctwo-release/">announced</a>
the second release candidate (RC2) of its <a
href="https://aeondesktop.github.io/">Aeon Desktop</a>, formerly known
as MicroOS Desktop GNOME. Aside from the new coat of naming paint,
Aeon breaks ground in a few other ways by dabbling with technologies not found in other openSUSE releases. The goal for Aeon is to provide
automated system updates using snapshots that can be applied
atomically, removing the burden of system maintenance for
"<q>lazy developers</q>" who want to focus on their work rather than desktop
administration. System-tinkerers need not apply.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977987/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 14:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Simplifying the BPF verifier</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977815/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The BPF verifier is a complex program. This has the unfortunate effect of making
it simultaneously more difficult for contributors to work on, and more likely
to harbor unknown bugs. Shung-Hsi Yu had two concrete proposals for how to
simplify the verifier to make it easier to maintain that he presented at the 2024
<a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>. Yu proposed changing how the
verifier tracks partially known values and cleaning up the interface to
hide the details of the value-tracker's internal representation.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977815/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 17:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Improving control-flow integrity for Linux on RISC-V</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977720/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Redirecting execution flow is a common malware
technique that can be used to compromise operating systems. To protect from such attacks,
the chip makers of leading architectures like x86 and arm64 have implemented
<a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/900099/">control-flow-integrity (CFI) extensions</a>, though they need system
software support to function. At the <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/linux-security-summit-north-america/">Linux
Security Summit North America</a>,  <a
href="https://riscv.org/">RISC-V</a> kernel developer Deepak Gupta described the CFI
protections for that architecture and  invited community input on the
kernel support for them.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977720/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 16:25:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>OpenSUSE Leap Micro 6.0 is now available</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979748/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The openSUSE project has <a
href="https://news.opensuse.org/2024/06/25/leap-micro-60-availability/">announced</a>
Leap Micro <a href="https://get.opensuse.org/leapmicro/6.0/">version
6.0</a>. Leap Micro is an image-based, lightweight Linux distribution
that is designed to run containerized and virtualized applications. It
is based on <a href="https://www.suse.com/products/micro/">SUSE Linux
Enterprise (SLE) Micro</a>. Changes in this release include the
support for full-disk encryption, the addition of Cockpit for
web-based system management, and an optional real-time kernel for
x86_64. Boot support for legacy BIOS on x86_64 is deprecated with 6.0, and will be removed in a later release. See the <a
href="https://www.suse.com/releasenotes/x86_64/SL-Micro/6.0/index.html">SLE
Micro release notes</a> for more information.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979748/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 15:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hutterer: GNOME tablet support papercut fixes</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979745/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Peter Hutterer has <a
href="http://who-t.blogspot.com/2024/06/gnome-tablet-support-papercut-fixes.html">written</a>
a summary of "papercut fixes" for GNOME tablet support that are
planned to ship with GNOME 47.</p>


<blockquote class="bq">
<p>If you're an avid tablet user, you may have multiple stylus tools -
but it's also likely that you have multiple tools of the same type
which makes differentiating them in the GUI hard. Which is why they're
highlighted now - if you bring the tool into proximity, the matching
image is highlighted to make it easier to know which stylus you're
about to configure. Oh, and in the process we added a new SVG for AES
styli too to make the picture look more like the actual physical
tool. The &lt;blink&gt; tag may no longer be cool but at least we can disco
our way through the stylus configuration now. </p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979745/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 14:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Types Team Update and Roadmap (Rust Blog)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979741/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Rust Blog is carrying <a
href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2024/06/26/types-team-update.html">an
update</a> on what the Rust Types Team has been up to and its near-future
plans.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	There has been <a
	href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pulls?q=is%3Apr+label%3AWG-trait-system-refactor+-label%3Arollup+is%3Amerged+closed%3A%3E2023-01-20+sort%3Acreated-asc+">a
	lot of work</a> on the <a
	href="https://github.com/rust-lang/trait-system-refactor-initiative/">next-generation
	trait solver</a>. The initiative posted <a
	href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/12/22/trait-system-refactor-initiative.html">a
	separate update</a> at the end of last year. While we would have
	liked to <a
	href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/121848">stabilize its
	use in coherence</a> a few months ago, this surfaced additional
	small behavior regressions and hangs, causing delays. We are
	working on fixing these issues and intend to merge the
	stabilization PR soon. We are getting close to compiling the
	standard library and the compiler with the new solver enabled
	everywhere, after which will be able to run crater to figure out
	the remaining issues.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979741/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:16:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979740/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (git, python3.11, and python3.9), <b>Debian</b> (chromium, emacs, git, linux-5.10, and org-mode), <b>Fedora</b> (libopenmpt, nginx-mod-modsecurity, and thunderbird), <b>Mageia</b> (emacs, python-ansible-core, and python-authlib), <b>Oracle</b> (git, python3.11, and python3.9), <b>Red Hat</b> (kernel, kernel-rt, and samba), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (ansible, cups, google-guest-agent, google-osconfig-agent, libheif, openvpn, roundcube, and salt).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979740/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Darktable 4.8.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979666/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://www.darktable.org/2024/06/darktable-4.8.0-released/">Version
4.8.0</a> of the <a href="https://www.darktable.org/">darktable</a>
photo editor has been released.  Changes include performance
improvements for large collections, addition of more EXIF fields in
the image information module, and two new modules for image
composition: Enlarge Canvas and Overlay. Enlarge Canvas allows adding
areas to an image, while Overlay allows adding new content by
overlaying pixels from the current image or another image. LWN last
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/881853/">looked at darktable</a> in
2022. Users are "<q>strongly advised</q>" to make a backup of their
configuration and library before upgrading, as they will not be
compatible with darktable 4.6.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979666/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>RIP Daniel Bristot de Oliveira</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979617/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[We have just received <a
href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7211345863858655233/">the
sad news</a> of the passing of Daniel Bristot de Oliveira at far too young
an age.  He was a strong contributor to the core kernel and associated
realtime infrastructure, and always a joyful presence in person; he will be
deeply missed.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979617/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 14:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Not all &quot;open source&quot; AI models are actually open (Nature)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979609/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Nature <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-02012-5">looks
at a recent paper</a> on the openness of "open-source" language 
models.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	It is not yet clear how many of these models will fit the EU's
	definition of open source. Under the act, this would refer to
	models that are released under a "free and open" licence that, for
	example, allows users to modify a model but says nothing about
	access to training data. Refining this definition will probably
	form "a single pressure point that will be targeted by corporate
	lobbies and big companies", the paper says.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979609/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 13:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979606/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (python3.11), <b>Debian</b> (composer), <b>Fedora</b> (thunderbird), <b>Mageia</b> (chromium-browser-stable, python-aiohttp, python-gunicorn, python-werkzeug, and virtualbox), <b>Oracle</b> (libreswan and python3.11), <b>Red Hat</b> (git, kpatch-patch, python3.11, python3.9, and thunderbird), and <b>SUSE</b> (avahi, ghostscript, grafana and mybatis, hdf5, kernel, openssl-1_1-livepatches, python-docker, and wget).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979606/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 13:18:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Min: sched_ext: scheduler architecture and interfaces</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979532/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Changwoo Min has posted <a
href="https://blogs.igalia.com/changwoo/sched-ext-scheduler-architecture-and-interfaces-part-2/">an
introduction to writing custom schedulers</a> with sched_ext.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	In a particular situation, when each scheduling policy needs its
	specific action, the core kernel scheduler calls an operation
	defined in <tt>struct sched_class</tt>. For example, when the core
	kernel scheduler needs to select a task to be scheduled, it calls
	the <tt>sched_class.pick_next_task(rq)</tt> callback of a concrete
	scheduling policy. When a task becomes runnable, the core kernel
	scheduler calls <tt>sched_class.enqueue(rq, p, flags)</tt> so the
	concrete scheduling policy enqueues task <tt>p</tt> to run queue
	<tt>rq</tt>. When a task's runtime state needs to be updated, the
	core kernel scheduler calls <tt>sched_class.update_curr(rq)</tt>.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979532/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 16:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979520/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (ipa and libreswan), <b>Debian</b> (netty), <b>Fedora</b> (python-PyMySQL, tomcat, and webkitgtk), <b>Gentoo</b> (Flatpak, GLib, JHead, LZ4, and RDoc), <b>Mageia</b> (thunderbird), <b>Oracle</b> (nghttp2 and thunderbird), <b>Red Hat</b> (dnsmasq, libreswan, pki-core, and python3.11), <b>Slackware</b> (emacs), <b>SUSE</b> (gnome-settings-daemon, libarchive, qpdf, vte, and wget), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (libhibernate3-java).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979520/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 14:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Emacs 29.4 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979491/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/CADwFkmkkwvMzpysVFYiBP8ZzYqeEoBt-rWXhTF1=672swTv1BQ@mail.gmail.com">Version
29.4</a> of the Emacs editor has been released.  This is "<q>an emergency
bugfix release</q>" fixing a <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/87wmmguk44.fsf@localhost">vulnerability</a> that can cause
the editor to execute arbitrary Org-mode code.  Anybody who runs Emacs on
untrusted files — including those using Gnus or one of the Emacs mail modes
— should be looking to update.  For those who cannot update, a pair of
messages from <a href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/87h6djh2dv.fsf@hope.eyrie.org">Russ
Allbery</a> and <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/87wmmehffa.fsf@oldenburg.str.redhat.com">Florian Weimer</a>
investigates how to disable the Org-mode evaluation, a task that is
seemingly more complicated than it should be.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979491/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 14:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.10-rc5</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979442/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/979441/">6.10-rc5</a> kernel prepatch is out for
testing.  "<q>So far, the 6.10 release cycle has been fairly calm, and rc5
continues that trend. Let's hope things stay that way.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979442/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 22:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Larry Finger RIP</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979419/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The linux-wireless mailing list carries the <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/77997185-86a6-41c5-af7a-74e4e9064437@lwfinger.net">terse
notice</a> that longtime networking developer Larry Finger passed away on
June&nbsp;21.  The <a href="https://lwn.net/ksdb/developers/show?dev=3787">LWN Kernel
Source Database</a> shows that Finger contributed to 94&nbsp;releases in
the (Git era) kernel history, starting with 2.6.16 — 1,464 commits in
total.  He will be missed.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979419/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 14:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>