<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 11:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 6 Feb 2025 11:23:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for January 30, 2025</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005953/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Inside this week's LWN.net Weekly Edition:
        <p>
        <ul>
<li> <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1005953/">Front</a>: Go vendoring in Fedora; Rust 2024 edition; 6.14 Merge window; uretprobe(); FOSDEM keynote; Earthstar.
            <li> <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1005955/">Briefs</a>: Git security; Ubuntu discussion; LWN EPUBs; Facebook moderation; Quotes; ...
            <li> <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1005956/">Announcements</a>: Newsletters, conferences, security updates, patches, and more.
            </ul>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005953/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 03:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Offline applications with Earthstar</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005639/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
<a href="https://earthstar-project.org/">
Earthstar</a> is a privacy-oriented,
offline-first, LGPL-licensed database intended to support distributed
applications. Unlike other distributed storage libraries, it
focuses on providing mutable data with human-meaningful names and modification
times, which gives it an interface similar to many non-distributed
key-value databases.
Now, the developers are looking at switching to a new synchronization
protocol — one that is general enough that it might see wider adoption.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005639/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 15:53:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] FOSDEM keynote causes concerns</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006351/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>This year's edition of the <a href="https://fosdem.org/">Free and Open
Source Software Developers' European Meeting</a> (FOSDEM) begins on
February&nbsp;1 in Brussels. The event is widely regarded as one of
the most important open-source conferences. One of the reasons that
FOSDEM is held in high esteem by the community is its non-commercial
nature. It does accept <a
href="https://fosdem.org/2025/about/sponsors/">sponsors</a>, but
sponsorships come with few perks and no "pay-for-play" speaking
slots. Thus, the scheduling of a keynote by Jack
Dorsey&#8288;&mdash;&#8288;primarily known for his role in co-founding Twitter, and
currently CEO and chairman of FOSDEM sponsor <a
href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Block%2C_Inc.">Block,&nbsp;Inc.</a>&#8288;&mdash;&#8288;raised eyebrows and led to plans for a protest. The
keynote has since been removed from the schedule, but there are still
a number of lingering questions.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006351/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 17:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Vendoring Go packages by default in Fedora</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005655/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://go.dev">Go language</a> is designed to make it
easy for developers to <a
href="https://go.dev/doc/tutorial/getting-started#call">import other
Go packages</a> and compile everything into a static binary
for simple distribution. Unfortunately, this complicates things for
those who package Go programs for Linux distributions, such as Fedora,
that have guidelines which require dependencies to be packaged
separately. Fedora's <a
href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/SIGs/Go">Go special interest
group</a> (SIG) is asking for relief and a loosening of the bundling
guidelines to allow Go packagers to bundle dependencies into the
packages that need them, otherwise known as vendoring. So far, the
participants in the discussion have seemed largely in favor of the
idea.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005655/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 15:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Rust 2024 Edition takes shape</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002456/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Last year, LWN <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/958792/">examined</a> the changes lined up for
Rust's 2024 edition. Now, with the edition
<a href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2025/01/22/rust-2024-beta.html">
ready to be stabilized</a> in February,
it's time to look back at the edition process and see what was
successfully adopted, which new changes were added, and what still remains to
work on. A surprising amount of new work was proposed, implemented, and
stabilized during the year.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002456/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 16:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The trouble with the new uretprobes</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005662/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[A "uretprobe" is a dynamic, user-space tracepoint injected by the kernel
into a running process; <a
href="https://docs.kernel.org/trace/uprobetracer.html">this document</a>
tersely describes their use.  Among other things, uretprobes are used by
the <tt>perf</tt> utility to time function calls.  The 6.11 kernel saw a
significant change to uretprobes that improved their performance, but that
change is also creating trouble for some users.  The best way to solve the
problem is not entirely clear.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005662/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 22:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The first part of the 6.14 merge window</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005651/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[As of this writing, just over 4,300 non-merge changesets have been pulled
into the mainline repository for the 6.14 release.  Many of the pull
requests this time around include remarks saying that activity has been
relatively low this time around, presumably due to the holidays.  So those
4,300 changesets are probably closer to the merge-window halfway point than
usual.  Much of the work merged thus far looks more like incremental
improvements than major new initiatives, but there still have been a number
of interesting changes in the mix.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005651/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 15:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Servo in 2024: stats, features and donations</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1008137/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://servo.org/">Servo</a> Rust-based rendering
engine project has <a
href="https://servo.org/blog/2025/01/31/servo-in-2024/">published</a>
an article summarizing its progress in&nbsp;2024, and plans for the
future:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Servo main dependencies (SpiderMonkey, Stylo and WebRender) have been
upgraded, the new layout engine has kept evolving adding support for
floats, tables, flexbox, fonts, etc. By the end of&nbsp;2024 Servo passes&nbsp;1,515,229 WPT subtests (79%). Many other new features have been under
active development: WebGPU, Shadow DOM, ReadableStream, WebXR, ... Servo
now supports two new platforms: Android and OpenHarmony. And we have
got the first experiments of applications using Servo as a web engine
(like <a
href="https://servo.org/blog/2024/01/19/embedding-update/">Tauri</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/DioxusLabs/blitz">Blitz</a>, <a
href="https://github.com/KDABLabs/cxx-qt-servo-webview">QtWebView</a>,
<a
href="https://github.com/mcclure/cuervo/tree/unstable_traversal_experiment">Cuervo</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/versotile-org/verso/">Verso</a> and <a
href="https://github.com/moto-browser/moto">Moto</a>).
</blockquote>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1008137/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 20:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>LWN site tour 2025</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006001/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Over the past year or so, LWN has added a number of useful new
features for our subscribers to enhance the experience of reading and
commenting on our content. Those features are of little use, however,
to readers who do not know about them. It has been more than a decade
since we last provided <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/622988/">a
tour of the site</a>&mdash;it seems that another is in
order. Walk this way for a look at the LWN kernel source database (KSDB),
enhanced commenting features, EPUB downloads, and more.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006001/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 18:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1008051/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (firefox-esr), <b>Fedora</b> (fastd, ovn, and yq), <b>Mageia</b> (libreoffice), <b>Slackware</b> (mozilla), <b>SUSE</b> (google-osconfig-agent, grafana, helm, and rime-schema-all), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-azure, linux-azure-5.4, linux-lowlatency, openjdk-17, openjdk-21, openjdk-23, openjdk-8, and openjdk-lts).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1008051/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 14:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Firefox 135.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007887/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/135.0/releasenotes/">Version
135.0</a> of the Firefox web browser has been released.  Changes include
more languages for the translations feature, increasing roll-out of the
credit-card autofill and AI chatbot features, and (perhaps most welcome):
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Firefox now includes safeguards to prevent sites from abusing the
	history API by generating excessive history entries, which can make
	navigating with the back and forward buttons difficult by
	cluttering the history. This intervention ensures that such
	entries, unless interacted with by the user, are skipped when using
	the back and forward buttons.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007887/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 15:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007886/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (openjdk-17), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, fastd, ovn, and yq), <b>Mageia</b> (libxml2 and redis), <b>Oracle</b> (gstreamer1-plugins-base, gstreamer1-plugins-good), <b>Red Hat</b> (buildah, bzip2, galera, mariadb, grafana, keepalived, libsoup, mariadb:10.11, mariadb:10.5, mingw-glib2, podman, python-jinja2, and rsync), <b>SUSE</b> (bind, ignition, java-11-openjdk, java-17-openjdk, krb5, libxml2, openssl-1_1, orc, python-asteval, rsync, and xrdp), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (harfbuzz, libndp, libvpx, and opencv).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007886/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 15:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What’s new in GTK, winter 2025 edition</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007677/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Matthias Clasen has written a short update on a GTK hackfest that
took place at <a href="https://fosdem.org/">FOSDSEM</a> and what's
coming in GTK 4.18. This includes fixes for pointer sizes in Wayland
when fractional scaling is enabled, removal of the old GL renderer in
favor of the <a
href="https://blog.gtk.org/2024/01/28/new-renderers-for-gtk/">GL
renderer</a> introduced in <a
href="https://download.gnome.org/sources/gtk/4.13/gtk-4.13.6.news">GTK
4.13.6</a>, and deprecation of X11 and Broadway backends with intent
to remove them in GTK 5.</p>

<p>The deprecated backends will remain available until then, and no
action is required by developers at this time, Clasen wrote: "<q>There
is no need to act on deprecations until you are actively porting your
app to the next major version of GTK, which is not on the horizon
yet</q>".</p>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007677/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007646/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (git-lfs, libsoup, and unbound), <b>Debian</b> (dcmtk, ffmpeg, openjdk-11, pam-u2f, and python-aiohttp), <b>Fedora</b> (buku, chromium, jpegxl, nodejs18, nodejs20, and rust-routinator), <b>Mageia</b> (clamav, kernel, kmod-virtualbox, kmod-xtables-addons &amp; dwarves, and kernel-linus), <b>SUSE</b> (apptainer, bind, buildah, chromedriver, clamav, dovecot24, ignition, kubelogin, libjxl, libQt5Bluetooth5-32bit, orc, owasp-modsecurity-crs, python-pydantic, python311-ipython, and stb), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-azure and netdata).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007646/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 15:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.14-rc1</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007547/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has released <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1007546/">6.14-rc1</a> and closed the
merge window for this release.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	This is actually a _tiny_ merge window, and that's ok. The holidays
	clearly meant that people did less development than during a normal
	cycle, and that then shows up as a much smaller-than-average
	release.  I really felt like this year we got the whole holiday
	season release timing right, and this is just another sign of that.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007547/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 01:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>GNU Binutils 2.44 Released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007541/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Version 2.44 of the GNU Binutils package has been released.  Perhaps the
most significant change is the absence of the "gold" linker, which is
deprecated and about to disappear entirely.  Gold <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/274859/">appeared in 2008</a> with some fanfare as a faster
linker, but it has suffered from a lack of maintenance in recent years.
This release also includes some architecture-specific assembler
improvements, and some (non-gold) linker enhancements.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007541/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 23:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Stable kernel updates for Saturday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007438/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1007439/">6.13.1</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1007440/">6.12.12</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1007441/">6.6.75</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1007442/">6.1.128</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1007443/">5.15.178</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1007444/">5.10.234</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1007445/">5.4.290</a>
stable kernel updates have all been released; each contains another set of
important fixes.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007438/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 20:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Linux Foundation on global regulations and sanctions</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007272/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Linux Foundation has published <a
href="https://www.linuxfoundation.org/blog/navigating-global-regulations-and-open-source-us-ofac-sanctions">its
long-awaited article on international sanctions</a> and open-source
development.  This is the reasoning that went into <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/995186/">the removal of a group of Russian kernel
maintainers</a> in October.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	It is disappointing that the open source community cannot operate
	independently of international sanctions programs, but these
	sanctions are the law of each country and are not optional. Many
	developers work on open source projects in their spare time, or for
	fun. Dealing with U.S. and international sanctions was unlikely on
	the list of things that most (or very likely any) open source
	developers thought they were signing up for. We hope that in time
	relevant authorities will clarify that open source and standards
	activities may continue unabated. Until that time, however, with
	the direct and indirect sponsorship of developers by companies, the
	intersection of sanctions on corporate entities leaves us in a
	place where we cannot ignore the potential risks.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007272/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 14:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007252/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (libsoup), <b>Debian</b> (debian-security-support and redis), <b>Fedora</b> (expat, java-21-openjdk, lemonldap-ng, and phpMyAdmin), <b>Mageia</b> (chromium-browser-stable and git-lfs), <b>Oracle</b> (bzip2, git-lfs, libsoup, mariadb:10.11, mariadb:10.5, python-jinja2, redis, and unbound), <b>Red Hat</b> (git-lfs, libsoup, python-jinja2, rsync, and unbound), <b>SUSE</b> (buildah, chromium, google-osconfig-agent, govulncheck-vulndb, hauler, ignition, krb5, libxml2, python311-pydantic, SDL2_sound, and trivy), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (jquery, linux-azure, linux-azure-4.15, linux-azure-5.15, linux-hwe-5.4, linux-oracle, and mysql-8.0).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007252/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 13:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Freedesktop looking for new home for its GitLab instance</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007032/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Visitors to the <a href="https://www.freedesktop.org/">freedesktop.org</a>
<a href="https://gitlab.freedesktop.org/">GitLab instance</a> are currently being greeted with a message noting that
the company who has been hosting it for free for nearly five years, Equinix, has
asked that it be moved (or start being paid for) by the end of April.  The
<a
href="https://gitlab.freedesktop.org/freedesktop/freedesktop/-/issues/2011">issue
ticket</a> opened by Benjamin Tissoires in order to  track the planning of a move is clear that the project is grateful for
the gift:
"<q>First, I'd like to thank Equinix Metal for the years of support they gave us. They were very kind and generous with us and even if it's a shame we have to move out on a short notice, all things come to an end.</q>"

<p>
The current cost for the services, much of which is for 50TB of bandwidth
per month and a half-dozen beefy servers for running continuous-integration
(CI) jobs, comes to around $24,000 per month.  Tissoires believes that the
project should start paying for service somewhere, in order to avoid
upheaval of this sort, sometimes on short or no notice. "<q>I personally
think we better have fd.o pay for its own servers, and then have sponsors
chip in. This way, when a sponsor goes away, it's technically much simpler
to just replace the money than change datacenter.</q>"  Various options are
being discussed there, but any move is likely to disrupt normal services
for a week or more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007032/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 17:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>GNU C Library 2.41 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007024/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/6975370.R56niFO833@pinacolada">Version 2.41</a> of the GNU
C Library has been released.  Changes include a number of test-suite
improvements, strict-error support in the DNS stub resolver, wrappers for
the the <a
href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man2/sched_setattr.2.html"><tt>sched_setattr()</tt>
and <tt>sched_getattr()</tt></a> system calls,
Unicode 16.0.0 support,
improved C23 support,
support for <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/885818/">extensible restartable
sequences</a>,
Guarded Control Stack support on 64-bit Arm systems,
and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007024/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 16:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Thunderbird moving to monthly updates in March</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006917/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.thunderbird.net/en-US/">Thunderbird</a> project has <a
href="https://thunderbird.topicbox.com/groups/planning/Td58a7d8581e7d60f">announced</a>
that it is making its <a
href="https://developer.thunderbird.net/releases/channels">Release
channel</a> the default download beginning with the 135.0 release in
March. This will move users to major monthly releases instead of the
annual major Extended Support Release (ESR) that is the current
default.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
One of our goals for 2025 is to increase active installations on the
release channel to at least 20% of the total installations. At last
check, we had 29,543 active installations on the release channel,
compared to 20,918 on beta, and 5,941 on daily. The release channel
installations currently account for 0.27% of the 10,784,551 total
active installations tracked on stats.thunderbird.net.
</blockquote>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006917/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 14:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006978/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (redis:7), <b>Debian</b> (bind9, chromium, flightgear, pam-u2f, and simgear), <b>Red Hat</b> (fence-agents, git-lfs, libsoup, python3.9, rsync, and traceroute), <b>Slackware</b> (bind), <b>SUSE</b> (apache2-mod_security2, corepack22, go1.24, hplip, ignition, iperf, kernel, kernel-devel-longterm, nginx, nodejs22, openvpn, owasp-modsecurity-crs, and shadow), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (bind9, jinja2, libxml2, linux-lowlatency-hwe-6.8, php7.0, tomcat6, and vlc).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006978/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 14:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>