<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 22:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 22:08:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973496/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (nodejs:18 and shim), <b>Debian</b> (atril and chromium), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, glib2, gnome-shell, mediawiki, php-wikimedia-cdb, php-wikimedia-utfnormal, stb, and tcpdump), <b>Gentoo</b> (Kubelet, PoDoFo, Rebar3, and thunderbird), <b>Mageia</b> (glibc and libnbd), <b>Oracle</b> (kernel), <b>Red Hat</b> (bind and dhcp and varnish), and <b>SUSE</b> (chromium, cpio, freerdp, giflib, gnutls, opera, python-Pillow, python-Werkzeug, tinyproxy, and tpm2-0-tss).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973496/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 13:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The 6.9 kernel is out</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972886/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/973397/">released</a> the 6.9 kernel. 
"<q>So 6.9 is now out, and last week has looked quite stable (and the
whole release has felt pretty normal).</q>"
Significant changes in this release include
the ability to create <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/794707/">pidfds</a> for individual
threads,
the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/961941/">BPF arena</a> subsystem,
the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/947173/">BPF token</a> security mechanism,
<tt>truncate()</tt> support in <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/776703/">io_uring</a>,
support for the Rust language on 64-bit Arm systems,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/948037/">weighted interleaving</a> in the
memory-management subsystem,
the <a
href="https://docs.kernel.org/admin-guide/device-mapper/vdo.html">device-mapper
virtual data optimizer</a> target,
initial <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/932060/">FUSE passthrough</a> support,
and more.

See the LWN merge-window summaries
(<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/965141/">part&nbsp;1</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/965541/">part&nbsp;2</a>) for more information.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972886/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 22:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973206/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (container-tools:4.0, container-tools:rhel8, git-lfs, glibc, libxml2, nodejs:18, and nodejs:20), <b>Debian</b> (dav1d and libpgjava), <b>Fedora</b> (kernel and pypy), <b>Red Hat</b> (glibc and nodejs:16), <b>SUSE</b> (ffmpeg, ffmpeg-4, ghostscript, go1.21, go1.22, less, python-python-jose, python-Werkzeug, and sssd), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (fossil, glib2.0, and libspreadsheet-parsexlsx-perl).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973206/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 13:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973071/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (ansible-core, avahi, bind, buildah, containernetworking-plugins, edk2, fence-agents, file, freeglut, freerdp, frr, git-lfs, gnutls, golang, grafana, grafana-pcp, gstreamer1-plugins-bad-free, gstreamer1-plugins-base, gstreamer1-plugins-good, harfbuzz, httpd, ipa, libjpeg-turbo, libnbd, LibRaw, libreswan, libsndfile, libssh, libtiff, libvirt, libX11, libXpm, mingw components, mingw-glib2, mingw-pixman, mod_http2, mod_jk and mod_proxy_cluster, motif, mutt, openssl and openssl-fips-provider, osbuild-composer, pam, pcp, perl, pmix, podman, python-jinja2, python-jwcrypto, python3.11, python3.11-cryptography, python3.11-urllib3, qemu-kvm, qt5-qtbase, runc, skopeo, sssd, systemd, tcpdump, tigervnc, toolbox, webkit2gtk3, xorg-x11-server, xorg-x11-server-Xwayland, and zziplib), <b>CentOS</b> (firefox, grub2, kernel, squid, thunderbird, tigervnc, and xorg-x11-server), <b>Debian</b> (chromium, glib2.0, python-idna, webkit2gtk, and wordpress), <b>Fedora</b> (freerdp, freerdp2, and pypy), <b>Mageia</b> (chromium-browser-stable, exfatprogs, freeglut, libtiff, libvirt, libxml2, openpmix, php-tcpdf, ruby, tpm2-tools, tpm2-tss, traceroute, and zziplib), <b>Oracle</b> (bind, buildah, git-lfs, gnutls, golang, grafana, grafana-pcp, libreswan, libvirt, libxml2, mod_http2, podman, python-jwcrypto, skopeo, sssd, and tigervnc), <b>Red Hat</b> (nodejs:18, nodejs:20, and squid:4), and <b>SUSE</b> (avahi, ghostscript, go1.21, go1.22, python-pymongo, python-Werkzeug, and sssd).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973071/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 13:31:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for May 2, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971093/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for May 2, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971093/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 01:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A look at Ubuntu Desktop LTS 24.04</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971143/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Ubuntu&nbsp;24.04&nbsp;LTS, code-named "Noble&nbsp;Numbat", was <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/971175/">released</a> on April&nbsp;25. This release includes <a
href="https://release.gnome.org/46/">GNOME&nbsp;46</a>, installer updates,
security enhancements, a lot of updated packages, and a new App Center
that puts a heavy emphasis on using Snaps to install software. It is not an ambitious release, but it brings enough to the table that it's a worthwhile update.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971143/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 17:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Security patterns and anti-patterns in embedded development</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970818/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to security, telling developers to do (or not do)
something can be ineffective. Helping them understand the why behind
instructions, by illustrating good and bad practices using stories, can be
much more effective. With several such stories Marta
Rybczyńska fashioned an interesting <a
href="https://eoss24.sched.com/event/1aBEg/patterns-and-anti-patterns-in-embedded-development-what-security-incidents-of-2023-teach-us-marta-rybczynska-syslinbit">talk</a>
about patterns and anti-patterns in embedded Linux security at the
<a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/embedded-open-source-summit/">Embedded
Open Source Summit</a> (EOSS), co-located with <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/open-source-summit-north-america/">Open
Source Summit North America</a> (OSSNA), on April 16 in Seattle, Washington.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970818/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 15:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A leadership crisis in the Nix community</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970824/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
On April 21, a group of anonymous authors and non-anonymous signatories published
<a href="https://save-nix-together.org/">a lengthy open letter</a> to the
<a href="https://nixos.org/">
Nix</a> community
and Nix founder Eelco Dolstra calling for his resignation from the project. They
claimed ongoing problems with the project's leadership, primarily focusing on the
way his actions have allegedly
undermined people nominally empowered to perform various
moderation and governance tasks. Since its release, the letter has gained
more than 100 signatures.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970824/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 14:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Giving Rust a chance for in-kernel codecs</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970565/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Video playback is undeniably one of the most important features in modern
consumer devices. Yet, surprisingly, users are by and large unaware of the
intricate engineering involved in the compression and decompression of
video data, with codecs being left to find a delicate balance between image
quality, bandwidth, and power consumption. In response to constant
performance pressure, video codecs have become complex and hardware
implementations are now common, but programming these devices is becoming
increasingly difficult and fraught with opportunities for exploitation. I
hope to convey how Rust can help fix this problem.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970565/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 15:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Support for the TSO memory model on Arm CPUs</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970907/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[At the CPU level, a memory model describes, among other things, the amount
of freedom the processor has to reorder memory operations.  If low-level
code does not take the memory model into account, unpleasant surprises are
likely to follow.  Naturally, different CPUs offer different memory models,
complicating the portability of certain types of concurrent software.  To
make life easier, some Arm CPUs offer the ability to emulate the x86 memory
model, but efforts to make that feature available in the kernel are running
into opposition.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970907/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 13:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Python JIT stabilization</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970397/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
On April 11, Brandt Bucher posted
<a href="https://peps.python.org/pep-0744">PEP 744</a> ("JIT Compilation"),
which summarizes the current state of Python's new <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/958350/">
copy-and-patch just-in-time (JIT) compiler</a>. The JIT is currently
experimental, but the PEP proposes some criteria for the circumstances under which it
should become a non-experimental part of Python.
<a href="https://discuss.python.org/t/pep-744-jit-compilation/50756">
The discussion</a> of the PEP hasn't
reached a conclusion, but
several members of the community have already raised questions
about how the JIT would fit into future iterations of the Python language.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970397/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 17:57:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The state of realtime and embedded Linux at OSSNA</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970555/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linux, famously, appears in a wide range of systems.  While servers and
large data centers get a lot of the attention, and this year will always be
the year of the Linux desktop, there is also a great deal of Linux to be
found in realtime and embedded applications.  Two talks held in the
realtime and embedded tracks of the 2024 <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/open-source-summit-north-america/">Open
Source Summit North America</a> provided listeners with an update on how
Linux is doing in those areas.  Work on realtime Linux appears to be nearing
completion, while the embedded community is still pushing forward at full
speed.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970555/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 14:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Fedora Asahi Remix 40 is now available</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972874/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Fedora Magazine <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/fedora-asahi-remix-40-is-now-available/">reports</a>
that the <a href="https://fedora-asahi-remix.org/">Fedora Asahi
Remix</a> for Apple Arm hardware, based on <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/whats-new-fedora-workstation-40/">Fedora
40</a>, is now available:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Fedora Asahi Remix offers <a href="https://kde.org/announcements/megarelease/6/">KDE Plasma 6</a> as our flagship desktop
experience. It also features a custom Calamares-based initial setup
wizard. A GNOME variant is also available, featuring GNOME 46, with
both desktop variants matching what Fedora Linux offers. Fedora Asahi
Remix also provides a Fedora Server variant for server workloads and
other types of headless deployments. Finally, we offer a Minimal image
for users that wish to build their own experience from the ground up.
</blockquote>

<p>See the <a
href="https://docs.fedoraproject.org/en-US/fedora-asahi-remix/installation/">installation
guide</a> to get started with the Asahi Remix.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972874/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 15:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972861/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (glib2.0 and php7.3), <b>Gentoo</b> (Commons-BeanUtils, Epiphany, glibc, MariaDB, Node.js, NVIDIA Drivers, qtsvg, rsync, U-Boot tools, and ytnef), <b>Oracle</b> (kernel), <b>Red Hat</b> (git-lfs and kernel), <b>SUSE</b> (flatpak, less, python311, rpm, and sssd), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (libde265, libvirt, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.4, linux-azure, linux-azure-5.4, linux-gcp,
 linux-gcp-5.4, linux-gkeop, linux-hwe-5.4, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.4,
 linux-iot, linux-kvm, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-5.4, linux-raspi,
 linux-raspi-5.4, linux-xilinx-zynqmp, linux, linux-azure, linux-azure-5.15, linux-azure-fde,
 linux-azure-fde-5.15, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.15, linux-gke, linux-gkeop,
 linux-gkeop-5.15, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.15, linux-kvm, linux-lowlatency,
 linux-lowlatency-hwe-5.15, linux-nvidia, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-5.15, linux-oem-6.5, and nghttp2).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972861/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 13:46:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>GCC 14.1 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972683/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://lwn.net/ml/gcc/7244o293-0qqs-65qq-6n7r-r374399qq79r@fhfr.qr/">Version
14.1</a> of the GCC compiler suite has been released.  The list of changes
is long; it includes support for more C++26 features, preparation for
Fortran 2023 support, a new <tt>-fhardened</tt> flag to enable
security-hardening features, vectorizer improvements, and a number of <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/946733/">static-analyzer improvements</a>.  See <a
href="https://gcc.gnu.org/gcc-14/changes.html">the release notes</a> for
details.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972683/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 12:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Secure Randomness in Go 1.22 (Go Blog)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972680/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Go Blog has <a href="https://go.dev/blog/chacha8rand">a detailed
article</a> on the new, more secure random-number generator implemented for
the 1.22 release.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	For example, when Go 1.20 deprecated math/rand's Read, we heard
	from developers who discovered (thanks to tooling pointing out use
	of deprecated functionality) they had been using it in places where
	crypto/rand's Read was definitely needed, like generating key
	material. Using Go 1.20, that mistake is a serious security problem
	that merits a detailed investigation to understand the
	damage. Where were the keys used? How were the keys exposed? Were
	other random outputs exposed that might allow an attacker to derive
	the keys? And so on. Using Go 1.22, that mistake is just a mistake.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972680/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 12:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972679/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (kernel), <b>Gentoo</b> (libjpeg-turbo, xar, and Xpdf), <b>Red Hat</b> (bind, dhcp and glibc), and <b>SUSE</b> (bouncycastle, curl, flatpak, less, and xen).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972679/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 12:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>