<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 21:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 21:33:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Brown: Fixing a 6-year-old bug in Ubuntu MATE and Xubuntu</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981565/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Doug Brown <a
href="https://www.downtowndougbrown.com/2024/07/i-fixed-a-6-year-old-deb-installation-bug-in-ubuntu-mate-and-xubuntu/">documents
the long journey</a> to fixing a bug in the <a
href="https://simple.wikipedia.org/wiki/GDebi">GDebi</a> utility for
installing Debian packages. He first encountered the bug in
Ubuntu&nbsp;MATE&nbsp;18.04: "<q>at the time I just ignored this
issue. I didn't want to deal with it. I went off to the trusty Linux
terminal and installed Chrome that way instead</q>".</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>Two and a half years ago, I committed to doing more open-source
contributions in my free time and was finally irritated enough about
this problem to look into it. I searched around for more info. Lo and
behold, <a
href="https://askubuntu.com/questions/985009/gdebi-installer-exits-without-installing-the-deb-file-in-17-10">lots
of</a> <a href="https://dev1galaxy.org/viewtopic.php?id=4900">people
were</a> <a
href="https://forums.debian.net/viewtopic.php?t=142601">also
affected</a> and <a href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/gdebi/+bug/1854588">there was already an
issue from 2019 on Ubuntu's bug tracker</a> about it.</p>

<p>[...] As is commonly the case in software development, the difficult part of
this fix had nothing to do with the code itself. All of my effort was
spent figuring out Ubuntu's patch submission processes and advocating
for my merge request. Nobody else seemed to be interested in doing the
work to actually fix this bug that has been plaguing Ubuntu MATE and
Xubuntu, not to mention some Debian users, for over 6 years. After
dealing with the long process of getting my merge request approved, I
think I'm starting to understand why!
</blockquote>

<p>Brown notes that the fix <a
href="https://changelogs.ubuntu.com/changelogs/pool/universe/g/gdebi/gdebi_0.9.5.7+nmu7ubuntu0.24.10.1/changelog">is
now packaged</a> for the upcoming Ubuntu 24.10 release, and should be
backported to 22.04 and 24.04 eventually.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981565/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 18:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Fix for Fedora Atomic Desktop and Fedora IoT boot failure</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981561/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Fedora <a
href="https://fedoraproject.org/atomic-desktops/">Atomic Desktop</a>
and <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/iot/">Fedora IoT</a> systems installed
before Fedora&nbsp;40 may fail to boot after an update if secure boot
is enabled. Fedora Magazine has <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/manual-action-needed-to-resolve-boot-failure-for-fedora-atomic-desktops-and-fedora-iot/">a
post</a> by Timothée Ravier about the problem, how users can work
around it, and what the project is doing to avoid the similar problems
in the future:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>On Fedora Atomic Desktops and Fedora IoT systems, the components
that are part of the boot chain (Shim, GRUB) are not (yet)
automatically updated alongside the rest of the system. Thus, if you
have installed a Fedora Atomic Desktop or a Fedora IoT system before
Fedora 40, it uses an old versions of the Shim and bootloader binaries
to boot your system.</p>

<p>When Secure Boot is enabled, the EFI firmware loads Shim
first. Shim is signed by the Microsoft Third Party Certificate
Authority so that it can be verified on most hardware out of the
box. The Shim binary includes the Fedora certificates used to verify
binaries signed by Fedora. Then Shim loads GRUB, which in turn loads
the Linux kernel. Both are signed by Fedora.</p>

<p>Until recently, the kernel binaries where signed two times, with an
older key and a newer one. With the 6.9 kernel update, the kernel is
no longer signed with the old key. If GRUB or Shim is old enough and
does not know about the new key, the signature verification fails.</p>
</blockquote>

<p> </p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981561/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 17:20:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981508/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (buildah, gvisor-tap-vsock, kernel-rt, libreswan, linux-firmware, pki-core, and podman), <b>Fedora</b> (firefox and jpegxl), <b>Gentoo</b> (Buildah, HarfBuzz, and LIVE555 Media Server), <b>Oracle</b> (buildah, gvisor-tap-vsock, kernel, libreswan, and podman), <b>Red Hat</b> (containernetworking-plugins, dotnet6.0, dotnet8.0, fence-agents, kernel, libreswan, libvirt, perl-HTTP-Tiny, python39:3.9, toolbox, and virt:rhel and virt-devel:rhel modules), <b>SUSE</b> (firefox, freeradius-server, haproxy, jbigkit, kernel, kernel-firmware, pam, ppp, python3-cryptography, skopeo, and tar), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (dotnet6, dotnet8, exim4, firefox, golang-1.21, golang-1.22, openssh, and python-django).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981508/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 13:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Firefox 128.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981334/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/128.0/releasenotes/">Version
128.0</a> of the Firefox browser has been released.  Changes this time
include the ability to translate highlighted phrases from the context menu,
display of recent searches on opening the address bar (US/Canada only), a
streamlined dialog for clearing user data, and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981334/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Another OpenSSH remote code execution vulnerability</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981287/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Alexander "Solar Designer" Peslyak has <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20240708162106.GA4920@openwall.com">disclosed another OpenSSH
vulnerability</a> that can be exploited for remote code execution, but only
on distributions that have applied a patch to add auditing support.
Specifically, RHEL&nbsp;9 and derivatives are affected, as are
Fedora&nbsp;36 and&nbsp;37 (but not later releases).
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	The main difference from CVE-2024-6387 is that the race condition
	and RCE potential are triggered in the privsep child process, which
	runs with reduced privileges compared to the parent server process.
	So immediate impact is lower.  However, there may be differences in
	exploitability of these vulnerabilities in a particular scenario,
	which could make either one of these a more attractive choice for
	an attacker, and if only one of these is fixed or mitigated then
	the other becomes more relevant.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981287/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 13:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Stable kernel update 6.6.38</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981256/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/981255/">6.6.38</a> stable kernel update has been
released, without the benefit of the usual review process.  It reverts some
BPF changes with patches that do not appear in the mainline (in this form,
at least).  "<q>All powerpc and arm64 users of the 6.6 kernel series must
upgrade.  Everyone else probably should as well to be safe.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981256/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 12:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981285/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (virt:rhel and virt-devel:rhel), <b>Fedora</b> (ghostscript, golang, httpd, libnbd, netatalk, rust-sequoia-chameleon-gnupg, rust-sequoia-gpg-agent, rust-sequoia-keystore, rust-sequoia-openpgp, and rust-sequoia-sq), <b>Mageia</b> (apache), <b>Red Hat</b> (booth, buildah, edk2, fence-agents, git, gvisor-tap-vsock, kernel, kernel-rt, less, libreswan, linux-firmware, openssh, pki-core, podman, postgresql-jdbc, python3, tpm2-tss, virt:rhel, and virt:rhel and virt-devel:rhel modules), <b>SUSE</b> (krb5, poppler, and python-docker), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (apache2, cinder, glance, nova, and Tomcat).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981285/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 13:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Esfahbod: State of Text Rendering 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981178/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On his blog, Behdad Esfahbod has <a href="https://behdad.org/text2024/">published</a> a lengthy and detailed look at the state of open-source text rendering.  It looks at the libraries available, application support, future directions, and gives a summary analysis of the ecosystem. 

<blockquote class="bq">
In broad strokes, OpenType added support for <i>color fonts</i>, <i>variable fonts</i>, and the <i>Universal Shaping Engine</i>. The Free &amp; Open Source stack supports all of these advances at the lower level, but application UI support has been slower to arrive. The Open Source text stack also gained enormous market-share when Android and Google Chrome fully embraced it.
<p>
Looking forward, there is a <i>Rust</i> migration of the text stack underway, which will unify font compilation and consumption under a safe programming language. <i>Incremental Font Transfer</i> will enable streaming fonts to web browsers. And my proposed <i>Wasm-fonts</i> will enable more expressive fonts.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981178/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 03:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>GDB 15.1 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981080/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Version 15.1 of the GNU debugger has been released.  Changes include a
number of enhancements to GDB's Python support, some Debugger Adapter
Protocol additions, some new GDBserver options, and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981080/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 14:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981119/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (openssh), <b>Debian</b> (krb5), <b>Fedora</b> (yt-dlp), <b>Gentoo</b> (firefox, KDE Plasma Workspaces, Stellarium, thunderbird, and X.Org X11 library), <b>Mageia</b> (python-js2py and znc), <b>Oracle</b> (389-ds, c-ares, container-tools, cups, go-toolset, httpd:2.4/httpd, iperf3, kernel, less, libreoffice, libuv, nghttp2, openldap, openssh, python-idna, python-jinja2, python-pillow, python3, python3.11-PyMySQL, and xmlrpc-c), <b>Red Hat</b> (kernel, kernel-rt, openssh, and virt:rhel and virt-devel:rhel modules), and <b>SUSE</b> (go1.21, go1.22, krb5, kubevirt, virt-api-container, virt-controller-container, virt-exportproxy-container, virt-exportserver-container, virt-handler-container, virt-launcher-container, virt-libguestfs-t, netty3, opera, and python-urllib3).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981119/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 14:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.10-rc7</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981020/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/981019/">6.10-rc7</a> kernel prepatch is out for
testing.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Things remain calm, although I do suspect that part of it is that
	it's been the July 4th week in the US, and a lot of Europe is
	starting to go away on summer vacation.
<p>
	But hey, let's not look a gift horse too closely in the
	mouth. Maybe it's really just that 6.10 is shaping up well. Right?
	RIGHT?
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981020/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 23:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/980855/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (cockpit, python-astropy, python3-docs, and python3.12), <b>Gentoo</b> (BusyBox, GNU Coreutils, GraphicsMagick, podman, PuTTY, Sofia-SIP, TigerVNC, and WebKitGTK+), <b>Mageia</b> (chromium-browser-stable and openvpn), <b>SUSE</b> (cockpit, krb5, and netatalk), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (kopanocore, libreoffice, linux-aws, linux-oem-6.8, linux-aws-5.15, linux-azure, linux-azure-4.15, linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-6.5, linux-oracle, linux-starfive-6.5, and virtuoso-opensource).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/980855/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 12:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Seven new stable kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/980856/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Greg Kroah-Hartman has announced the release of seven more stable kernels.
Versions <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/980859/">6.9.8</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/980860/">6.9.37</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/980861/">6.1.97</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/980862/">5.15.162</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/980863/">5.10.221</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/980864/">5.4.279</a>,
and <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/980865/">4.19.317</a> are now available.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/980856/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 12:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/980755/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (389-ds, c-ares, container-tools, cups, fontforge, go-toolset, iperf3, less, libreoffice, libuv, nghttp2, openldap, python-idna, python-jinja2, python-pillow, python3, python3.11-PyMySQL, qemu-kvm, and xmlrpc-c), <b>Debian</b> (znc), <b>Fedora</b> (firmitas and libnbd), <b>Mageia</b> (dcmtk, krb5, libcdio, and openssh), <b>Oracle</b> (golang, openssh, pki-core, and qemu-kvm), <b>Red Hat</b> (openssh), <b>SUSE</b> (apache2-mod_auth_openidc, emacs, go1.21, go1.22, krb5, openCryptoki, and openssh), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-hwe, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-4.15, linux-hwe,
 linux-kvm, linux-oracle, linux, linux-aws, linux-azure, linux-azure-5.4, linux-bluefield,
 linux-gcp, linux-gkeop, linux-hwe-5.4, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.4,
 linux-iot, linux-kvm, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-5.4, linux-raspi,
 linux-raspi-5.4, linux-xilinx-zynqmp, linux, linux-aws, linux-kvm, linux-lts-xenial, linux, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-6.5, linux-laptop, linux-nvidia-6.5,
 linux-raspi, linux, linux-gcp, linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-5.15,
 linux-nvidia, linux-xilinx-zynqmp, linux, linux-ibm, linux-lowlatency, linux-nvidia, linux-raspi, linux-aws, linux-aws-6.5, linux-oem-6.5, linux-oracle, linux-oracle-6.5,
 linux-starfive, linux-aws, linux-azure, linux-azure-5.15, linux-azure-fde,
 linux-azure-fde-5.15, linux-gke, linux-gkeop, linux-gkeop-5.15, linux-ibm,
 linux-intel-iotg, linux-intel-iotg-5.15, linux-kvm, linux-oracle,
 linux-oracle-5.15, linux-azure, linux-azure, linux-azure-6.5, linux-bluefield, linux-iot, linux-gcp, linux-intel, linux-hwe-5.15, and php7.0 and php7.2).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/980755/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 15:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for June 27, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979084/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for June 27, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979084/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 23:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Finishing the conversion to the &quot;new&quot; mount API</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979166/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Eric Sandeen led a filesystem-track session at 
the
2024 <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a> on completing the
conversion of the existing kernel filesystems to use the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/759499/">mount API</a> that was <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/787963/">added for the 5.2 kernel</a> in 2019.  That API is
invariably called the "new" API, which it <i>is</i> when compared to the
venerable <a 
href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man2/mount.2.html"><tt>mount()</tt></a>
system call, but it has been available for five years or so at this point
without really pushing its predecessor aside.  Sandeen wanted to discuss
the status of the conversion process and some other questions surrounding
the new API.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979166/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Programming in Unison</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978955/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
<a href="https://www.unison-lang.org/">
Unison</a> is a
MIT-licensed programming language, in development since 2013, that
explores the ramifications of making code immutable and stored in a database,
instead of a set of text files.
Unison supports a greatly simplified model for distributed
programming — one that describes the configuration of and communication between
programs in the same language as the programs themselves. Along the way, it
introduces a new approach to interfacing with programming languages, which is tailored to
its design.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978955/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Making containers bootable for fun and profit</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/979182/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Dan Walsh, Stef Walter, and Colin Walters all walk into a
presentation and Walter asks, "why would
you want to boot your containers?" This isn't the setup for some technology joke, this is part of the trio's
<a href="https://pretalx.com/devconf-cz-2024/talk/AVSUU3/">keynote at
DevConf.cz</a> in Brno, Czech Republic on June&nbsp;14 about <a
href="https://containers.github.io/bootc/">bootable containers</a>
(bootc). The talk, which was streamed to YouTube for those of us who
didn't attend DevConf.cz in person, provided a solid overview of bootc
and the problems it is intended to solve. The idea behind bootc is to
make creating operating-system images just as easy as creating
application-container images while using the same tools.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/979182/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The GhostBSD in the machine</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978837/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.ghostbsd.org/">GhostBSD</a> is a
desktop-oriented operating system based on <a
href="https://www.freebsd.org/">FreeBSD</a> and the <a
href="https://mate-desktop.org/">MATE Desktop Environment</a>. The
goal of the project is to lower the barrier to entry of using FreeBSD
on a desktop or laptop system, and it largely succeeds at this. While it has a few rough edges
that make it hard to recommend for the average desktop user, it is
a fine choice for users who want a desktop with FreeBSD underpinnings
such as the Z File System (ZFS), and the <a
href="https://wiki.ghostbsd.org/index.php/Ports">Ports</a> (source) and <a
href="https://wiki.ghostbsd.org/index.php/Pkg">Packages</a> (binary) software collections.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978837/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 14:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Rust for filesystems</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978738/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[At the
2024 <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>, Wedson Almeida Filho and
Kent Overstreet led a combined storage and filesystem session on using Rust
for Linux filesystems. Back in December 2023, Almeida had <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-fsdevel/20231018122518.128049-1-wedsonaf@gmail.com/">posted
an RFC patch set</a> with
some Rust abstractions for filesystems, which resulted in <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/958072/">some disagreement over the approach</a>.  On the
same mid-May day as the session, he <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20240514131711.379322-1-wedsonaf@gmail.com/">posted</a>
a second version of the RFC patches, which he wanted to discuss along with
other Rust-related topics.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978738/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 14:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A capability set for user namespaces</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978846/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/532593/">User namespaces</a> in Linux create an
environment in which all privileges are granted, but their effect is
contained within the namespace; they have become an important tool for the
implementation of containers.  They have also become a significant source
of worries for people who do not like the increased attack surface they
create for the kernel.  Various attempts have been made to restrict that
attack surface over the years; the latest is <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20240609104355.442002-1-jcalmels@3xx0.net">user namespace
capabilities</a>, posted by Jonathan Calmels.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978846/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 18:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Updates to pahole</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/978727/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Arnaldo Carvalho de Melo spoke at the 2024
<a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>
about his work on
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/335942/">
Poke-a-hole</a> (pahole),
a program that has expanded greatly over the years, but which was relevant to the
BPF track because it produces BPF Type Format (BTF) information from DWARF
debugging information. He covered some small changes to the program, and then
went into detail about the new support for data-type profiling. His
<a href="http://vger.kernel.org/~acme/prez/lsfmm-bpf-2024/">slides</a> include
several examples.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/978727/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>