<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 19:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 19:48:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Linux-related discussion as a cybersecurity threat</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006328/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://distrowatch.com/weekly.php?issue=20250127">DistroWatch
January 27 edition</a> includes this interesting tidbit:
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Starting on January 19, 2025 Facebook's internal policy makers
	decided that Linux is malware and labeled groups associated with
	Linux as being "cybersecurity threats". Any posts mentioning
	DistroWatch and multiple groups associated with Linux and Linux
	discussions have either been shut down or had many of their posts
	removed.
<p>
	We've been hearing all week from readers who say they can no longer
	post about Linux on Facebook or share links to DistroWatch. Some
	people have reported their accounts have been locked or limited for
	posting about Linux. 
</blockquote>
<p>
One can only hope that this is a mistake that will be resolved soon.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006328/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 15:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006261/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (git-lfs, java-17-openjdk, java-21-openjdk, kernel, and python-jinja2), <b>Debian</b> (git and git-lfs), <b>Fedora</b> (buildah, chromium, containers-common, freeipa, glibc, golang, mediawiki, pam-u2f, podman, and rsync), <b>Mageia</b> (glibc, iperf, openssl, phpmyadmin, and poppler), <b>Oracle</b> (firefox, git-lfs, grafana, java-17-openjdk, java-21-openjdk, kernel, python-jinja2, and redis:6), and <b>SUSE</b> (chromium, go1.22-1.22.11-1.1, go1.23-1.23.5-1.1, go1.24-1.24rc2-1.1, java-11-openjdk, kernel, libopenssl-3-devel, libQt6Bluetooth6, nodejs18, nodejs20, python311-azure-storage-blob, qt6-connectivity, and ruby3.4-rubygem-nokogiri-1.18.2-1.1).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006261/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 14:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006103/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (chromium and python-django), <b>Fedora</b> (git-lfs and pam-u2f), <b>Mageia</b> (golang), <b>Red Hat</b> (java-11-openjdk with Extended Lifecycle Support, java-17-openjdk, and java-21-openjdk), <b>SUSE</b> (cheat, dante, docker-stable, grafana, and kernel), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (cacti, cyrus-imapd, HTMLDOC, and PCL).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006103/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 15:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Four new stable kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006006/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Greg Kroah-Hartman has released the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1006009/">6.12.11</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1006010/">6.6.74</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1006011/">6.1.127</a>, and <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1006012/">5.15.177</a> stable kernels.  They all contain
important fixes, as is the usual case.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006006/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 23:07:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005946/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (redis:6), <b>Debian</b> (frr and git-lfs), <b>Fedora</b> (SDL2_sound and webkit2gtk4.0), <b>Gentoo</b> (firefox, GPL Ghostscript, libgsf, libuv, PHP, Qt, QtWebEngine, and Yubico pam-u2f), <b>Mageia</b> (chromium-browser-stable), <b>SUSE</b> (helmfile, nvidia-modprobe, qt6-webengine, ruby3.4-rubygem-actioncable-8.0-8.0.1-1.1, ruby3.4-rubygem-actionpack-8.0-8.0.1-1.1, ruby3.4-rubygem-actiontext-8.0-8.0.1-1.1, ruby3.4-rubygem-actionview-8.0-8.0.1-1.1, ruby3.4-rubygem-activejob-8.0-8.0.1-1.1, ruby3.4-rubygem-activerecord-8.0-8.0.1-1.1, ruby3.4-rubygem-activestorage-8.0-8.0.1-1.1, ruby3.4-rubygem-rails-8.0-8.0.1-1.1, and ruby3.4-rubygem-railties-8.0-8.0.1-1.1), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (bluez, openjpeg2, and python-django).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005946/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 15:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Ghostty 1.0 has been summoned</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004377/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://ghostty.org/">Ghostty</a> terminal emulator
project has generated a surprising amount of interest, even before
code was released to the public. This is in part due to the high
profile of its creator, <a
href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HashiCorp">HashiCorp</a> founder
Mitchell Hashimoto. Its development was conducted behind closed doors
for beta testing, until version&nbsp;1.0 was <a
href="https://github.com/ghostty-org/ghostty/releases/tag/v1.0.0">released</a>
on December 26 under the <a
href="https://github.com/ghostty-org/ghostty?tab=MIT-1-ov-file#readme">MIT
license</a>. While far from finished, Ghostty is ready for day-to-day
use and might be of interest to those who spend significant amounts of
time at the command line.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004377/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The slow death of TuxFamily</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004988/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.tuxfamily.org/">TuxFamily</a> is a
French free-software-hosting service that has been in operation since
1999. It is a non-profit that <a
href="https://www.tuxfamily.org/en/about">accepts</a> "<q>any project
released under a free license</q>", whether that is a software license
or a free-content license, such as CC-BY-SA. It is also,
unfortunately, slowly dying due to hardware failures and lack of
interest. For example, the site's download servers are currently
offline with no plan to restore them.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004988/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Modifying another process&apos;s system calls</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004455/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a
href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man2/ptrace.2.html"><tt>ptrace()</tt></a>
system call allows a suitably privileged process to modify another in a
large number of ways.  Among other things, <tt>ptrace()</tt> can intercept
system calls and make changes to them, but such operations can be fiddly
and architecture-dependent.  <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20250107230153.GA30560@strace.io">This patch series from
Dmitry Levin</a> seeks to improve that situation by adding a new
<tt>ptrace()</tt> operation to make changes to another process's system
calls in an architecture-independent manner.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004455/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 17:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Chimera Linux works toward a simplified desktop</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004324/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
<a href="https://chimera-linux.org/">Chimera Linux</a> is a new distribution
designed to be "<q>simple, transparent, and easy to pick up</q>". The
distribution is built from scratch, and
<a href="https://chimera-linux.org/news/2024/12/entering-beta.html">
recently announced</a> its first beta release. While the documentation and
installation process are both a bit rough, the project already provides a
usable desktop with plenty of useful software — one built primarily on
tools adopted from BSD.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004324/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The state of Vim</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002342/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The death of Bram Moolenaar, <a href="https://www.vim.org/">Vim</a>
founder and benevolent dictator for life (BDFL), in 2023 sent a shock
through the community, and raised concern about the future of the
project. At <a href="https://vimconf.org/">VimConf</a> 2024 in
November, current Vim maintainer Christian Brabandt delivered a
keynote on "<q>the new Vim project</q>" that detailed how the
community has reorganized itself to continue maintaining Vim and what
the future looks like.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002342/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 19:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Page-table hardening with memory protection keys</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004029/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Attacks on the kernel can take many forms; one popular exploitation path is
to find a way to overwrite some memory with attacker-supplied data.  If the
right memory can be targeted, one well-targeted stray write is all that is
needed to take control of the system.  Since the system's page tables
regulate access to memory, they are an attractive target for this type of
attack.  <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20250108103250.3188419-1-kevin.brodsky@arm.com">This patch 
set</a> from Kevin Brodsky is an attempt to protect page tables (and,
eventually, other data structures) using the "memory protection keys"
feature provided by a number of CPU architectures.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004029/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 15:16:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Zero-trust builds for FreeBSD</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005838/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://freebsdfoundation.org/">FreeBSD Foundation</a>
has <a href="https://freebsdfoundation.org/blog/zero-trust-builds-for-freebsd/">announced</a> that it has undertaken a project to deliver zero-trust
builds commissioned by the <a
href="https://www.sovereign.tech/">Sovereign Tech Agency</a> (STA).</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>The Zero-Trust Build project is scheduled from Jan-Aug 2025 and
centers on the FreeBSD build process, and in particular, release
building. The primary goal of this work is to enable the entire
release process to run without requiring root access, and that build
artifacts build reproducibly – that is, that a third party can build
bit-for-bit identical artifacts.</p>

<p>Additionally, the project aims to enhance build process
documentation, ensuring that release building is straightforward and
does not require specialized knowledge. The work is targeted for
completion prior to the release of FreeBSD 15.0.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The Foundation says that updates should not impact users of FreeBSD
release images, but it may have an impact on developers basing
projects or products on FreeBSD that make modifications to its release
process.</p>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005838/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 19:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Puppet fork OpenVox makes first release</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005781/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://voxpupuli.org/">Vox Pupuli</a> project has
announced the first release of <a
href="https://voxpupuli.org/openvox/">OpenVox</a>, a
"<q>soft-fork</q>" of the <a href="https://www.puppet.com/">Puppet</a>
automation framework. The intention to fork was <a
href="https://github.com/OpenVoxProject/planning/discussions/11">announced</a>
in December&nbsp;2024.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>OpenVox 8.11 is functionally equivalent to Puppet and should be a
drop-in replacement. Be aware, of course, that even though you can
type the same commands, use all the same modules and extensions, and
configure the same settings, OpenVox is not yet tested to the same
standard that Puppet is. [...]</p>

<p>Please don't use these packages on critical production
infrastructures yet, unless you're comfortable with troubleshooting
and reporting back on the silly errors we've made while rebranding and
rebuilding.</p>
</blockquote>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005781/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Wine 10.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005801/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://gitlab.winehq.org/wine/wine/-/releases/wine-10.0">Version
10.0</a> of the Wine Windows compatibility layer is out.  "<q>This release
represents a year of development effort and over 6,000 individual
changes</q>".  Those changes include full support for the ARM64EC
architecture, better high-DPI display support, Wayland enabled by default,
and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005801/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 14:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005798/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (snapcast), <b>Fedora</b> (python-jinja2), <b>Mageia</b> (rsync), <b>SUSE</b> (cdi-apiserver-container, cdi-cloner-container, cdi- controller-container, cdi-importer-container, cdi-operator-container, cdi- uploadproxy-container, cdi-uploadserver-container, cont, gh, kernel, kubevirt, virt-api-container, virt-controller-container, virt-exportproxy-container, virt-exportserver-container, virt-handler-container, virt-launcher-container, virt-libguestfs-t, nvidia-open-driver-G06-signed, and pam_u2f), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-oem-6.11 and vim).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005798/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 14:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005708/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (grafana), <b>Debian</b> (libebml, poco, redis, sympa, tiff, and ucf), <b>Fedora</b> (rsync), <b>Mageia</b> (dcmtk, git, proftpd, and raptor2), <b>Red Hat</b> (grafana, iperf3, kernel, microcode_ctl, and redis), <b>SUSE</b> (chromium, dhcp, git, libqt5-qtwebkit, and pam_u2f), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (python3.10, python3.8 and python3.12).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005708/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 14:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Stable kernel 6.6.73</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005710/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The series of singleton stable kernel updates continues with <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1005709/">6.6.73</a>, which reverts three changes that were
causing problems for users of the overlayfs filesystem.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1005710/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 14:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>