<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 18:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 18:12:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Firefox 127.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977973/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/127.0/releasenotes/">Version
127.0</a> of the Firefox browser is out.  Changes include support for DNS
prefetching and the ability to close duplicate tabs in a window.  The
browser will now try to upgrade images and videos with HTTP URLs that are
found in an HTTPS page to HTTPS as well; if that fails, the non-HTTPS
resources will simply fail to load.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977973/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 16:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977939/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (ruby:3.3), <b>Fedora</b> (efifs, libvirt, podman-tui, prometheus-podman-exporter, and strongswan), <b>Red Hat</b> (firefox, idm:DL1, ipa, nghttp2, and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (aws-nitro-enclaves-cli, cdi-apiserver-container, cdi-cloner-container, cdi- controller-container, cdi-importer-container, cdi-operator-container, cdi- uploadproxy-container, cdi-uploadserver-container, containerized-data-importer, frr, glibc, go1.21, go1.22, gstreamer-plugins-base, kernel, kernel-firmware-nvidia-gspx-G06, nvidia-open- driver-G06-signed, libxml2, mariadb, poppler, python-Brotli, python-docker, python-idna, rmt-server, skopeo, sssd, unbound, unrar, util-linux, and webkit2gtk3), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (giflib, libphp-adodb, linux-gkeop, linux-gkeop-5.15, linux-kvm, linux-laptop, linux-oem-6.8, nodejs, and tiff).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977939/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 13:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>perl v5.40.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977765/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Version 5.40.0 of the Perl language has been released.  "<q>Perl 5.40.0
represents approximately 11 months of development since Perl 5.38.0 and
contains approximately 160,000 lines of changes across 1,500 files from 75
authors</q>".  Significant changes include a new <tt>__CLASS__</tt>
keyword, a <tt>:reader:</tt> attribute for field variables, a new
"<tt>^^</tt>" logical-OR operator (because two of those were not enough),
moving "<tt>try/catch</tt>" out of the experimental category, and more; see
<a
href="https://metacpan.org/release/HAARG/perl-5.40.0/view/pod/perldelta.pod">this
page</a> for lots of details.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977765/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 15:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977789/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (galera and mariadb10.11), <b>Mageia</b> (0-plugins-base and plasma-workspace), <b>Oracle</b> (ruby:3.1 and ruby:3.3), <b>Red Hat</b> (bind, bind-dyndb-ldap, and dhcp), <b>SUSE</b> (apache2, glib2, libvirt, openssl-1_1, openssl-3, opera, python-Jinja2, python-requests, and squid), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.15, linux-lowlatency,
 linux-lowlatency-hwe-5.15, linux-xilinx-zynqmp, linux, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-6.5, linux-lowlatency,
 linux-lowlatency-hwe-6.5, linux-raspi, linux, linux-ibm, linux-lowlatency, linux-raspi, linux-aws, linux-gcp, linux-azure, linux-azure-6.5, linux-starfive, linux-starfive-6.5, and linux-gke, linux-ibm, linux-intel-iotg, linux-oracle).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977789/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 14:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.10-rc3</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977725/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/977724/">6.10-rc3</a> kernel prepatch is out.
"<q>So things look good, the water is warm, please jump right in and keep
testing,</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977725/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 03:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Linux nftables vulnerability exploited in the wild (CrowdStrike)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977583/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
<a
href="https://www.crowdstrike.com/blog/active-exploitation-linux-kernel-privilege-escalation-vulnerability/">
According to CrowdStrike</a>, a
<a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2024-1086">
vulnerability</a> in the Linux kernel's nftables code
that was <a href="https://pwning.tech/nftables/"> discovered earlier this
year</a> is being actively exploited in the wild. The vulnerability allows for
local privilege escalation. Most distributions have already released a fix.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
As noted by the exploit developer, leveraging this POC is dependent on the
kernel's unprivileged user namespaces feature accessing nf_tables. This access
is enabled by default on Debian, Ubuntu and kernel capture-the-flag (CTF)
distributions. An attacker can then trigger the double-free vulnerability, scan
the physical memory for the kernel base address, bypass kernel address-space
layout randomization (KASLR) and access the modprobe_path kernel variable with
read/write privileges. After overwriting the modprobe_path, the exploit drops a
root shell.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977583/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 17:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977555/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Mageia</b> (libtiff), <b>Oracle</b> (cockpit, glibc, kernel, less, libxml2, linux-kernel, and tomcat), <b>Red Hat</b> (java-1.8.0-ibm, nghttp2, and ruby:3.3), <b>Slackware</b> (php), <b>SUSE</b> (go1.21, go1.22, and python-docker), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (aom and libvpx).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977555/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 13:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977442/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (cockpit, kernel, kernel-rt, libxml2, ruby:3.1, and tomcat), <b>Debian</b> (libarchive, pillow, and tinyproxy), <b>Fedora</b> (apptainer), <b>Mageia</b> (amavisd-new and libxml2), <b>Oracle</b> (edk2), <b>Red Hat</b> (booth, cockpit, kernel-rt, less, libxml2, nghttp2, ruby:3.1, ruby:3.3, and tomcat), <b>Slackware</b> (kernel), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (atril, bluez, frr, gdk-pixbuf, openjdk-17, openjdk-21, openjdk-8, openjdk-lts, qemu, and unixodbc).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977442/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 16:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for May 30, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974709/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for May 30, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974709/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 02:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Fedora approves shipping pre-built macOS binaries</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/975445/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://asahilinux.org/">Asahi Linux</a> project works
to support Linux on Apple Silicon hardware. The
project's <a
href="https://asahilinux.org/2023/08/fedora-asahi-remix/">flagship</a>
distribution is the <a href="https://asahilinux.org/fedora/">Fedora
Asahi Remix</a>, which has its own <a
href="https://github.com/AsahiLinux/asahi-installer">installer</a> (rather than <a
href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Anaconda">Anaconda</a>) to
accommodate the unique requirements of installing on Apple's
hardware. Previously the installer was built by the Asahi project, but it has asked for (and received) an exception
from the <a href="https://docs.fedoraproject.org/en-US/fesco/">Fedora
Engineering Steering Committee</a> (FESCo) to include two binaries
from upstream open-source projects so that the installer can be built on Fedora
infrastructure.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/975445/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 18:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Supporting BPF in GCC</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/975412/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The GCC project has been <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/946254">working</a> to support compiling to BPF
for some time. José Marchesi and David Faust spoke in an extended session at the 2024
<a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>
about how that work has been going, and what is left for GCC to be on-par with
LLVM with regard to BPF support. They also related tentative plans for how
GCC BPF support would be maintained in the future.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/975412/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 19:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Filesystems and iomap</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974958/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://kernelnewbies.org/KernelProjects/iomap">iomap</a>
block-mapping abstraction is being used by more filesystems, in part
because of its support for large folios.  But there are some challenges in
adopting iomap, which was the topic of a discussion led by Ritesh Harjani
in a combined storage and filesystem session at the 2024 <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>.  One of the main trouble
spots is how to handle metadata, which is not an area that iomap has been aimed
at.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974958/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 13:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The state of the memory-management community in 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974939/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[A longstanding tradition in the memory-management track of the <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory-Management and BPF Summit</a> is a session with
maintainer Andrew Morton to discuss the overall state of the community and
the development process.  The 2024 gathering upheld that tradition toward
the end of the final day of the event.  It seems that Morton and the
assembled developers were all happy with how memory-management work is
going, but there is always room for improvement.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974939/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 13:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Measuring memory fragmentation</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974943/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In the final session in the memory-management track of the <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">2024 Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory-Management and BPF Summit</a>, the exhausted group of
developers looked one more time at the use of huge pages and the associated
problem of memory fragmentation.  At its worst, this problem can make huge
pages harder (and more expensive) to allocate.  Luis Chamberlain, who ran
the session, felt that people were worried about this problem, but that
there was little data on how severe it truly is.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974943/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 13:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LLVM improvements for BPF verification</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974945/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Alan Jowett gave a remote presentation at the 2024
<a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a> about what features could be
added to LLVM to make writing BPF programs easier. While there is nothing specific
to LLVM about BPF code (and the next session in the track was led by GCC
developer José Marchesi about better support for that compiler), LLVM is currently the most
common way to turn C code into BPF bytecode. That translation, however, runs
into problems when the BPF verifier cannot understand the code LLVM's
optimizations produce.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974945/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 17:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Fleshing out memory descriptors</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974937/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[One of the long-term goals of the folio conversion in the kernel's
memory-management subsystem is the replacement of the <tt>page</tt>
structure, which describes a page of physical memory, with an eight-byte
"memory descriptor".  This change would reduce the overhead of tracking
physical memory, increase type safety, and make memory management more
flexible.  Thus far, though, details on what the memory-descriptor future
will look like have been relatively scarce.  At the <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">2024 Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory-Management and BPF Summit</a>, Matthew Wilcox led a
discussion to try to fill in the picture somewhat.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974937/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 13:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The rest of the 6.10 merge window</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974869/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/975144/">released 6.10-rc1</a> and closed
the 6.10 merge window on May&nbsp;26.  By that time, 11,534 non-merge
changesets had been pulled into the mainline for the next release; nearly
5,000 of those came in after "<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/973687/">The first half of
the 6.10 merge window</a>" was written.  While the latter half of the merge
window tends to focus more on fixes, there was also a lot of new
functionality that landed during this time.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974869/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 13:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The next steps for the maple tree</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974860/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/845507/">maple tree data structure</a> was added
during the 6.1 development cycle; since then, it has taken its
place at the core of the kernel's memory-management subsystem.
Unsurprisingly, work on maple trees is not yet done.  Maple-tree maintainer
Liam Howlett ran a session in the memory-management track of the <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">2024 Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory-Management and BPF Summit</a> to discuss the current
state of the maple tree and which features can be expected next.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974860/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 12:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Two talks on multi-size transparent huge page performance</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974826/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Using huge pages has been known for years to improve the performance of
many workloads.  But traditional huge pages, often sized by the CPU at 2MB,
can be difficult to allocate and can waste memory due to internal
fragmentation.  Driven by both the folio transition and hardware
improvements, attention to smaller, multi-size transparent huge pages
(mTHPs) has been on the rise.  In two memory-management-track sessions at
the <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">2024 Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory-Management and BPF Summit</a>, developers discussed the
kernel's ability to reliably allocate mTHPs and the performance gains that
result.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974826/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 16:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Atomic writes without tears</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974578/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[John Garry and Ted Ts'o led a discussion about supporting atomic writes for buffered
I/O, without any torn (or partial) writes to the device, at the 2024 <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>.  It is something of a
continuation of a <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/933015/">discussion at last year's
summit</a>. The goal is to help PostgreSQL, which writes its data using
16KB buffered I/O; it currently has to do a lot of extra work to ensure
that its data is safe on disk.  A promise of non-torn, 16KB buffered writes
would allow the database 
to avoid doing double writes.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974578/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 21:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Allocator optimizations for transparent huge pages</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974636/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The original Linux kernel, posted in 1991, ran on a system with a 4KB page
size.  Over 30&nbsp;years later, most of us are still running on systems
with 4KB pages, even though the amount of installed memory has grown by a
few orders of magnitude.  It is generally accepted that using large page
sizes results in better performance for most applications, but allocating
larger pages is often difficult.  During a memory-management session at the <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">2024 Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory-Management and BPF Summit</a>, Yu Zhao presented his
ideas on improving the allocation of huge pages in the kernel.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974636/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 20:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Recent improvements to BPF&apos;s struct_ops mechanism</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974848/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Kui-Feng Lee spoke early in the BPF track at the 2024
<a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a> about some of the
recent improvements to BPF. These changes were largely driven by the
sched_ext work that David Vernet had <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/974387">covered in
the previous talk</a>. Lee focused on changes relevant to <tt>struct_ops</tt>
programs, but several of those changes apply to all BPF programs.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974848/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 19:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Readying DNF5 for Fedora 41</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/969640/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>With the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/970893/">release</a> of <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/969145/">Fedora&nbsp;40</a> it's time to
start looking ahead to what Fedora&nbsp;41 has in store. One of the largest
changes planned for the next release is a switch to
DNF5, a C++ rewrite of the <a
href="https://docs.fedoraproject.org/en-US/quick-docs/dnf/">DNF</a>
package manager. A previous attempt to make the switch, during the Fedora&nbsp;39 cycle, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/941154/">was called off</a>, and
deferred to Fedora&nbsp;41. The developers have had nearly a year to address
compatibility problems and bring DNF5 to a state suitable to replace DNF4. Signs point to a successful switch in
the upcoming release, though there may be a few surprises lurking for Fedora users.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/969640/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 16:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Large-folio support for shmem and tmpfs</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974630/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The kernel contains a pair of related filesystems that, among other things,
can be used for shared-memory applications; shmem is an internal mechanism
used within the kernel, while the tmpfs filesystem is mounted and
accessible from user space.  As is the case elsewhere in the kernel, these
subsystems would benefit from the addition of large-folio support.  During
a joint storage, filesystem, and memory-management session at the <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">2024 Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory-Management and BPF Summit</a>, Daniel Gomez talked about
the work he is doing to add that support.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974630/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 14:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A new swap abstraction layer for the kernel</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974587/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Swapping may be a memory-management technique at its core, but its
implementation also involves the kernel's filesystem and storage layers.
So it is not surprising that a session on the kernel's swap abstraction
layer, led by Chris Li at the <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">2024 Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory-Management and BPF Summit</a>, was held jointly by all
three of those tracks.  Li has some ambitious ideas for an improved
subsystem, but getting to a workable implementation may not be easy.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974587/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 19:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] What&apos;s scheduled for sched_ext</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974387/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
David Vernet's second talk at the 2024
<a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a> was a summary of the state of
sched_ext, the extensible BPF scheduler that <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/972710/">LWN
covered a in early May</a>. In short, sched_ext is intended as a platform for
rapid experimentation with schedulers, and a tool to let performance-minded
administrators customize the scheduler to their workload. The patch set has seen
several revisions, becoming more generic and powerful over time.
Vernet spoke about what has been done in the past year,
and what is still missing before sched_ext can be considered pretty much
complete.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974387/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 17:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The twilight of the version-1 memory controller</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974575/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Almost immediately after the merging of <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/603762/">control
groups</a>, kernel developers set their sights on reimplementing them
properly.  The second version of the control-group API started trickling
into the kernel around the 3.16 release in 2014 and users have long since
been encouraged to migrate, but support for (and users of) the initial API
remain.  At the <a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">2024
Linux Storage, Filesystem, Memory-Management and BPF Summit</a>,
memory-management developers discussed whether (and when) it might be
possible to remove the version-1 memory controller.  The session was led by
Shakeel Butt and (participating remotely) Roman Gushchin.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974575/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 14:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kali Linux 2024.2 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977303/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Version 2024.2 of the <a href="https://www.kali.org/">Kali Linux</a> penetration testing distribution
has been <a
href="https://www.kali.org/blog/kali-linux-2024-2-release/">released</a>. This
release includes an update to <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/966187/">GNOME
46</a>, a high-resolution (HiDPI) mode for Xfce, as well as a number
of new packages such as the <a
href="https://www.kali.org/tools/autorecon/">AutoRecon</a> network
reconnaissance tool, <a
href="https://www.kali.org/tools/pspy/">pspy</a> command-line utility for
snooping on Linux processes, and <a
href="https://www.kali.org/tools/sploitscan/">SploitScan</a> tool for
fetching and displaying CVE information. Kali Linux is based on Debian
testing, and 2024.2 incorporates Debian's work to <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/938149/">transition to 64-bit
time_t</a> to avoid year 2038 problems. Users with existing Kali
systems should be sure to follow the <a
href="https://www.kali.org/docs/general-use/updating-kali/">documentation</a>
when upgrading.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977303/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 19:14:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>FreeBSD 14.1 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977285/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Version 14.1 of <a href="https://www.freebsd.org/">FreeBSD</a> has
been <a
href="https://www.freebsd.org/releases/14.1R/announce/">released</a>. This
is the second release of the 14.x stable branch. Highlights of this
release include upgrades to OpenZFS 2.2.4, Clang/LLVM 18.1.5, and
OpenSSH 9.7p1. FreeBSD 14.1 also features <a href="https://cloud-init.io/">cloud-init</a> support,
sound subsystem improvements, and more. See the
<a
href="https://freebsdfoundation.org/blog/freebsd-14-1-whats-new-and-how-did-we-get-here/">what's
new blog post</a> from the <a
href="https://freebsdfoundation.org/">FreeBSD Foundation</a>, 
<a
href="https://www.freebsd.org/releases/14.1R/relnotes/">release
notes</a>, and <a
href="https://www.freebsd.org/releases/14.1R/errata/">errata</a> for
more information.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977285/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 17:39:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The state of SourceHut</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977174/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Drew DeVault has <a
href="https://sourcehut.org/blog/2024-06-04-status-and-plans/">published</a>
an update about the state of the <a
href="https://sourcehut.org/">SourceHut</a> software development
platform and its plans for the coming months. This is the first update
since the January <a
href="https://sourcehut.org/blog/2024-01-19-outage-post-mortem/">post-mortem</a>
following a distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attack that resulted
in a <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/958125/">prolonged
outage</a>:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>As you can imagine, it has been a stressful time for us. However, I
wish to stress that everything we've been dealing with is planned for
in our models, both technical and financial. There is no existential
threat to SourceHut. Nevertheless, we are grateful for your patience
and support.</p>

<p>[...] We have been focusing on two things this year: provisioning
and managing our infrastructure and getting as much rest as
possible. Our situation has calmed down, and while we still have a lot
of loose ends to attend to I'm happy to say that we're resuming a
sense of normalcy here and preparing to resume our work on the
features you need.</p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977174/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 15:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977233/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (deepin-qt5integration, deepin-qt5platform-plugins, dotnet8.0, dwayland, fcitx-qt5, fcitx5-qt, gammaray, kddockwidgets, keepassxc, kf5-akonadi-server, kf5-frameworkintegration, kf5-kwayland, plasma-integration, python-qt5, qadwaitadecorations, qgnomeplatform, qt5, qt5-qt3d, qt5-qtbase, qt5-qtcharts, qt5-qtconnectivity, qt5-qtdatavis3d, qt5-qtdeclarative, qt5-qtdoc, qt5-qtgamepad, qt5-qtgraphicaleffects, qt5-qtimageformats, qt5-qtlocation, qt5-qtmultimedia, qt5-qtnetworkauth, qt5-qtquickcontrols, qt5-qtquickcontrols2, qt5-qtremoteobjects, qt5-qtscript, qt5-qtscxml, qt5-qtsensors, qt5-qtserialbus, qt5-qtserialport, and qt5-qtspeech), <b>Oracle</b> (389-ds-base and ruby:3.1), <b>Red Hat</b> (389-ds-base, glibc, and kernel), <b>SUSE</b> (python-PyMySQL), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (libarchive).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977233/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 13:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mike Karels has passed away</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977070/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[We have just received <a
href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/BSDCan/permalink/10159552565206372/">the
sad news</a> that longtime core BSD developer Mike Karels has died; he will
certainly be missed.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977070/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 20:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Incus 6.2 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977059/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Version 6.2 of the Incus container-management system is out.  "<q>This
release contains the second wave of changes contributed by students of the
University of Texas at Austin and a few other features and
improvements.</q>"  The features include a new <tt>incus&nbsp;top</tt>
command, a new API for system load information, and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977059/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 19:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New site feature: comment subthread hiding</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/977033/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/975597/">recent discussion</a> on commenting at
LWN, several readers asked for the ability to hide subthreads of a long
comment stream.  That feature has just been added; it is also integrated
with the three comment-display modes and with comment filtering, removing
the need for JavaScript for filtering.  Hiding is not persistent; no extra
data is stored at either end.
<p>
Give it a try; if you have comments on the new mechanism, this is the place
to put them.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/977033/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 18:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>