<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 14:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 6 Sep 2024 14:48:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Man pages maintenance suspended</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989215/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Alejandro Colomar, who has been maintaining the Linux man pages for the
last four years, has <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/4d7tq6a7febsoru3wjium4ekttuw2ouocv6jstdkthnacmzr6x@f2zfbe5hs7h5">announced</a>
that he will have to stop that work.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	 I've been doing it in my free time, and no company has sponsored
	 that work at all.  At the moment, I cannot sustain this work
	 economically any more, and will temporarily and indefinitely stop
	 working on this project.  If any company has interests in the
	 future of the project, I'd welcome an offer to sponsor my work
	 here; if so, please let me know.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989215/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 14:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The realtime preemption end game — for real this time</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989212/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Work on realtime preemption for the Linux kernel <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/106010/">got its start</a> almost exactly 20&nbsp;years ago
(though it had its roots in earlier work, of course).  It is fair to say
that finishing that job has taken a bit longer than anybody involved would
have expected.  Now, though, Sebastian Andrzej Siewior has <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20240906111841.562402-1-bigeasy@linutronix.de">posted a brief
patch series</a> making it possible to enable realtime preemption in the
mainline kernel on three architectures.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	With the printk bits merged, PREEMPT_RT could be enabled on X86,
	ARM64 and Risc-V. These three architectures merged required changes
	over the years leaving me in a position where I have no essential
	changes in the queue that would affect them.
</blockquote>
<p>
Congratulations are due to the many developers who have worked on this
project for the last two decades.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989212/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 14:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989196/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (bubblewrap, flatpak), <b>Debian</b> (libxml2), <b>Fedora</b> (lua-mpack, mingw-python3, python-django, python-django4.2, python3.11, python3.13, and python3.9), <b>Oracle</b> (bubblewrap, flatpak), <b>Red Hat</b> (fence-agents, python-urllib3, resource-agents, and wget), <b>Slackware</b> (expat and mozilla), <b>SUSE</b> (buildah, chromium, firefox, gradle, java-1_8_0-ibm, kubernetes1.26, postgresql16, python-Django, python312-pip, and systemd), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (python-aiohttp).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989196/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 13:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rust 1.81.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989106/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2024/09/05/Rust-1.81.0.html">Version
1.81.0</a> of the Rust language has been released.  Changes include the
stabilization of the <tt>Error</tt> trait in <tt>core</tt>, some new sort
algorithms, some linting improvements, and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989106/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 17:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989046/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (bubblewrap and flatpak, containernetworking-plugins, fence-agents, ghostscript, krb5, orc, podman, python3.11, python3.9, resource-agents, runc, and wget), <b>Debian</b> (chromium, cinder, glance, gnutls28, nova, nsis, python-oslo.utils, ruby-sinatra, and setuptools), <b>Fedora</b> (kernel), <b>Oracle</b> (bubblewrap and flatpak, buildah, containernetworking-plugins, fence-agents, ghostscript, gvisor-tap-vsock, kernel, krb5, libndp, nodejs:18, orc, podman, postgresql, python-urllib3, python3.11, python3.12, python3.9, runc, skopeo, and wget), <b>SUSE</b> (hdf5, netcdf, trilinos), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (firefox, imagemagick, ironic, openssl, python-django, vim, and znc).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989046/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Samba 4.21.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989047/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Version 4.21.0 of the Samba Windows interoperability suite has been
released.  Changes include some authentication hardening, a number of LDAP
improvements, per-user and per-group veto and hide files, group-managed
service accounts, and quite a bit more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989047/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for August 29, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986853/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for August 29, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986853/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 01:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] MemHive: sharing immutable data between Python subinterpreters</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987238/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Immutable data makes concurrent access easier, since it
eliminates the data-race conditions that can plague multithreaded programs. At
<a
href="https://us.pycon.org/2024/">PyCon&nbsp;2024</a>, Yury Selivanov
introduced an early-stage project called <a
href="https://github.com/edgedb/memhive">MemHive</a>, which uses Python
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/820424/">subinterpreters</a> and immutable data to
overcome the problems of thread serialization that are caused by the
language's Global Interpreter Lock (GIL).  Recent <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/985041/">developments in the Python world</a> have opened
up different strategies for avoiding the longstanding problems with the
GIL.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987238/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 19:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Debian discusses principles for package maintenance</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986480/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Achieving consensus among Debian Developers on technical topics and
procedures can be, to put it mildly, challenging. Nevertheless, that
is exactly what Otto Kekäläinen has tried to do with a <a
href="https://salsa.debian.org/dep-team/deps/-/raw/798bfa5a1e1609afd4e48ee20aff80a82bcd4a2f/web/deps/dep18.mdwn">proposal</a> that
would set up "<q>principles all Debian packages should follow to be
open for collaboration in package maintenance</q>". In the near term,
it seems unlikely that the proposal will be accepted, but the
discussion may be effective at improving collaboration nonetheless.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986480/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 14:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] NIST finalizes post-quantum encryption standards</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973231/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
On August 13, the US National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST)
<a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/news/2024/postquantum-cryptography-fips-approved">
published</a> the final form of its new post-quantum cryptographic standards. One
key-exchange mechanism and two digital-signature schemes are now officially
sanctioned by the institute. Adopting the new standards should be fairly
painless for most developers, but the overhead added by the schemes could pose
challenges for some applications.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973231/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 13:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A new version of modversions</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986892/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <tt>genksyms</tt> tool has long been buried deeply within the kernel's
build system; it is one of the two C-code parsers shipped with the kernel
(the other being <a
href="https://elixir.bootlin.com/linux/v6.11-rc4/source/scripts/kernel-doc">the
horrifying <tt>kernel-doc</tt> script</a>).  It is a key part of how the
kernel's module-loading infrastructure works.  While <tt>genksyms</tt> has
quietly done its job for decades, that period may soon be coming to an end.
It would seem that <tt>genksyms</tt> is not up to the task of handling Rust
code, so Sami Tolvanen is <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20240815173903.4172139-21-samitolvanen@google.com/">proposing
a new tool</a> to handle this task going forward.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986892/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 17:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The history, status, and plans for reproducible builds</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/985739/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[On the second day of <a href="https://debconf24.debconf.org/">DebConf24</a>
in Busan, South Korea, Holger Levsen provided a history lesson on the
"first 11 years" of the <a
href="https://reproducible-builds.org/">Reproducible Builds project</a>.
He has been involved in the project for most of that time and has been a
Debian user since the mid-1990s, contributor since 2001, and a Debian
member since 2007; "I love Debian".  Meanwhile, his aim is to make all free
software be reproducible, so that anyone can check that a binary program
comes from the source code it purports to.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/985739/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 13:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Call for candidates for the 2024 Linux Foundation TAB election</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/988862/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/87zforv3zc.fsf@trenco.lwn.net">call for candidates</a>
has gone out for the 2024 election of members of the Linux Foundation
Technical Advisory Board:
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	The TAB exists to provide advice from the kernel community to the
	Linux Foundation and holds a seat on the LF's board of directors;
	it also serves to facilitate interactions both within the community
	and with outside entities.  Over the last year, the TAB has
	overseen the organization of the Linux Plumbers Conference, advised
	on the setup of the kernel CVE numbering authority, worked behind
	the scenes to help resolve a number of contentious community
	discussions, worked with the Linux Foundation on community
	conference planning, and more.
</blockquote>
<p>
Nominations are due by September 20.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/988862/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 18:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tellico 4.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/988837/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://tellico-project.org/tellico-4-0-released/">Version 4.0</a> of the <a
href="https://tellico-project.org/">Tellico</a> collection management
software has been released. This is the first release to use the
KDE&nbsp;Frameworks&nbsp;6 and Qt6 libraries, with a fallback
available for Frameworks&nbsp;5 and Qt5. Other notable changes in 4.0
include importing video collections from file metadata and correctly
importing multi-disc album data from <a
href="https://www.discogs.com/">Discogs</a>, <a
href="https://musicbrainz.org/">MusicBrainz</a>, and <a
href="https://developer.apple.com/library/archive/documentation/AudioVideo/Conceptual/iTuneSearchAPI/index.html">iTunes</a>. Users
of prior versions are advised to make a backup of their data before upgrading.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/988837/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 17:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Seven stable kernel updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/988747/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/988748/">6.10.8</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/988749/">6.6.49</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/988750/">6.1.108</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/988751/">5.15.166</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/988752/">5.10.225</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/988753/">5.5.283</a>, and <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/988754/">4.19.321</a> stable kernel updates have all
been released. As usual, they contain important fixes throughout the
tree. Users of those kernels should upgrade.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/988747/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 13:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/988746/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (buildah, gvisor-tap-vsock, nodejs:18, python-urllib3, and skopeo), <b>Debian</b> (firefox-esr and openssl), <b>Fedora</b> (apr and seamonkey), <b>Red Hat</b> (podman), <b>Slackware</b> (mozilla and seamonkey), <b>SUSE</b> (bubblewrap and flatpak, buildah, docker, dovecot23, ffmpeg, frr, go1.21-openssl, graphviz, java-1_8_0-openj9, kubernetes1.26, kubernetes1.27, kubernetes1.28, openssl-1_0_0, openssl-3, perl-DBI, python-aiohttp, python-Django, python-WebOb, thunderbird, tiff, ucode-intel, unbound, webkit2gtk3, and xen), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (drupal7 and twisted).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/988746/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 12:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Firefox 130.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/988607/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/130.0/releasenotes/">Version
130.0</a> of the Firefox browser has been released. Notable in this
release is the addition of a Firefox Labs tab in Firefox
Settings. This allows users to easily enable experimental features,
such as the ability to translate selected text portions to different
languages after a full-page translation, and <a
href="https://blog.mozilla.org/products/firefox/firefox-news/ai-services-on-firefox/">add
an AI chatbot to the sidebar</a>. Firefox 130 also addresses <a
href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/security/advisories/mfsa2024-39/">several
security issues</a>, adds 11 new languages to its translation support,
and more.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/988607/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 16:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/988570/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (python3.12), <b>Debian</b> (calibre, exfatprogs, frr, git, libtommath, nbconvert, ruby-nokogiri, ruby-tzinfo, and webkit2gtk), <b>Fedora</b> (flatpak, lua-mpack, and python3.12), <b>Red Hat</b> (389-ds-base, 389-ds:1.4, buildah, fence-agents, gvisor-tap-vsock, httpd:2.4, kernel, kernel-rt, nodejs:18, orc, postgresql, postgresql:12, postgresql:13, postgresql:15, python-urllib3, python3.12, and skopeo), <b>SUSE</b> (389-ds, bubblewrap and flatpak, cacti, cacti-spine, curl, glib2, kernel-firmware, libqt5-qt3d, libqt5-qtquick3d, opera, python39, qemu, unbound, xen, and zziplib), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (ffmpeg, linux-raspi-5.4, and python-webob).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/988570/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 13:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/988364/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (postgresql:16), <b>Debian</b> (dovecot, pymatgen, ruby2.7, systemd, and webkit2gtk), <b>Fedora</b> (microcode_ctl, python3.11, vim, and xen), <b>Oracle</b> (kernel, postgresql:12, postgresql:13, postgresql:15, and python39:3.9 and python39-devel:3.9), <b>Slackware</b> (libpcap), <b>SUSE</b> (cacti, cacti-spine, python-Django, and trivy), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (dovecot).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/988364/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 14:23:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.11-rc6</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/988184/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has released <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/988183/">6.11-rc6</a> for testing.
"<q>Things look pretty normal, although we have perhaps unusually many
filesystem fixes here, spread out over smb, xfs, bcachefs and netfs.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/988184/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 14:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Understanding the Postgres Hackers Mailing List Language</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987892/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Reading an established open-source project's developer mailing list
may leave new contributors wishing they had a decoder ring. Greg
Sabino Mullane has written up a valuable <a
href="https://www.crunchydata.com/blog/understanding-the-postgres-hackers-mailing-list">explainer</a>
for those new to the PostgreSQL hackers (<a
href="https://www.postgresql.org/list/pgsql-hackers/">pgsql-hackers</a>)
mailing list that may also be useful for decoding other lists as well:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>The mailing lists are full of acronyms and jargon that might not be
familiar to younger people who did not grow up on email (although text
messages have inherited many of the abbreviations). If you are a
non-native English speaker, or under the age of 30, or not steeped in
the world of tech, I offer some solutions below.</p>

<p>To do this, I downloaded the last year's worth of hackers email,
wrote a program to strip out all the non-human stuff (headers, code
blocks, attachments, etc.), and then did some data analysis on the
results.</p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987892/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 15:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>