<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 19:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 19:48:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Firefox version 132.0 is now available</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996216/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Mozilla has
<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/132.0/releasenotes/">announced</a> the release of a new version of Firefox. This version has the usual mix of 
<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/security/advisories/mfsa2024-55/">
security fixes</a> and new features, as well as a handful of deprecations. The release removes support for HTTP/2 Push, but adds hardware acceleration for SVGs, support for wide color gamuts on more platforms, and restores support for remote debugging via USB.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996216/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 17:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Fedora 41 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996214/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Fedora Linux 41 <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/announcing-fedora-linux-41/">has been
released</a>. See the "what's new" pages for <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/whats-new-fedora-workstation-41/">Fedora
Workstation</a> and <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/whats-new-in-fedora-kde-41/">Fedora
KDE</a>, to learn more about the latest in those editions. There is
also a new <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/spins/miraclewm">Fedora
Miracle Window Manager Spin</a> that offers the <a
href="https://miracle-wm.org/">Miracle</a> tiling window manager for
Wayland.</p>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996214/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 17:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996196/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (exim4) and <b>SUSE</b> (chromium, openssl-1_1, and openssl-3).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996196/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 13:27:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Flock: a Flutter fork</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996147/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[A project called Flock has <a
href="https://flutterfoundation.dev/blog/posts/we-are-forking-flutter-this-is-why/">announced
its existence</a>.  Flock is a fork of the Flutter user-interface toolkit
project, motivated by frustration with the resources that Google is putting
into Flutter.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	We describe Flock as "Flutter+". In other words, we do not want, or
	intend, to fork the Flutter community. Flock will remain constantly
	up to date with Flutter. Flock will add important bug fixes, and
	popular community features, which the Flutter team either can't, or
	won't implement.
</blockquote>
<p>
(LWN <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/828475/">looked at flutter</a> in 2020).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996147/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 03:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Coker: The CUPS vulnerability</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996108/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Debian Developer Russell Coker has <a
href="https://etbe.coker.com.au/2024/10/26/cups-vulnerability/">written
up</a> an analysis of the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/991929/">remote exploit of CUPS</a>
announced in September:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>He seems to have a different experience to me of reporting bugs, I
have had plenty of success getting bugs fixed without hyping them. I
just report the bug, wait a while, and it gets fixed. [...] I
was quite confident that my systems wouldn't be at any risk.</p>

<p>When it was published my opinion was proven to be correct, <a
href="https://www.securityweek.com/highly-anticipated-linux-flaw-allows-remote-code-execution-but-less-serious-than-expected/">it
turned out to be a series of CUPS bugs</a>.</p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996108/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 21:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Open Source Initiative announces Open Source AI Definition 1.0</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996104/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://opensource.org/">Open Source Initiative</a>
(OSI) has <a
href="https://opensource.org/blog/the-open-source-initiative-announces-the-release-of-the-industrys-first-open-source-ai-definition">announced</a>
the release of <a
href="https://opensource.org/ai/open-source-ai-definition">version
1.0</a> of the Open Source AI Definition:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
The OSAID offers a standard by which community-led, open and public
evaluations will be conducted to validate whether or not an AI system
can be deemed Open Source AI. This first stable version of the OSAID
is the result of multiple years of research and collaboration, an
international roadshow of workshops, and a year-long co-design process
led by the Open Source Initiative (OSI).
</blockquote>

<p>LWN <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/995159/">covered</a> the
OSAID process, and final release candidate, on October 25.</p>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996104/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 21:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/996085/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (kernel, python3.12, and python3.9), <b>Debian</b> (activemq, chromium, libheif, nss, and twisted), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, dnsdist, dotnet8.0, edk2, glibc, libdigidocpp, mbedtls3.6, NetworkManager-libreswan, oath-toolkit, podman-tui, prometheus-podman-exporter, python-fastapi, python-openapi-core, python-platformio, python-rpyc, python-starlette, rust-pyo3, rust-pyo3-build-config, rust-pyo3-ffi, rust-pyo3-macros, rust-pyo3-macros-backend, suricata, thunderbird, and yarnpkg), <b>Mageia</b> (cpanminus, libgsf, mozjs78, redis, and thunderbird), <b>Oracle</b> (firefox, python3.12, python3.9, and python39:3.9 and python39-devel:3.9), <b>Red Hat</b> (edk2, grafana, httpd, httpd:2.4, and mod_jk), and <b>SUSE</b> (nodejs-electron, python3, python310, and python39).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/996085/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 14:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.12-rc5</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/995981/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has released <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/995980/">6.12-rc5</a> for testing.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	rc5 looks perfectly normal, and maybe even on the small side of
	normal. The diffstat looks nice and flat too, with the exception of
	the removal of the da8xx fbdev driver due to it having been
	replaced by the tilcdc driver. And I'm sure we're all thinking the
	same thing: "What lovely descriptive driver names we have".
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/995981/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/995768/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (distro-info-data), <b>Fedora</b> (libtiff), <b>Mageia</b> (firefox and oath-toolkit), <b>Red Hat</b> (krb5), and <b>SUSE</b> (openssl-1_1).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/995768/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 13:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/995550/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (grafana, NetworkManager-libreswan, python3.11, and python39:3.9 and python39-devel:3.9), <b>Fedora</b> (dotnet6.0, koji, python-fastapi, python-openapi-core, python-platformio, python-starlette, rust-pyo3, rust-pyo3-build-config, rust-pyo3-ffi, rust-pyo3-macros, rust-pyo3-macros-backend, and yarnpkg), <b>Oracle</b> (grafana, kernel, linux-firmware, NetworkManager-libreswan, and python3.11), <b>Slackware</b> (php81), and <b>SUSE</b> (apache2, buildah, cups-filters, go1.21-openssl, podman, postgresql16, python-pyOpenSSL, and webkit2gtk3).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/995550/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 14:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for October 17, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993610/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for October 17, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993610/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 01:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Using LKMM atomics in Rust</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993785/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Rust, like C, has its own memory model describing how concurrent access to the
same data by multiple threads can behave.
The Linux kernel, however, has its own
ideas. The
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/718628/">
Linux kernel memory model</a> (LKMM) is subtly different from both the
standard C memory model and Rust's model.
At Kangrejos, Boqun Feng gave a presentation about the
need to reconcile the memory models used by Rust and the kernel,
including a few potential avenues for doing so. While
no consensus was reached, it is an area of active discussion.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993785/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 15:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Two pidfd tweaks: PIDFD_GET_INFO and PIDFD_SELF</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992991/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The pidfd mechanism, which uses file descriptors to refer to processes in
an unambiguous and race-free way, <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/773459/">was first
introduced</a> in 2018.  Since then, the interface has <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/794707/">gained a number of new features</a>, but 
development has slowed over time as the interface has matured.  There are,
however, a couple of patches in circulation that are meant to make working
with pidfds simpler in some situations.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992991/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 13:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Zapping pointers out of thin air</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993484/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Paul McKenney gave a presentation at Kangrejos this year that wasn't (directly)
related to Rust. Instead, he spoke about the work he has been doing in concert
with many other contributors on improving the handling of subtle concurrency
problems in C++.
Although he cautioned that his talk was only an overview, and not a
substitute for reading the relevant papers, he hoped that the things the C++
community is working on would be of interest to the Rust developers present as
well, and potentially inform future work on the language. McKenney's talk was,
as is his style, full of subtle examples of weird multithreaded behavior.
Interested readers may wish to refer to
<a href="https://kangrejos.com/2024/Lifetime-End%20Pointer%20Zap%20&amp;%20How%20to%20Avoid%20OOTA%20Without%20Really%20Trying.pdf">
his slides</a> in an attempt to follow along.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993484/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 13:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] WordPress retaliation impacts community</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993895/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>It is too early to say what the outcome will be in the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/991906/">ongoing fight</a> between <a
href="https://automattic.com/">Automattic</a> and <a
href="https://wpengine.com/">WP&nbsp;Engine</a>, but the <a
href="https://wordpress.org">WordPress</a> community at large is already the
loser. Automattic founder and CEO Matt Mullenweg has been using
his control of the project, and the WordPress.org infrastructure, to
punish WP&nbsp;Engine and remove some dissenting contributors from discussion
channels. Most recently, Mullenweg has instituted a hostile fork of a
WP&nbsp;Engine plugin and the forked plugin is replacing the original
via WordPress updates.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993895/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 18:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Debian&apos;s &quot;secret&quot; sauce</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990177/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[While Debian's "sauce" is not actually all that secret, it is not particularly
well-known either, Samuel Henrique said at the start of his <a
href="https://debconf24.debconf.org/">DebConf24</a> talk.  There is a lot
of software-engineering effort that has been put in place by the
distribution in order to create and maintain its releases, but "<q>loads of
people are not aware</q>" of it.  That may be due to the fact that all of
that is
not really documented anywhere in a central location that he can just point
someone to.  Recognizing that is what led him to give the talk;
hopefully it will be a "<q>first step toward</q>" helping solve the problem.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990177/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 16:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] FFI type mismatches in Rust for Linux</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993163/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
At Kangrejos, Gary Guo wanted to discuss three problems with the way
Rust and C code in the kernel interact: mismatched types, too many type casts,
and the overhead of helper functions. To fix the first two problems, Guo proposed
changing the way the kernel maps C types into Rust types. The last problem was a
bit trickier, but he has a clever workaround for that, based on tricking
the compiler into inlining the helper functions across language boundaries.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993163/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 13:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] On Rust in enterprise kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993337/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[At the recently concluded Maintainers Summit, it was <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/991062/">generally agreed that the Rust experiment would
continue</a>, and that the path was clear for more Rust code to enter the
kernel.  But the high-level view taken at such gatherings cannot always
account for the difficult details that will inevitably arise as the Rust
work proceeds.  A recent discussion on the nouveau mailing list may have
escaped the notice of many, but it highlights some of the problems that
will have to be worked out as important functionality written in Rust heads
toward the mainline.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993337/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 13:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tor Browser 14.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/995353/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://blog.torproject.org/new-release-tor-browser-140/">Version
14.0</a> of the privacy-focused <a
href="https://www.torproject.org/">Tor browser</a> has been released. 

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>This is our first stable release based on <a
href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/128.0esr/releasenotes/">Firefox
ESR 128</a>, incorporating a year's worth of changes shipped upstream
in Firefox. As part of this process we've also completed our annual
ESR transition audit, where we <a
href="https://gitlab.torproject.org/tpo/applications/tor-browser/-/issues/?sort=updated_desc&state=all&search=Review%20Mozilla&label_name%5B%5D=14.0%20stable&first_page_size=20">reviewed and addressed over 200 Bugzilla issues</a> for changes in Firefox that
may negatively affect the privacy and security of Tor Browser
users. Our final reports from this audit are now available in the <a
href="https://gitlab.torproject.org/tpo/applications/tor-browser-spec/-/tree/main/audits">tor-browser-spec
repository</a> on our Gitlab instance.</p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/995353/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 17:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kadlčík: Copr Modularity, the End of an Era</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/995337/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Jakub Kadlčík <a
href="https://frostyx.cz/posts/copr-modularity-the-end-of-an-era">announced
on his blog</a> that Fedora's <a
href="https://copr.fedorainfracloud.org/">Copr</a> build system will
be dropping support for building <a
href="https://docs.fedoraproject.org/en-US/modularity/core-concepts/module-stream/">modules</a>
(groups of RPM packages that are built, installed, and shipped
together) soon:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
The Fedora Modularity project never really took off, and building
modules in Copr even less so. We've had only 14 builds in the last two
years. It's not feasible to maintain the code for so few
users. Modularity has also been <a
href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Changes/RetireModularity">retired
since Fedora 39</a> and will die with RHEL 9.
</blockquote>

<p>Modularity features in Copr are now deprecated, and it will not be
possible to submit new module builds after April&nbsp;2025. LWN <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/805180/">covered</a> some of the
problems with Fedora's <a href="https://docs.pagure.org/modularity/">modularity initiative</a> in 2019.</p>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/995337/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 15:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/995293/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (dmitry, libheif, and python-sql), <b>Fedora</b> (suricata and wireshark), <b>SUSE</b> (cargo-c, libeverest, protobuf, and qemu), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (golang-1.22, libheif, unbound, and webkit2gtk).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/995293/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 13:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Several Russian developers lose kernel maintainership status</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/995186/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Perhaps one of the more surprising changes in the 6.12-rc4 development
kernel was <a href="https://git.kernel.org/linus/6e90b675cf94">the removal
of several entries</a> from the kernel's <tt>MAINTAINERS</tt> file.  The <a
href="https://lore.kernel.org/all/2024101835-tiptop-blip-09ed@gregkh/">patch</a>
performing the removal was sent (by Greg Kroah-Hartman) only to the
patches@lists.linux.dev mailing list; the change was included in <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-kernel/ZxUH2J0BL3FCV6Hr@kroah.com/">a char-misc drivers
pull request</a> with no particular mention.
<p>
The explanation for the removal is simply "<q>various compliance
requirements</q>".  Given that the developers involved all appear to be of
Russian origin, it is not too hard to imagine what sort of compliance is
involved here.  There has, however, been no public posting of the policy
that required the removal of these entries.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/995186/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 22:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>