<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 18:41:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 9 Oct 2024 19:09:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Julia v1.11.0 has been released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993436/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The Julia project has
<a href="https://discourse.julialang.org/t/julia-v1-11-0-has-been-released-and-v1-10-is-now-lts/121064">
released</a> version 1.11.0. A separate
<a href="https://julialang.org/blog/2024/10/julia-1.11-highlights/">
blog post</a> covers some of the highlights. The release includes a number of helpful features.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
In previous Julia versions, there was no "programmatic way" of knowing if an unexported name was considered part of the public API or not. Instead, the guideline was basically that if it was not in the manual then it was not public which was a bit underwhelming. To remedy that, there is now a <tt>public</tt> keyword in Julia that can be used to indicate that an unexported name is part of the public API.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993436/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 14:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993433/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (firefox, mod_jk, and thunderbird), <b>Debian</b> (apache2 and firefox-esr), <b>Fedora</b> (crosswords, logiops, p7zip, and perl-App-cpanminus), <b>Red Hat</b> (.NET 6.0, firefox, git, kernel, kernel-rt, openssl, and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (buildah, json-lib, kernel, Mesa, mozjs78, pgadmin4, podman, podofo, qatlib, redis7, roundcubemail, rusty_v8, and seamonkey), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (dotnet6, dotnet8, nginx, and ruby-webrick).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993433/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 13:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993276/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (kernel), <b>Fedora</b> (webkitgtk), <b>Mageia</b> (cups), <b>Oracle</b> (e2fsprogs, kernel, and kernel-container), <b>Red Hat</b> (buildah, container-tools:rhel8, containernetworking-plugins, git-lfs, go-toolset:rhel8, golang, grafana-pcp, podman, and skopeo), <b>SUSE</b> (Mesa, mozjs115, podofo, and redis7), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (cups and cups-filters).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993276/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 13:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>OpenBSD 7.6 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993203/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>OpenBSD&nbsp;7.6 has been <a
href="https://www.openbsd.org/76.html">released</a>. Notable new
features include work to improve suspend/resume on modern hardware,
support for the arm64 Qualcomm Snapdragon X Elite laptops, as well as many
improvements in hardware support and driver bug fixes.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
With this release all files that existed in the first commit
in the OpenBSD source repository have been updated,
modified or replaced at some point in time, reaching OpenBSD of Theseus.
</blockquote>

<p>See the <a href="https://www.openbsd.org/plus76.html">changelog</a>
for all changes between OpenBSD&nbsp;7.5 and 7.6.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993203/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 21:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Python 3.13 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993191/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Version 3.13 of the <a href="https://www.python.org/">Python</a> programming language has been <a
href="https://www.python.org/downloads/release/python-3130/">released</a>. The
"<a href="https://docs.python.org/3.13/whatsnew/3.13.html">What's New
In Python 3.13</a>" page has a summary of all the new features and
changes. Highlights of the release include <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/977855/">a basic JIT compiler</a>,
experimental support for <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/985041/">free-threading</a>, and much
more. See the <a
href="https://docs.python.org/3.13/whatsnew/changelog.html">changelog</a>
for even more details.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993191/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 17:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Git 2.47.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993180/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/xmqqa5fg9bsz.fsf@gitster.g">Version 2.47.0</a> of the Git
source-code management system has been released.  The changes include a
long list of incremental improvements; see the announcement and <a
href="https://github.blog/open-source/git/highlights-from-git-2-47/">this
GitHub blog post</a> for details.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993180/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 16:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>RPM 4.20 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993161/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://rpm.org/wiki/Releases/4.20.0">Version 4.20</a> of
the RPM Package Manager (RPM) has been released. Major changes in this
release include a new plugin to prevent filesystem and network access
by scriptlets, the <tt>BuildSystem</tt> directive for declaring the
build system to be used by packaged software, and more. LWN <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/988927/">covered</a> the development of
RPM 4.20 in September.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993161/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 14:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993160/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (go-toolset:rhel8 and linux-firmware), <b>Arch Linux</b> (oath-toolkit), <b>Debian</b> (e2fsprogs, firefox-esr, libgsf, mediawiki, and oath-toolkit), <b>Fedora</b> (aws, chromium, firefox, p7zip, pgadmin4, python-gcsfs, unbound, webkitgtk, znc, znc-clientbuffer, and znc-push), <b>Mageia</b> (ghostscript and rootcerts nss firefox firefox-l10n), <b>Oracle</b> (kernel, oVirt 4.4 ovirt-engine, and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (chromedriver, chromium, cups-filters, ffmpeg-7, frr, Mesa, openssl-3, openvpn, pcp, and redis), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (firefox and ruby-webrick).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993160/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 14:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.12-rc2</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993107/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has released <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/993106/">6.12-rc2</a> for testing.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Anyway, this isn't one of the small rc2's. But looking at
	historical trends, being a bigger rc2 isn't _that_ unusual, and
	nothing in here looks all that odd. Yes, the diffstat may look a
	bit unusual, in that we had a global header renaming
	(asm/unaligned.h -&gt; linux/unaligned.h) and we had a couple of
	reverts that stand out as spikes in the stats, but everything else
	looks nice and small.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993107/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 12:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Akamai finds many systems with exposed CUPS vulnerability</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/993044/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Akamai
<a href="https://www.akamai.com/blog/security-research/october-cups-ddos-threat">
released a report</a> pointing out that the
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/991929/">
recently-reported CUPS vulnerability</a>
(<a href="https://www.evilsocket.net/2024/09/26/Attacking-UNIX-systems-via-CUPS-Part-I/">original disclosure</a>)
could be used to drive distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks as well. Even if an attacker cannot gain remote control over a computer, they can still cause it to fetch a URL of their choice — potentially getting free DDoS amplification.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
The Akamai Security Intelligence and Response Team (SIRT) found that more than 198,000 devices are vulnerable to this attack vector and are accessible on the public internet; roughly 34% of those could be used for DDoS abuse (58,000+).
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/993044/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 21:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Three Friday kernel updates</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992977/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/992978/">6.11.2</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/992979/">6.10.13</a>,
and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/992980/">6.6.54</a> stable kernels have been released.
They contain important fixes, and upgrading is, as always, recommended.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992977/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 15:39:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>oath-toolkit: privilege escalation in pam_oath.so (SUSE Security Team Blog)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992948/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The SUSE Security Team Blog has a <a
href="https://security.opensuse.org/2024/10/04/oath-toolkit-vulnerability.html">detailed
report</a> on its discovery of <a href="https://www.nongnu.org/oath-toolkit/security/CVE-2024-47191/">a privilege escalation</a> in the
<a
href="https://gitlab.com/oath-toolkit/oath-toolkit">oath-toolkit</a>,
which provides libraries and utilities for managing one-time password
(OTP) authentication.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Fellow SUSE engineer Fabian Vogt approached our Security Team about
the project's PAM module. A couple of years ago, the module gained a
feature which allows to place the OTP state file (called usersfile) in
the home directory of the to-be-authenticated user. Fabian noticed
that the PAM module performs unsafe file operations in users' home
directories. Since PAM stacks typically run as root, this can easily
cause security issues.
</blockquote>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992948/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 15:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992936/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (firefox, golang, linux-firmware, and thunderbird), <b>Debian</b> (kernel and zabbix), <b>Fedora</b> (firefox, pgadmin4, and php), <b>Mageia</b> (chromium-browser-stable, cjson, hostapd and wpa_supplicant, and openjpeg2), <b>Oracle</b> (firefox, flatpak, and go-toolset:ol8), <b>Red Hat</b> (cups-filters, firefox, grafana, linux-firmware, python3, python3.11, and python3.9), <b>SUSE</b> (expat, firefox, libpcap, and opensc), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (freeradius, imagemagick, and unzip).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992936/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 13:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/992798/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (cups-filters), <b>Debian</b> (chromium and php8.2), <b>Fedora</b> (firefox), <b>Oracle</b> (cups-filters, flatpak, kernel, krb5, oVirt 4.5 ovirt-engine, and python-urllib3), <b>Red Hat</b> (cups-filters, firefox, go-toolset:rhel8, golang, and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (postgresql16), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (gnome-shell and linux-azure-fde-5.15).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/992798/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 12:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for September 26, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990791/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for September 26, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990791/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 01:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] What the Nova GPU driver needs</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990736/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
In March, Danilo Krummrich <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/966129">announced</a> the new
Nova GPU driver — a successor to Noveau for controlling NVIDIA GPUs.
At Kangrejos 2024, Krummrich gave a
presentation about what it is, why it's needed, and where it's
going next. Hearing about the needs of the driver provoked extended discussion
on related topics, including what level of safety is reasonable to expect from
drivers, given that they must interact with the hardware.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990736/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 15:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Linus and Dirk on succession, Rust, and more</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990534/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The "Linus and Dirk show" has been a fixture at Open Source Summit for as
long as the conference has existed; it started back when the conference was
called LinuxCon.  Since Linus Torvalds famously does not like to give
talks, as he said during this year's edition at <a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/open-source-summit-europe/">Open Source Summit Europe</a>
(OSSEU) in Vienna, Austria, he and Dirk Hohndel have been sitting down for an
informal chat on a wide range of topics as a keynote session.  That way,
Torvalds does not need to prepare, but also does not know what topics
will be brought up, which makes it "so much more fun for one of us", Hohndel
said with a grin.   The topics this time ranged from the just-released&nbsp;6.11
kernel and the upcoming Linux&nbsp;6.12, through Rust for the kernel, to the recurring topic of succession and
the graying of Linux maintainers.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990534/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 13:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] KDE sets its goals through 2026</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990604/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Almost a decade ago <a href="https://ev.kde.org/">KDE&nbsp;e.V.</a>,
the non-profit organization that supports <a
href="http://kde.org/">KDE</a>, started a <a href="https://community.kde.org/Goals/Goals_Process">process</a> for
selecting <a href="https://kde.org/goals/">goals</a> to help the community unite behind a common vision for where the
project should go in the near future. KDE
recently wrapped up its 2022-2024 <a
href="https://community.kde.org/Goals">cycle</a> and announced the goals for 2024-2026 at <a
href="https://akademy.kde.org/2024/">Akademy</a> on September&nbsp;7, in Würzburg,
Germany. This time around, KDE will be looking to streamline its
application-development experience, improve support for input devices,
and bring in new contributors.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990604/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 15:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Committing to Rust in the kernel</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991062/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The project to enable the writing of kernel code in Rust has been underway
for several years, and each kernel release includes more Rust code.  Even
so, some developers have expressed frustration at the time it takes to get
new functionality merged, and an air of uncertainty still hangs over
the project.  At the 2024 Maintainers Summit, Miguel Ojeda led a discussion
on the status of Rust in the kernel and whether the time had come to stop
considering it an experimental project.  There were not answers to all of the
questions, but it seems clear that Rust in the kernel will continue
steaming ahead.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991062/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 11:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Resources for learning Rust for kernel development</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990619/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Dirk Behme led a second session, back-to-back with
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/990489/">his session on error handling</a> at
Kangrejos 2024, discussing providing better guidance for users of the kernel's
Rust abstractions. Just after that,
Carlos Bilbao and Miguel Ojeda had their own time slot dedicated to collecting
resources that could be of use to someone trying to come up to speed
on kernel development in
Rust. The attendees provided a lot of guidance in both sessions, and
discussed what they could do to make things easier for people coming
from non-Rust backgrounds.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990619/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 15:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Tools for kernel developers</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/991033/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Konstantin Ryabitsev started a session on development tooling at the 2024
Maintainers Summit by saying that he does not want to be a "wrecking ball".
If a given workflow is working for people, he does not want to try to force
any sort of change.  That said, he has ideas for how he can continue his
work on providing better tooling for the development community.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/991033/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 11:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The 6.12 merge window begins</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990750/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[As of this writing, 6,778 non-merge changesets have been pulled into the
mainline kernel for the 6.12 release — over half of the work that had been
staged in linux-next prior to the opening of the merge window.  There has
been a lot of refactoring and cleanup work this time around, but also some
significant changes.  Read on for a summary of the first half of the 6.12
merge window.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990750/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 14:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Considering kernel pass-through interfaces</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990802/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The kernel normally sits firmly between user space and the system's
peripheral devices, and provides a standard interface to those devices.  At
times, though, a more direct interface to a device is desired — but such
interfaces can be controversial.  At the 2024 Maintainers Summit, the
assembled developers considered a specific case — the proposed <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/969383/">fwctl subsystem</a> — as well as the role of such
drivers in general.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990802/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 12:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Best practices for error handling in kernel Rust</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990489/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Dirk Behme led a session discussing the use of Rust's question-mark operator in
the kernel at Kangrejos 2024. He was particularly concerned with the concept of
"silent" errors that don't print any messages to the console.
Other attendees were less convinced that this was a problem, but his presentation
sparked a lot of discussion about whether the Rust-for-Linux project could
improve error handling in kernel Rust code.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990489/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 15:54:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] RPM 4.20 is coming</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/988927/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://rpm.org/">RPM Package Manager</a> (RPM) project is
nearing the release of RPM&nbsp;4.20, the last major planned update for the RPM 4.x
series. It has few user-facing changes, but
several additions and enhancements for developers&mdash;as well as
some small incompatibilities that will likely require RPM packagers to
revise their <a
href="https://rpm-packaging-guide.github.io/#what-is-a-spec-file">spec
files</a>. 4.20 will be rolling out to many users soon, in
Fedora&nbsp;41, which is scheduled for October. RPM&nbsp;6.0 is
already in the works, with a new package format and opening the door
to enabling C++ use in the RPM codebase.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/988927/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 13:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The uncertain future of kernel regression tracking</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/990599/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Tracking of regressions seems like an important task for any project; there
is no other way to ensure that known problems are fixed.  At the 2024
Maintainers Summit, though, Thorsten Leemhuis, who has been doing that work
for the kernel, expressed some doubts about whether it is worth continuing.
The result was an energetic session on how regression tracking should be
done better, and how this work should be supported.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/990599/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 06:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>