<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 21:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 9 Jan 2025 22:10:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Rust 1.84.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004614/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2025/01/09/Rust-1.84.0.html">Version
1.84.0</a> of the Rust language has been released.  Changes include
improved version selection for dependencies in Cargo, the beginning of the
migration to a new trait solver, and some updated pointer-provenance APIs.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Most of the time, programmers do not need to worry much about
	provenance, and it is very clear how a pointer got
	derived. However, when casting pointers to integers and back, the
	provenance of the resulting pointer is underspecified. With this
	release, Rust is adding a set of APIs that can in many cases
	replace the use of integer-pointer-casts, and therefore avoid the
	ambiguities inherent to such casts. In particular, the pattern of
	using the lowest bits of an aligned pointer to store extra
	information can now be implemented without ever casting a pointer
	to an integer or back. This makes the code easier to reason about,
	easier to analyze for the compiler, and also benefits tools like
	Miri and architectures like CHERI that aim to detect and diagnose
	pointer misuse.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004614/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 18:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>SFC reports a successful (L)GPL suit in Germany</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004595/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Software Freedom Conservancy is <a
href="https://sfconservancy.org/news/2025/jan/09/avm-copyleft-lawsuit-resolved-with-install/">reporting</a>
that AVM has released the full source and installation scripts for its
routers in response to a lawsuit, filed by Sebastian Steck, based on Lesser
GNU Public License rights.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Historically, lawsuits have focused on the copyrights licensed
	under GPL (or the GPL and LGPL together). Steck's lawsuit uniquely
	focused exclusively on users' rights under the LGPL. Steck's work
	showed that despite being a "Lesser" license than GPL, LGPLv2.1
	still guarantees users the right to repair, modify and reinstall
	modified versions of the software on their device. There is now no
	doubt that both GPL and LGPL mandate the device owner's ability to
	make changes to the software in the flash memory so those changes
	persist across reboots.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004595/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 15:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Six new stable kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004548/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1004549/">6.12.9</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1004551/">6.6.70</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1004552/">6.1.124</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1004553/">5.15.176</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1004555/">5.10.233</a>, and <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1004557/">5.4.289</a> stable kernels have been released.
As usual, they contain important fixes all over the kernel tree.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004548/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 15:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004543/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (cups, kernel, and kernel-rt), <b>Debian</b> (chromium, firefox-esr, and webkit2gtk), <b>Fedora</b> (curl, firefox, gimp, mupdf, openjpeg2, and valkey), <b>Red Hat</b> (389-ds-base, cups, firefox, iperf3, kernel, kernel-rt, libreswan, python3.11-urllib3, thunderbird, and webkit2gtk3), <b>Slackware</b> (firefox, seamonkey, and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (apptainer, firefox-esr, libopenjp2-7, libruby3_4-3_4, openjpeg2, and tomcat10), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (firefox, linux-azure, linux-azure, linux-azure-4.15, linux-azure, linux-azure-6.8, linux-azure, linux-intel-iotg-5.15, linux-azure-5.15, python2.7, thunderbird, and xfpt).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004543/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 14:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for December 26, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002827/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for December 26, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002827/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 01:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A 2024 retrospective</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002368/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[It is often said that the definition of insanity is repeating the same
action and expecting different results.  Be that as it may, LWN has
repeatedly started a new year with a set of predictions, only to have to
review how badly they went at the end.  There was no break in that pattern
this year, so there is no help for it; the time has come to review 
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/954544/">our 2024 predictions</a> in the hope that they
came out better this time around.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002368/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 17:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Systemd takes steps toward a more secure boot process</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1001730/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The systemd project has been working for some time on
<a href="https://0pointer.net/blog/brave-new-trusted-boot-world.html">
promoting</a>
<a href="https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/unified_kernel_image/">
unified kernel
images</a> (UKIs), a format that bundles a kernel, initial disk image, kernel command line, and
other associated data into a single file. The advantage of the format is the ability to
authenticate the entire collection with secure boot, which makes it easier for
end users to know that their operating system hasn't been tampered with. The
downside is the lack of flexibility and increase in disk usage, since all of the
things packaged in a UKI must be updated together. But the
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1001657/">
recent systemd 257 release</a> (along with other changes to be covered in a
future article) includes some
major changes to the UKI format, and the rest of the boot process, that
partially mitigate those downsides. The release also includes improvements for
hardware-locked disk encryption, which may also help secure some computers.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1001730/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 14:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Systemd improves image features and adds varlink API</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002398/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1001657/">systemd v257</a> release brings a number of incremental
enhancements to various components and utilities for working with
Linux systems. This includes more support for <a href="https://varlink.org/">varlink</a>, automated
downloading of disk images at boot time, and a number of improvements
to the secure-boot process for unified kernel images (UKIs), which we
have covered in <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1001730/">a separate
article</a>.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002398/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 15:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Tim Peters returns to the Python community</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002340/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In the past, suspensions of Python core developers have effectively been
permanent because the recipients of the punishment chose not to return.
Things have played out quite differently after Tim Peters was <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/988894/">suspended for three months</a> back in August;
Peters has been posting to the Python discussion forum since his suspension
ended in early November and, generally, getting back to work as usual.
That does not mean that he—or others in the community—have accepted the way
he was treated, but he has largely made his peace with it.  The incident is
still reverberating through the Python world, however.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002340/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Process creation in io_uring</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002371/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Back in 2022, Josh Triplett <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/908268/">presented a
plan</a> to implement a "spawn new process" functionality in the io_uring
subsystem.  There was a fair amount of interest at the time, but developers
got distracted, and the work did not progress.  Now, Gabriel Krisman
Bertazi has returned with <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20241209234316.4132786-1-krisman@suse.de">a patch series</a>
updating and improving Triplett's work.  While interest in this
functionality remains, it may still take some time before it is ready for
merging into the mainline.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002371/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] FESCo provenpackager sanction causes problems</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002450/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Fedora Engineering Steering Council (FESCo) has made a series of
missteps in deciding to revoke a longtime Fedora contributor's <a
href="https://docs.fedoraproject.org/en-US/fesco/Provenpackager_policy/">provenpackager</a>
status. FESCo made the decision during a closed session, based on private
complaints. It then publicly announced its decision, including the
contributor's name, while only supplying a vague account of the
contributor's actions. This has left the Fedora community with more
questions than answers, and raised a number of complaints about the
transparency of FESCo's process. In addition, the sequence of events has
sparked discussions about package ownership, as well as when and how it's
appropriate to push changes to packages that a developer doesn't own.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002450/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 15:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2024: Year in Review (Tor Blog)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004460/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.torproject.org/">Tor Project</a> has <a
href="https://blog.torproject.org/2024-year-in-review/">published a
review</a> of major milestones from 2024, including <a
href="https://blog.torproject.org/tor-tails-join-forces/">merging with
the Tails project</a>, work to enable human-friendly <tt>.onion</tt>
addresses, and the launch of <a
href="https://blog.torproject.org/introducing-webtunnel-evading-censorship-by-hiding-in-plain-sight/">WebTunnel</a>:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
By mimicking common internet protocols, WebTunnel improves the
resilience of the Tor network in regions with heavy censorship. And
since its launch earlier this year, we've made sure to prioritize
small download sizes for more convenient distribution and simplified
the support of uTLS integration further mimicking the characteristics
of more widespread browsers. This makes Webtunnel safe for general
users because it helps conceal the fact that a tool like Tor is being
used.
</blockquote>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004460/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 18:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Announcing the pkgsrc-2024Q4 branch</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004429/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://pkgsrc.org/">pkgsrc</a> developers have
announced the 2024Q4 branch of the pkgsrc cross-platform
packaging system. It is the default package manager for <a
href="https://www.netbsd.org/">NetBSD</a>, <a
href="https://wiki.smartos.org/">SmartOS</a>, and is <a
href="https://pkgsrc.smartos.org/install-on-linux/">available for
Linux</a> as well. This marks the 85th quarterly release of pkgsrc:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Since the pkgsrc-2024Q3 release, 110 packages were added, 1580 packages
were updated (with 2399 updates, including language-specific updates:
24 Go, 3 OCaml, 66 Perl, 5 PHP, 626 Python, 282 Ruby, 44 TeX).  33
packages were removed.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004429/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004428/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (firefox, mupdf, and php-tcpdf), <b>SUSE</b> (etcd, file-roller, gtk3, kernel, python-django-ckeditor, rubygem-json-jwt, and tomcat10), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (ffmpeg, HTMLDOC, linux-aws, linux-raspi, linux-gke, linux-hwe-6.8, linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-6.8, and tinyproxy).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004428/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:21:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kicinski: netdev in 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004376/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Kernel networking maintainer Jakub Kicinski <a
href="https://people.kernel.org/kuba/netdev-in-2024">reviews progress in
the networking subsystem</a> in 2024.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Work on relieving the rtnl_lock pressure has continued throughout
	the year. The rtnl_lock is often mentioned as one of the biggest
	global locks in the kernel, as it protects all of the network
	configuration and state. The efforts can be divided into two broad
	categories – converting read operations to rely on RCU protection
	or other fine grained locking (v6.9, v6.10), and splitting the lock
	into per-network namespace locks (preparations for which started in
	v6.13).
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004376/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 21:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2024 in retrospect (Gentoo News)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004373/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Gentoo Linux has published a <a
href="https://www.gentoo.org/news/2025/01/05/new-year.html">project
retrospective</a> that looks at the major improvements and news from
2024, the Gentoo Foundation's finances, and contributions to Gentoo by
the numbers.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>The number of commits to the <a
href="https://gitweb.gentoo.org/repo/gentoo.git/">main ::gentoo
repository</a> has remained at an overall high level in 2024, with a
2.4% increase from 121000 to 123942. The number of commits by external
contributors has grown strongly from 10708 to 12812, now across 421
unique external authors.</p>

<p>The importance of <a
href="https://wiki.gentoo.org/wiki/Project:GURU">GURU, our
user-curated repository with a trusted user model</a>, as entry point
for potential developers, is clearly increasing as well. We have had
7517 commits in 2024, a strong growth from 5045 in 2023. The number of
contributors to GURU has increased a lot as well, from 158 in 2023 to
241 in 2024. Please join us there and help packaging the latest and
greatest software.</p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004373/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 19:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Firefox 134.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004368/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/134.0/releasenotes/">Version 134.0</a> of the Firefox browser has been released. Changes include support for touchpad hold gestures on Linux, a refreshed layout for the New Tab page for users in the US and Canada, and improved support for debugging web extensions.</p>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004368/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:46:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003856/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (debootstrap) and <b>SUSE</b> (assimp-devel, grpc, libQt6Pdf6, and poppler).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003856/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>LineageOS 22.1 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003862/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://lineageos.org/Changelog-29/">Version 22.1</a> of the
Android-based LineageOS distribution is out.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	We've been hard at work since Android 15's release in September,
	adapting our unique features to this new version of
	Android. Android 15 introduced several complex changes under the
	hood, but due to our previous efforts adapting to Google's
	UI-centric adjustments in Android 12 through 14, we were able to
	rebase onto Android 15's code-base faster than anticipated.
<p>
	Additionally, this is far-and-away the easiest bringup cycle from a
	device perspective we have seen in years. This means that many more
	devices are ready on day one that we'd typically expect to have up
	this early in the cycle!
<p>
	Last, but not least, we even had enough time and resources to
	introduce not one, but two new exciting apps! The first one,
	Twelve, will replace our aging music app, while the other one,
	Camelot, will let you view PDF files.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003862/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004339/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (python-requests), <b>Oracle</b> (python-requests), <b>SUSE</b> (python-Jinja2 and rizin), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (ceph, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-hwe, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-4.15, linux-hwe,
 linux-kvm, linux-oracle, linux, linux-lts-xenial, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.15, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.15, linux-hwe-5.15,
 linux-nvidia, linux-oracle, linux-raspi, linux-aws, linux-kvm, linux-hwe-6.8, linux-intel-iotg, linux-oem-6.11, linux-raspi-5.4, and salt).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004339/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Cook: Colliding with the SHA prefix of Linux&apos;s initial Git commit</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003797/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Kees Cook <a
href="https://people.kernel.org/kees/colliding-with-the-sha-prefix-of-linuxs-initial-git-commit">describes
his work</a> resulting in a kernel documentation commit whose ID shares the
same first 12 characters as the initial commit in the kernel's repository.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	This is not yet in the upstream Linux tree, for fear of breaking
	countless other tools out in the wild. But it can serve as a test
	commit for those that want to get this fixed ahead of any future
	collisions (or this commit actually landing).
</blockquote>
<p>
LWN <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1001526/">looked at commit-ID collisions</a> a few
weeks back.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003797/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 20:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mourning Steve Langasek</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004297/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[From the Ubuntu Discourse instance comes <a
href="https://discourse.ubuntu.com/t/remembering-and-thanking-steve-langasek/52665">the
sad news</a> that longtime Debian and Ubuntu contributor Steve Langasek has
passed away.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Steve passed away at the dawn of 2025. His time was short but
	remarkable. He will forever remain an inspiration. Judging by the
	outpouring of feelings this week, he is equally missed and mourned
	by colleagues and friends across the open source landscape, in
	particular in Ubuntu and Debian where he was a great mind, mentor
	and conscience.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004297/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 19:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003768/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (gst-plugins-good1.0 and opensc), <b>Fedora</b> (iwd and libell), and <b>SUSE</b> (chromium, govulncheck-vulndb, and poppler).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003768/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 14:55:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004262/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (ofono and webkitgtk), <b>Mageia</b> (ruby and virtualbox &amp; kmod-virtualbox), <b>Red Hat</b> (oci-seccomp-bpf-hook and runc), <b>SUSE</b> (corepack22, dpdk, libpoppler-cpp1, pcp, python-Jinja2, and sysstat), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (tinyproxy).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004262/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.13-rc6</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004230/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has released <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1004229/">6.13-rc6</a> for testing.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	So we had a slight pickup in commits this last week, but as
	expected and hoped for, things were still pretty quiet. About twice
	as many commits as the holiday week, but that's still not all that
	many.
<p>
	I expect things will start becoming more normal now that people are
	back from the holidays and are starting to recover and wake up from
	their food comas.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004230/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 23:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.13-rc5</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003730/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1003729/">6.13-rc5</a> kernel prepatch is out for
testing.  Linus says: "<q>It's been another week, but I'm happy to report
that clearly most people actually seem to have been enjoying the holidays,
because rc5 is tiny</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003730/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 21:35:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003601/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (node-postcss), <b>Fedora</b> (age, dr_libs, incus, libxml2, moodle, and python-sql), and <b>SUSE</b> (poppler and python-grpcio).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003601/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Three stable kernel updates</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003607/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Greg Kroah-Hartman has posted three new stable kernel updates:
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1003608/">6.12.7</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1003609/">6.6.68</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1003610/">6.1.122</a>. As usual, he warns that all users of
stable kernels must upgrade, although for many systems that seems unlikely to
happen until January.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003607/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004067/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (linux-6.1), <b>Fedora</b> (iwd and libell), <b>Red Hat</b> (python-requests), and <b>SUSE</b> (velero).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1004067/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>LineageOS 22.1 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003862/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://lineageos.org/Changelog-29/">Version 22.1</a> of the
Android-based LineageOS distribution is out.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	We've been hard at work since Android 15's release in September,
	adapting our unique features to this new version of
	Android. Android 15 introduced several complex changes under the
	hood, but due to our previous efforts adapting to Google's
	UI-centric adjustments in Android 12 through 14, we were able to
	rebase onto Android 15's code-base faster than anticipated.
<p>
	Additionally, this is far-and-away the easiest bringup cycle from a
	device perspective we have seen in years. This means that many more
	devices are ready on day one that we'd typically expect to have up
	this early in the cycle!
<p>
	Last, but not least, we even had enough time and resources to
	introduce not one, but two new exciting apps! The first one,
	Twelve, will replace our aging music app, while the other one,
	Camelot, will let you view PDF files.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003862/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003856/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (debootstrap) and <b>SUSE</b> (assimp-devel, grpc, libQt6Pdf6, and poppler).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003856/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Cook: Colliding with the SHA prefix of Linux&apos;s initial Git commit</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003797/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Kees Cook <a
href="https://people.kernel.org/kees/colliding-with-the-sha-prefix-of-linuxs-initial-git-commit">describes
his work</a> resulting in a kernel documentation commit whose ID shares the
same first 12 characters as the initial commit in the kernel's repository.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	This is not yet in the upstream Linux tree, for fear of breaking
	countless other tools out in the wild. But it can serve as a test
	commit for those that want to get this fixed ahead of any future
	collisions (or this commit actually landing).
</blockquote>
<p>
LWN <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1001526/">looked at commit-ID collisions</a> a few
weeks back.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003797/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 20:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003768/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (gst-plugins-good1.0 and opensc), <b>Fedora</b> (iwd and libell), and <b>SUSE</b> (chromium, govulncheck-vulndb, and poppler).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003768/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 14:55:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.13-rc5</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003730/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1003729/">6.13-rc5</a> kernel prepatch is out for
testing.  Linus says: "<q>It's been another week, but I'm happy to report
that clearly most people actually seem to have been enjoying the holidays,
because rc5 is tiny</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003730/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 21:35:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003601/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (node-postcss), <b>Fedora</b> (age, dr_libs, incus, libxml2, moodle, and python-sql), and <b>SUSE</b> (poppler and python-grpcio).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003601/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Three stable kernel updates</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003607/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Greg Kroah-Hartman has posted three new stable kernel updates:
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1003608/">6.12.7</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1003609/">6.6.68</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1003610/">6.1.122</a>. As usual, he warns that all users of
stable kernels must upgrade, although for many systems that seems unlikely to
happen until January.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003607/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>