<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 23:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 23:48:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Eight new kernel updates</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974064/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/974068/">6.9.1</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/974070/">6.8.10</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/974072/">6.6.31</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/974074/">6.1.91</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/974075/">5.15.159</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/974076/">5.10.217</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/974078/">5.4.276</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/974079/">4.19.314</a> stable kernels have been released.
These versions include several important fixes; as usual, Greg Kroah-Hartman advises
users to update right away.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974064/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 14:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974055/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, firefox, and podman), <b>Mageia</b> (chromium-browser-stable, ghostscript, and java-1.8.0, java-11, java-17, java-latest), <b>Red Hat</b> (bind, Firefox, firefox, gnutls, httpd:2.4, and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (glibc, opera, and python-Pillow), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (dotnet7, dotnet8, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.4, linux-azure, linux-azure-5.4,
 linux-bluefield, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.4, linux-gkeop, linux-hwe-5.4,
 linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.4, linux-iot, linux-kvm, linux-oracle,
 linux-oracle-5.4, linux-raspi, linux-raspi-5.4, linux-xilinx-zynqmp, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-6.5, linux-azure, linux-azure-6.5, linux-gcp,
 linux-gcp-6.5, linux-hwe-6.5, linux-laptop, linux-lowlatency,
 linux-lowlatency-hwe-6.5, linux-nvidia-6.5, linux-oem-6.5, linux-oracle,
 linux-oracle-6.5, linux-raspi, linux-signed, linux-signed-aws,
 linux-signed-aws-6.5, linux-starfive, linux-starfive-6.5, linux, linux-aws, linux-azure-4.15, linux-gcp-4.15, linux-hwe, linux-kvm,
 linux-oracle, linux, linux-aws, linux-kvm, linux-lts-xenial, and linux, linux-azure, linux-azure-5.15, linux-azure-fde,
 linux-azure-fde-5.15, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.15, linux-gkeop,
 linux-gkeop-5.15, linux-hwe-5.15, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.15,
 linux-intel-iotg, linux-kvm, linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-5.15,
 linux-nvidia, linux-oracle, linux-raspi).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974055/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 13:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>White paper: Vendor Kernels, Bugs and Stability</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973996/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Ronnie Sahlberg, Jonathan Maple, and Jeremy Allison of CiQ have published
<a href="https://ciq.com/whitepaper/vendor-kernels-bugs-stability/">a white
paper</a> looking at the security-relevant bug fixes applied (or <i>not</i>
applied) to the RHEL&nbsp;8.x kernel over time.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	This means that over time, the security of the RHEL kernels get
	worse and worse as more issues are discovered in the upstream code
	and are potentially exploitable but fewer and fewer of the fixes
	for these known bugs are back-ported into RHEL kernels.
<P>
	After reaching RHEL 8.7, the theory is that the kernel has been
	stabilized, with a corresponding improvement in security. However
	we still have an influx of newly discovered bugs in the upstream
	kernel affecting RHEL 8.7 that are not addressed. Each minor
	version of upstream is released on an approximately quarterly basis
	and we can see that the influx of new bugs that are unaddressed in
	RHEL is growing. The number of known issues in these kernels
	increases by approximately 250 new bugs per quarter or more.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973996/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 13:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Neovim 0.10 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973917/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://neovim.io/doc/user/news-0.10.html">Version
0.10</a> of the Vim-based text editor <a
href="https://neovim.io/">Neovim</a> is <a
href="https://neovim.io/news/2024/05">now available</a>. This release
includes a new default color scheme, enhanced support for rendering
multibyte characters, support for hyperlinks, system clipboard
synchronization, and more. Many features have been <a
href="https://neovim.io/doc/user/deprecated.html#deprecated-0.10">deprecated</a>
in 0.10 and will be removed in future release. Neovim core contributor
Gregory Anders has written a <a
href="https://gpanders.com/blog/whats-new-in-neovim-0.10/">summary</a>
of some of the highlights and thoughts on upcoming releases:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
 We follow a "fun driven development" paradigm: for the most part,
 contributors and maintainers work on things that are personally
 interesting to them. Because of this, it can be difficult to predict
 what will happen in future releases. If there is a feature you want
 to see implemented, the best way to do it is to take a crack at it
 yourself: many of the features mentioned in this very blog post were
 contributed by users that are not part of the "core" maintenance
 team!
 </blockquote>

<p> </p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973917/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 16:03:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973908/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (.NET 7.0, .NET 8.0, and nodejs:20), <b>Debian</b> (chromium, firefox-esr, ghostscript, and libreoffice), <b>Fedora</b> (djvulibre, mingw-glib2, mingw-python-jinja2, and mingw-python-werkzeug), <b>Oracle</b> (.NET 7.0, .NET 8.0, kernel, and nodejs:18), <b>Red Hat</b> (nodejs:20), <b>Slackware</b> (gdk and git), <b>SUSE</b> (python), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-hwe-5.15, linux-raspi).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973908/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 13:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mozilla Foundation Welcomes Nabiha Syed as Executive Director</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973820/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Mozilla Foundation has <a
href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/mozilla-foundation-welcomes-nabiha-syed-as-executive-director/">announced</a>
that its new executive director will be Nabiha Syed.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Syed is known for her mission-driven leadership, focused on
	increasing transparency into the most powerful institutions in
	society. She comes to Mozilla after leading The Markup, an
	award-winning publication that challenges technology to serve the
	public good, from its launch through its successful acquisition in
	2024. 
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973820/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 02:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for May 9, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972160/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for May 9, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972160/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Securing Git repositories with gittuf</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972467/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The so-called software supply chain starts with source code. But most security measures and tooling
don't kick in until source is turned into an artifact&mdash;a source
tarball, binary build, container image, or other method of delivering a
release to users. The <a href="https://gittuf.dev/">gittuf</a> project
is an attempt to provide a security layer for <a
href="https://git-scm.com/">Git</a> that can handle key management,
enforce security policies for repositories, and guard against attacks
at the version-control layer. At Open Source Summit North America (OSSNA), Aditya Sirish A
Yelgundhalli and Billy Lynch <a
href="https://ossna2024.sched.com/event/1aBPF/securing-git-repositories-with-gittuf-aditya-sirish-a-yelgundhalli-new-york-university-billy-lynch-chainguard">presented</a>
an introduction to gittuf with an overview of its goals and
status.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972467/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 16:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A proposal to switch Fedora Workstation&apos;s desktop</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970929/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[A proposal to switch the default desktop for Fedora Workstation from GNOME
to KDE Plasma largely went over like the proverbial lead balloon—unsurprisingly.
But the 
conversation about the proposal did surface some areas where the
distribution could 
perhaps be more inclusive with regard to the other desktop choices
available.  The project believes that it
benefits from being opinionated and not requiring users to make
multiple decisions before they can even install the distribution, but there
is a balance 
to be found.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970929/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 21:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Systemd heads for a big round-number release</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971866/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The
<a href="https://systemd.io/">
systemd project</a> is preparing for a new release.
<a href="https://github.com/systemd/systemd/releases/tag/v256-rc1">
Version&nbsp;256-rc1</a> was released
on April&nbsp;25 with a large number of changes and new features. Most of the
changes relate to security, easier configuration, unprivileged access to system
resources, or all three of these. Users of systemd will find setting up
containers — even without root access — much simpler and more secure.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971866/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 15:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Modernizing accessibility for desktop Linux</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971541/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In some aspects, such as in gaming, the Linux desktop has made
enormous strides in the past few years. In others, such as
accessibility, things have stagnated. At <a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/open-source-summit-north-america/">Open Source Summit North America</a> (OSSNA), Matt Campbell <a
href="https://ossna2024.sched.com/event/1aBO1/modernizing-accessibility-for-desktop-linux-matt-campbell-gnome-foundation">spoke</a>
about the need for, and an approach to, modernizing accessibility for
desktop Linux. This included a discussion of Newton, a fledgling
project that may greatly improve accessibility on the Linux desktop.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971541/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 17:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The file_operations structure gets smaller</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972081/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Kernel developers are encouraged to send their changes in small batches as
a way of making life easier for reviewers.  So when a longtime developer
and maintainer hits the list with a 437-patch series touching 859 files,
eyebrows are certain to head skyward.  Specifically, <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-kernel/20240411153126.16201-1-axboe@kernel.dk/">this series
from Jens Axboe</a> is cleaning up one of the core abstractions that has
been part of the Linux kernel almost since the beginning; authors of device
drivers (among others) will have to take note.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972081/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 15:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Inheritable credentials for directory file descriptors</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971825/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In Unix-like systems, an open file descriptor carries the right to access
the opened object in specific ways.  As a general rule, that file
descriptor does <i>not</i> enable access to any other objects.  The
recently merged <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/947173/">BPF token feature</a> runs
counter to this practice by creating file descriptors that carry specific
BPF-related access rights.  A similar but different approach to
capability-carrying file descriptors, in the form of directory file
descriptors that include their own credentials, is currently under
consideration in the kernel community.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971825/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 15:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Linux maintainers were infected for 2 years by SSH-dwelling backdoor
(ars technica)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973783/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Ars technica <a
href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/05/ssh-backdoor-has-infected-400000-linux-servers-over-15-years-and-keeps-on-spreading/">looks
at</a> a <a
href="https://web-assets.esetstatic.com/wls/en/papers/white-papers/ebury-is-alive-but-unseen.pdf">a
recent report</a> on the Ebury root kit, with a focus on the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/464233/">2011 compromise of kernel.org</a>, which may have
been more extensive than believed at the time.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	In 2014, ESET researchers said the 2011 attack likely infected
	kernel.org servers with a second piece of malware they called
	Ebury. The malware, the firm said, came in the form of a malicious
	code library that, when installed, created a backdoor in OpenSSH
	that provided the attackers with a remote root shell on infected
	hosts with no valid password required. In a little less than 22
	months, starting in August 2011, Ebury spread to 25,000
	servers. Besides the four belonging to the Linux Kernel
	Organization, the infection also touched one or more servers inside
	hosting facilities and an unnamed domain registrar and web hosting
	provider. 
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973783/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 18:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Firefox 126.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973763/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/126.0/releasenotes/">Version
126.0</a> of the Firefox browser is out.  Changes include improvements to
the "copy link without site tracking" feature, support for zstd
compression, and a new tracking "feature": "<q>Telemetry was added to create
an aggregate count of searches by category to broadly inform search feature
development.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973763/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 14:03:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973746/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Mageia</b> (sssd and tcpdump), <b>Red Hat</b> (.NET 7.0, .NET 8.0, expat, kernel, and kernel-rt), <b>Slackware</b> (mozilla), <b>SUSE</b> (kernel, postgresql15, postgresql16, python-arcomplete, python-Fabric, python-PyGithub, python- antlr4-python3-runtime, python-avro, python-chardet, python-distro, python- docker, python-fakeredis, python-fixedint, pyth, and python3), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-bluefield).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973746/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 13:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Manjaro 24.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973686/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://forum.manjaro.org/t/manjaro-24-0-wynsdey-released/161527">Version&nbsp;24.0</a>
of the Arch-based <a href="https://manjaro.org/">Manjaro</a> distribution is now available with
the 6.9&nbsp;kernel, GNOME&nbsp;46, Xfce&nbsp;4.18, and an update to the
<a href="https://wiki.manjaro.org/index.php/Pamac">Pamac</a> package
installer. This is also the project's first release with KDE&nbsp;Plasma&nbsp;6:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>The Plasma edition comes with the latest Plasma 6.0 series and KDE
Gear 24.02. It brings exciting new improvements to your desktop.</p>

<p>With Plasma 6, KDE's technology stack has undergone major upgrades:
a transition to the latest version of application framework, Qt, and
an improved graphics platform when Wayland is used. These changes are
as smooth and unnoticeable to the users as possible. You will see the
same familiar desktop environment that you know and love. But these
under-the-hood upgrades benefit Plasma's security, efficiency, and
performance, and improve support for modern hardware. Thus Plasma
delivers an overall more reliable user experience, while paving the
way for many more improvements in the future.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The project also offers minimal install images with the 6.6&nbsp;LTS
and 6.1&nbsp;LTS kernels to support older hardware.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973686/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 17:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973667/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (glib2.0 and shim), <b>Fedora</b> (glib2, gnome-shell, tcpdump, tpm2-tools, tpm2-tss, and uriparser), <b>Mageia</b> (mutt), <b>Oracle</b> (git-lfs, glibc, kernel, kernel-container, nodejs:18, nodejs:20, and pcp), <b>SUSE</b> (apache2, opensc, openssl-1_1, openssl-3, perl, python-Pillow, python-pyOpenSSL, python-Werkzeug, SUSE Manager Client Tools Beta, tpm2-0-tss, and tpm2.0-tools), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (sqlparse and strongswan).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973667/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 13:06:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/973496/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (nodejs:18 and shim), <b>Debian</b> (atril and chromium), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, glib2, gnome-shell, mediawiki, php-wikimedia-cdb, php-wikimedia-utfnormal, stb, and tcpdump), <b>Gentoo</b> (Kubelet, PoDoFo, Rebar3, and thunderbird), <b>Mageia</b> (glibc and libnbd), <b>Oracle</b> (kernel), <b>Red Hat</b> (bind and dhcp and varnish), and <b>SUSE</b> (chromium, cpio, freerdp, giflib, gnutls, opera, python-Pillow, python-Werkzeug, tinyproxy, and tpm2-0-tss).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/973496/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 13:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The 6.9 kernel is out</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972886/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/973397/">released</a> the 6.9 kernel. 
"<q>So 6.9 is now out, and last week has looked quite stable (and the
whole release has felt pretty normal).</q>"
Significant changes in this release include
the ability to create <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/794707/">pidfds</a> for individual
threads,
the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/961941/">BPF arena</a> subsystem,
the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/947173/">BPF token</a> security mechanism,
<tt>truncate()</tt> support in <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/776703/">io_uring</a>,
support for the Rust language on 64-bit Arm systems,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/948037/">weighted interleaving</a> in the
memory-management subsystem,
the <a
href="https://docs.kernel.org/admin-guide/device-mapper/vdo.html">device-mapper
virtual data optimizer</a> target,
initial <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/932060/">FUSE passthrough</a> support,
and more.

See the LWN merge-window summaries
(<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/965141/">part&nbsp;1</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/965541/">part&nbsp;2</a>) for more information.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972886/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 22:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>