<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 09:03:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 3 Sep 2024 09:46:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/988364/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (postgresql:16), <b>Debian</b> (dovecot, pymatgen, ruby2.7, systemd, and webkit2gtk), <b>Fedora</b> (microcode_ctl, python3.11, vim, and xen), <b>Oracle</b> (kernel, postgresql:12, postgresql:13, postgresql:15, and python39:3.9 and python39-devel:3.9), <b>Slackware</b> (libpcap), <b>SUSE</b> (cacti, cacti-spine, python-Django, and trivy), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (dovecot).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/988364/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 14:23:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.11-rc6</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/988184/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has released <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/988183/">6.11-rc6</a> for testing.
"<q>Things look pretty normal, although we have perhaps unusually many
filesystem fixes here, spread out over smb, xfs, bcachefs and netfs.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/988184/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 14:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Understanding the Postgres Hackers Mailing List Language</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987892/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Reading an established open-source project's developer mailing list
may leave new contributors wishing they had a decoder ring. Greg
Sabino Mullane has written up a valuable <a
href="https://www.crunchydata.com/blog/understanding-the-postgres-hackers-mailing-list">explainer</a>
for those new to the PostgreSQL hackers (<a
href="https://www.postgresql.org/list/pgsql-hackers/">pgsql-hackers</a>)
mailing list that may also be useful for decoding other lists as well:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>The mailing lists are full of acronyms and jargon that might not be
familiar to younger people who did not grow up on email (although text
messages have inherited many of the abbreviations). If you are a
non-native English speaker, or under the age of 30, or not steeped in
the world of tech, I offer some solutions below.</p>

<p>To do this, I downloaded the last year's worth of hackers email,
wrote a program to strip out all the non-human stuff (headers, code
blocks, attachments, etc.), and then did some data analysis on the
results.</p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987892/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 15:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>ElasticSearch and Kibana become free software (again)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987850/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Back in 2021, the ElasticSearch search engine and Kibana visualization
platform <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/843274/">were relicensed</a> under the non-free
Server Side Public License (SSPL).  Now, Elastic (the company owning those
projects) has <a
href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/elasticsearch-is-open-source-again">announced</a>
that those projects will also be distributable under the Affero GPL license.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	We never stopped believing and behaving like an open source
	community after we changed the license. But being able to use the
	term Open Source, by using AGPL, an OSI approved license, removes
	any questions, or fud, people might have.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987850/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 14:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>AnandTech shuts down</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987847/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The venerable AnandTech site has <a
href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/21542/end-of-the-road-an-anandtech-farewell">announced
its closing</a> after 27&nbsp;years of technology-industry coverage.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Still, few things last forever, and the market for written tech
	journalism is not what it once was – nor will it ever be again. So,
	the time has come for AnandTech to wrap up its work, and let the
	next generation of tech journalists take their place within the
	zeitgeist.
</blockquote>
<p>
The site will surely be missed.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987847/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 13:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Airlie: On Rust, Linux, developers, maintainers</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987849/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Dave Airlie <a
href="https://airlied.blogspot.com/2024/08/on-rust-linux-developers-maintainers.html">makes
an analogy</a> between the stages of road building and those of adding Rust
to the Linux kernel.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	For the wayfinders the process of interacting with maintainers is
	frustrating and slow, and they don't enjoy it as much as
	wayfinding, and because they still only care about the hotel at the
	end, when a maintainer gets into the details of their particular
	intersection they don't want to do anything but go stay in their
	hotel. 
<p>
	The road will get built, it will get traffic on it. There will be
	tunnels where we should have intersections, there will be bridges
	that need to be built from both sides, but I do think it will get
	built.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987849/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 13:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987836/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (libvpx, postgresql, postgresql:12, postgresql:13, postgresql:15, and python39:3.9 and python39-devel:3.9), <b>Debian</b> (chromium and ghostscript), <b>Fedora</b> (python3.13), and <b>SUSE</b> (chromium and podman).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987836/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 12:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Graham: Asking for donations in Plasma</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987715/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://kde.org/">KDE project</a> plans to directly
ask for donations in the Plasma desktop starting with version
6.2. According to <a
href="https://pointieststick.com/2024/08/28/asking-for-donations-in-plasma/">this
blog post</a> by Nate Graham, users will see <a
href="https://invent.kde.org/plasma/plasma-workspace/-/merge_requests/4490">a
system notification</a> once per year (in December) asking for a
donation to the non-profit <a href="https://ev.kde.org/">KDE&nbsp;e.V.</a>:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Now, I know that messages like this can be controversial! The
change was carefully considered, and we tried our best to minimize
the annoying-ness factor: It's small and unobtrusive, and no matter
what you do with it (click any button, close it, etc) it'll go away
until next year. It's implemented as a KDE Daemon (KDED) module,
which allows users and distributors to permanently disable it if they
like.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987715/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 19:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>GNU Screen v.5.0.0 is released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987700/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Version 5.0.0 of <a
href="https://www.gnu.org/software/screen/">GNU&nbsp;Screen</a> has
been released. Notable changes in this release include
new commands for authentication, input into multiple windows at the
same time, and to turn on/off truecolor support.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987700/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 18:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Three new stable kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987677/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Greg Kroah-Hartman has announced the release of the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/987678/">6.10.7</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/987679/">6.6.48</a>, and <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/987680/">6.1.107</a> stable kernels.  They all contain
important fixes throughout the kernel tree, as is the norm.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987677/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 16:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987664/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (bind and bind-dyndb-ldap and postgresql:16), <b>Fedora</b> (less and python3.6), <b>Mageia</b> (nodejs &amp; yarnpkg), <b>Oracle</b> (libvpx and postgresql:16), <b>Red Hat</b> (edk2, git, kernel, openldap, postgresql:15, postgresql:16, python3, and python39:3.9 and python39-devel:3.9), <b>SUSE</b> (apache2, python-setuptools, and python3-setuptools), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-oracle).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987664/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 14:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rust-for-Linux Wedson Almeida Filho drops out</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987635/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Wedson Almeida Filho, one of the key developers driving the <a
href="https://rust-for-linux.com/">Rust for Linux project</a>, has <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20240828211117.9422-1-wedsonaf@gmail.com">retired from the
project</a>.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	 After almost 4 years, I find myself lacking the energy and
	 enthusiasm I once had to respond to some of the nontechnical
	 nonsense, so it's best to leave it up to those who still have it
	 in them.
</blockquote>
<p>
As an example of the sort of "nonsense" he referred to, he provided <a
href="https://youtu.be/WiPp9YEBV0Q?t=1529">a link to the video</a> from the
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/978738/">Rust for filesystems discussion</a> at the 2024
Linux Storage, Filesystem, Memory-Management, and BPF Summit.  His work was
fundamental to getting the project as far as it has come; he will be missed.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987635/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 14:07:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A review of file descriptor memory safety in the kernel</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/985853/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
On July 30, Al Viro sent
<a href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20240730050927.GC5334@ZenIV/">
a patch set</a> to the linux-fsdevel mailing list with a
comprehensive cover letter explaining his
recent work on ensuring that the kernel's internal representation of
file descriptors are used correctly in the kernel.
File descriptors are ubiquitous; many system calls
need to handle them. Viro's review
identified a few existing bugs, and may prevent more in the future. He also had
suggestions for ways to keep uses consistent throughout the kernel.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/985853/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 15:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for August 22, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/985783/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for August 22, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/985783/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 01:51:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Modernizing openSUSE installation with Agama</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/974969/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Linux installers receive a disproportionate amount of attention
compared to the amount of time that most users spend with them. Ideally,
a user spends only a few minutes using the installer, versus years using
the distribution after it is installed. Yet, the installer sets the
first impression, and if it fails to do its job, little else matters.
Installers also have to continually evolve to keep pace with new
hardware, changes in distribution packaging (such as image-based Linux
distributions), and so forth. Along those lines, the SUSE team that maintains the
venerable <a href="https://yast.opensuse.org/">YaST</a> installer has
decided it's time to start (almost) fresh with a new Linux installer
project, called <a href="https://github.com/openSUSE/agama">Agama</a>,
for new projects. YaST is not going away as an administration tool,
but it is likely to be relieved of installer duties at some point.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/974969/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 15:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Python subinterpreters and free-threading</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/985041/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[At
<a
href="https://us.pycon.org/2024/">PyCon&nbsp;2024</a> in Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania, Anthony Shaw looked at the various kinds of parallelism
available to Python programs.  There have been two major developments on
the parallel-execution front over the last few years, with the effort to
provide <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/820424/">subinterpreters</a>, each with its own
global interpreter lock (GIL), along with the work to <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/940780/">remove the GIL entirely</a>.  In the talk, he
explored the two approaches to try to give attendees a sense of how to make
the right choice for their applications.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/985041/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 22:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Per-call-site slab caches for heap-spraying protection</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986174/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[One tactic often used by attackers set on compromising a system is <a
href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heap_spraying">heap spraying</a>; in
short, the attacker fills as much of the heap as possible with crafted data
in the hope of getting the target system to use that data in a bad way.  If
heap spraying can be blocked, attackers will lose an important tool.  The
kernel has some heap-spraying defenses now, including the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/965837/">dedicated bucket allocator</a> merged for the
upcoming 6.11 release, but its author, Kees Cook, thinks that more can be
done.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986174/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 13:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] FreeBSD considers Rust in the base system</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/985210/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.freebsd.org/">FreeBSD Project</a> is, for the second
time this year, engaging in a long-running discussion about the
possibility of including Rust in its <a
href="https://www.over-yonder.net/~fullermd/rants/bsd4linux/03">base
system</a>. The sequel to the first discussion included some work by
Alan Somers to show what it might look like to use Rust code in the
base tree. Support for Rust code does not appear much closer to being
included in FreeBSD's base system, but the conversation has been
enlightening.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/985210/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 15:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Custom string formatters in Python</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/985346/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Python has had
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/656898/">formatted string literals</a>
(<span style="white-space:nowrap">f-strings</span>), a syntactic shorthand for building
strings, since 2015. Recently, Jim Baker, Guido van Rossum, and Paul Everitt have
proposed
<a href="https://peps.python.org/pep-0750/">
PEP 750</a> ("Tag Strings For Writing Domain-Specific Languages") which would
generalize and expand that mechanism to provide Python library writers with additional
flexibility. Reactions to the proposed change were somewhat positive, although
there was a good deal of discussion of (and opposition to)
the PEP's inclusion of lazy evaluation of template parameters.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/985346/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 15:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Memory-management: tiered memory, huge pages, and EROFS</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984839/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The kernel's memory-management developers have been busy in recent times;
it can be hard to keep up with all that has been happening in this core
area.  In an attempt to catch up, here is a look at recent work
affecting tiered-memory systems, underutilized huge pages, and duplicated
file data in the Enhanced Read-Only Filesystem (EROFS).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984839/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 14:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Judge dismisses majority of GitHub Copilot copyright claims (Developer)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987524/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Developer <a
href="https://www.developer-tech.com/news/judge-dismisses-majority-github-copilot-copyright-claims/">reports</a>
that most (but not all) of the claims in the GitHub Copilot lawsuit have
been dismissed with prejudice by the judge.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Judge Jon Tigar's ruling, unsealed last week, leaves only two
	claims standing: one accusing the companies of an open-source
	license violation and another alleging breach of contract. This
	decision marks a substantial setback for the developers who argued
	that GitHub Copilot, which uses OpenAI's technology and is owned by
	Microsoft, unlawfully trained on their work.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987524/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 13:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987519/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (calibre, dotnet8.0, dovecot, webkit2gtk4.0, and webkitgtk), <b>Oracle</b> (nodejs:20), <b>Red Hat</b> (bind, bind and bind-dyndb-ldap, postgresql:16, and squid), <b>Slackware</b> (kcron and plasma), <b>SUSE</b> (keepalived and webkit2gtk3), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (drupal7).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987519/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 13:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>WineHQ to take over Mono</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987465/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Mono project was started in 2001 to develop a .NET environment for
Linux systems.  Microsoft has owned that project since 2016, but has not
made a major release since 2019.  The company has now <a
href="https://www.mono-project.com/">announced</a> that Mono is being
handed over to the WineHQ organization, which will maintain <a
href="https://gitlab.winehq.org/wine-mono/mono">the repository</a> going
forward.  Microsoft, meanwhile, is steering users toward its "<q>modern
fork</q>" that it continues to maintain.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987465/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 21:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Calligra Office 4.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987414/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>KDE developer Carl Schwan has <a
href="https://carlschwan.eu/2024/08/27/calligra-office-4.0-is-out/">announced</a>
the release of <a href="https://calligra.org/">Calligra Office</a>
version 4.0. The most significant changes in this release include a "<q>major
overhaul</q>" of the office suite's user interface, and a transition to <a
href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Qt_(software)">Qt&nbsp;6</a> and <a href="https://develop.kde.org/products/frameworks/">KDE&nbsp;Frameworks&nbsp;6</a>.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987414/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 17:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Call for nominations: Ubuntu Community Council</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987406/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Nominations are <a
href="https://fridge.ubuntu.com/2024/08/26/call-for-nominations-ubuntu-community-council/">now
open</a> for people interested in joining the <a
href="https://ubuntu.com/community/governance/community-council">Ubuntu
Community Council</a>, "<q>the highest governance body of the Ubuntu
project</q>". Any <a
href="https://ubuntu.com/community/membership">Ubuntu Member</a> can
apply from now until Sunday, September 22 at 23:59 UTC.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
The Ubuntu project turned 20 this year, but is still in constant
flux. The advent of new communication platforms, new projects under
our umbrella, and the ever-growing popularity of the project requires
our community to evolve. We need to make sure Ubuntu is set to tackle
the challenges of the next 20 years. It needs a strong and active
community council to guide the project forwards.
</blockquote>

<p>See Merlijn Sebrechts's <a
href="https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2024-02-17-ubuntu-community-council-year/">blog
post</a>, "A year in the Ubuntu community council", for an overview of
what it's like to serve on the council.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987406/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 16:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987393/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (nodejs:20), <b>Debian</b> (python3.11), <b>Fedora</b> (dotnet8.0), <b>Red Hat</b> (bind, krb5, libreoffice, linux-firmware, orc, orc:0.4.28, and orc:0.4.31), <b>SUSE</b> (mariadb and openssl-3), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-aws-5.4).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987393/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 12:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>