<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 10:37:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Forgejo changes license to GPLv3+</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986998/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The 
<a href="https://forgejo.org/">
Forgejo</a> project has <a href="https://forgejo.org/2024-08-gpl/">announced</a> that, starting from version 9.0, Forgejo will be released under the GPLv3 license (or a later version). Older versions of the software forge remain MIT-licensed.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
A copyleft license makes reusing other copyleft software easier. Recently, we discovered that 
<a href="https://forgejo.org/2024-07-non-free-dependency-found/">
some of the dependencies we used were incompatible with the license Forgejo was distributed with</a>, and they had to be removed for now. Choosing copyleft licenses enables us to reuse more work, and saves us precious time to focus on improving Forgejo itself.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986998/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 13:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986997/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (community-mysql, iaito, and radare2), <b>Oracle</b> (python3.12-setuptools and tomcat), <b>Red Hat</b> (krb5 and podman), <b>Slackware</b> (ffmpeg), <b>SUSE</b> (apache2, expat, firefox, webkit2gtk3, and xen), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (imagemagick and libxstream-java).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986997/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 13:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>LibreOffice 24.8 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986906/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a
href="https://blog.documentfoundation.org/blog/2024/08/22/libreoffice-248/">Version
24.8</a> of the LibreOffice office suite has been released.  Changes
include the ability to filter identifying information from exported files,
easier creation of cross reference, better control over hyphenation, a
number of new spreadsheet functions, accessibility improvements, and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986906/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 18:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986841/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (.NET 8.0, bind, bind9.16, curl, edk2, firefox, gnome-shell, grafana, jose, krb5, libreoffice, mod_auth_openidc:2.3, orc, pcs, poppler, python-setuptools, python-urllib3, python3.11-setuptools, python3.12-setuptools, thunderbird, tomcat, and wget), <b>Fedora</b> (webkitgtk), <b>SUSE</b> (apache2, glib2, and roundcubemail), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (kernel, linux, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.15, linux-azure, linux-azure-5.15,
 linux-azure-fde, linux-azure-fde-5.15, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.15,
 linux-gke, linux-gkeop, linux-gkeop-5.15, linux-hwe-5.15, linux-ibm,
 linux-ibm-5.15, linux-intel-iotg, linux-intel-iotg-5.15, linux-kvm,
 linux-lowlatency, linux-lowlatency-hwe-5.15, linux-nvidia, linux-oracle,
 linux-raspi, linux, linux-aws, linux-azure, linux-bluefield, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-5.4,
 linux-gkeop, linux-hwe-5.4, linux-ibm, linux-ibm-5.4, linux-kvm,
 linux-oracle, linux-oracle-5.4, linux-raspi, linux-xilinx-zynqmp, linux, linux-aws, linux-azure, linux-gcp, linux-gke, linux-ibm,
 linux-lowlatency, linux-nvidia, linux-nvidia-6.8, linux-nvidia-lowlatency,
 linux-oem-6.8, linux-oracle, linux-raspi, linux, linux-aws, linux-kvm, linux-lts-xenial, linux, linux-gcp, linux-gcp-4.15, linux-hwe, linux-kvm, linux-aws, linux-aws-hwe, linux-bluefield, linux-hwe-5.15, linux-raspi-5.4, and qemu).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986841/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 14:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Garrett: What is an SBAT and why does everyone suddenly care</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986844/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Matthew Garrett <a href="https://mjg59.dreamwidth.org/70348.html">describes
the role of the Secure Boot Advanced Targeting mechanism</a> and how it
played into the recent Windows upgrade problems.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	So why is this suddenly relevant? SBAT was developed
	collaboratively between the Linux community and Microsoft, and
	Microsoft chose to push a Windows update that told systems not to
	trust versions of grub with a security generation below a certain
	level. This was because those versions of grub had genuine security
	vulnerabilities that would allow an attacker to compromise the
	Windows secure boot chain, and we've seen real world examples of
	malware wanting to do that.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986844/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 14:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for August 15, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984770/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for August 15, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984770/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 01:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Standards for use of unsafe Rust in the kernel</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982868/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Rust is intended to let programmers write safer code.
But compilers are
not omniscient, and writing Rust code that interfaces with hardware (or that
works with memory outside of Rust's lifetime paradigm) requires, at
some point, the programmer's assurance that some operations are permissible. Benno Lossin
<a href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20240717221133.459589-1-benno.lossin@proton.me/">
suggested adding
some more documentation</a> to
<a href="https://rust-for-linux.com/">
the Rust-for-Linux project</a> clarifying the
standards for commenting uses of <tt>unsafe</tt> in kernel code. There's general
agreement that such standards are necessary, but less agreement on exactly when
it is appropriate to use <tt>unsafe</tt>.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982868/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 14:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Zettlr: note-taking and publishing with Markdown</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984502/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a> editors are a dime a dozen. Cheaper than that, actually,
since many of them are open&#8209;source software. Despite the sheer number of
options, finding an editor that has all of the features that one might want can
be tricky. For some users, <a href="https://www.zettlr.com/">Zettlr</a>
might the right tool. It is a <a
href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WYSIWYM">What You See is What You
Mean</a> (WYSIWYM) editor that stores its work locally as plain Markdown
files. The project is billed as a "<q>one-stop publication
workbench</q>", and is suitable for writing anything from blog posts to
academic papers, maintaining a personal journal, or keeping notes in a <a
href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zettelkasten">Zettlekasten</a>. It
is simple to get started with, but rewards deeper exploration and
customization.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984502/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Changes coming in PostgreSQL 17</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984599/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The
<a href="https://www.postgresql.org/">
PostgreSQL</a> project has
<a href="https://www.postgresql.org/about/news/postgresql-164-158-1413-1316-1220-and-17-beta-3-released-2910/">
released</a> beta
versions of PostgreSQL 17 containing several interesting security and usability
improvements, alongside the usual performance improvements and bug fixes. If the
release proceeds according to the usual timeline, the full release of version 17
is expected in September or October.
The most important changes are in what PostgreSQL does when a database
supervisor has their credentials revoked, and added
support for incremental database backups.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984599/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 14:10:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] COSMIC desktop makes its debut</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984638/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Linux hardware vendor <a
href="https://system76.com/about">System76</a> started <a
href="https://blog.system76.com/post/november-at-system76-products-promos--cosmic-de">promoting</a>
its work on a <a
href="https://github.com/pop-os/cosmic-epoch">Rust-based, Wayland
desktop environment</a> for its <a
href="https://pop.system76.com/"><nobr>Pop!_OS</nobr></a>
Ubuntu-derivative distribution almost two years
ago. On August 8, the company released an alpha version of the <a
href="https://system76.com/cosmic">COSMIC desktop environment</a> for
users to test out. While it has rough edges and missing features, it
is stable enough to get a good feel for what the finished product has
in store&mdash;and the initial results are promising.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984638/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 17:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Meeting the Debian Technical Committee</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984720/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[It is something of a DebConf tradition that members of the <a
href="https://www.debian.org/devel/tech-ctte">Debian Technical
Committee</a> (TC) take the stage to talk about the work that the committee
does—and more.  <a href="https://debconf24.debconf.org/">DebConf24</a> in
Busan, South Korea was no exception, as TC chair Sean Whitton, who
will complete his term at the end of the year, and one
of its newest members, Stefano Rivera, described the constitutional
underpinnings of the TC, how it tries to make decisions when it needs to,
and the constant process of recruiting new members.  After that, they took
a few questions from the audience.  The session provided a nice overview of
the TC and its role in Debian, but it may well be of interest further afield.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984720/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 01:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Distinguishing Debian testing from unstable</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984635/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Sometimes, the smallest changes create the longest discussions.  As a case
in point, a proposal to make a one-line change in an informational text
file on systems running the Debian unstable distribution has blown up into
an interminable and sometimes unfriendly debate.  At its core, though, this
discussion comes down to a seemingly simple question: should a program be
able to determine whether it is running on a Debian testing or unstable
system?]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984635/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 15:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Endless OS aimed at educational and offline environments</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984086/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
<a href="https://www.endlessos.org/os">
Endless OS</a> is a Linux distribution with a focus on improving access to
educational tools by providing a simple-to-manage, full-featured desktop for
educators and students — one that works offline, with minimal maintenance. The
distribution also aims to be suitable for older devices, in order to promote access to
computers by ensuring those systems remain usable.
In pursuit of those goals, it makes some unusual technical
choices. But what makes the distribution really shine is its curated collection
of software and educational resources.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984086/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 13:56:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>“Something has gone seriously wrong,” dual-boot systems warn after Microsoft update (ars technica)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986659/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Ars technica <a
href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/08/a-patch-microsoft-spent-2-years-preparing-is-making-a-mess-for-some-linux-users/">covers</a>
a recent <a
href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2022-2601">update</a>
that is causing problems for users with systems that dual-boot Windows
and Linux.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>"Note that Windows says this update won't apply to systems that
dual-boot Windows and Linux," one frustrated person wrote. "This
obviously isn't true, and likely depends on your system configuration
and the distribution being run. It appears to have made some linux efi
shim bootloaders incompatible with microcrap efi bootloaders (that's
why shifting from MS efi to 'other OS' in efi setup works). It appears
that Mint has a shim version that MS SBAT doesn't recognize."</p>

<p>The reports indicate that multiple distributions, including Debian,
Ubuntu, Linux Mint, Zorin OS, and Puppy Linux, are all
affected. Microsoft has yet to acknowledge the error publicly, explain
how it wasn't detected during testing, or provide technical guidance
to those affected. Company representatives didn't respond to an email
seeking answers.</p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986659/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 18:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Górny: Gentoo: profiles and keywords rather than releases</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986655/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Gentoo developer Michał Górny has written a lengthy <a
href="https://blogs.gentoo.org/mgorny/2024/08/20/gentoo-profiles-and-keywords-rather-than-releases/">blog
post</a> that explains how Gentoo approaches releases:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Gentoo is something of a hybrid, as it combines the best of both
worlds. It is a rolling release distribution with a single shared
repository that is available to all users. However, within this
repository we use a keywording system to provide a choice between
stable and testing packages, to facilitate both production and
development systems (with some extra flexibility), and versioned
profiles to tackle major lock-step upgrades.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986655/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 17:31:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986628/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (aom, cinder, dovecot, glance, and nova), <b>Fedora</b> (mysql8.0), <b>Oracle</b> (curl and libreoffice), <b>SUSE</b> (oniguruma, openssl-1_0_0, openssl1, and xen), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (cacti, curl, exfatprogs, firefox, and vim).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986628/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 13:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>uv 0.3.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986528/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/astral-sh/uv/releases/tag/0.3.0">Version 0.3.0</a> of the <a href="https://docs.astral.sh/uv/">uv</a>
Python package and project manager has been released. <a href="https://astral.sh/blog/uv">Introduced</a> in
February, uv is written in Rust and aims to be "<q>Cargo for
Python</q>".  Notable changes in this release include the addition of
interfaces for <a href="https://docs.astral.sh/uv/concepts/projects/">managing projects</a>, <a
href="https://docs.astral.sh/uv/guides/install-python/">installing
Python</a>, <a
href="https://docs.astral.sh/uv/guides/scripts/">running scripts</a>,
and <a href="https://docs.astral.sh/uv/">new documentation</a>. See the
accompanying <a href="https://astral.sh/blog/uv-unified-python-packaging">blog post</a> for more information.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986528/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 21:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986450/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (squid), <b>Fedora</b> (putty), <b>Mageia</b> (quictls), <b>Oracle</b> (bind, curl, python-setuptools, python3.11-setuptools, and python3.12-setuptools), <b>Red Hat</b> (kernel, kpatch-patch-4_18_0-305_120_1, kpatch-patch-4_18_0-372_87_1 and kpatch-patch-4_18_0-372_91_1, kpatch-patch-4_18_0-477_43_1, kpatch-patch-4_18_0-553, kpatch-patch-5_14_0-284_48_1 and kpatch-patch-5_14_0-284_52_1, kpatch-patch-5_14_0-427_13_1, and libreoffice), <b>SUSE</b> (cosign, dri3proto, presentproto, wayland-protocols, xwayland, freerdp, fwupdate, git, gnome-settings-daemon, hdf5, jasper, java-17-openjdk, java-1_8_0-ibm, java-1_8_0-openjdk, kernel, kernel-firmware, libaom, libqt5-qt3d, libqt5-qtquick3d, ntfs-3g_ntfsprogs, osc, python, python-aiohttp, python-azure-core, python-azure-storage-blob, python- azure-storage-queue, python-typing, python-typing_extensions, python-Jinja2, python-PyMySQL, python-requests, python-tqdm, python-WebOb, python3-sqlparse, python310, python311, qemu, sssd, thunderbird, tiff, unixODBC, uriparser, and wireshark), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (intel-microcode, linux-azure-5.4, and postgresql-12, postgresql-14, postgresql-16).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986450/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 13:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Seven new stable kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986229/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Today's crop of new stable kernels consists of seven new versions: <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/986230/">6.10.6</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/986231/">6.6.47</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/986232/">6.1.106</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/986233/">5.15.165</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/986234/">5.10.224</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/986235/">5.4.282</a>, and <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/986236/">4.19.320</a>.  As usual, each contains important
fixes throughout the kernel tree.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986229/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 14:43:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986225/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (python-asyncssh), <b>Fedora</b> (bind, bind-dyndb-ldap, httpd, and tor), <b>SUSE</b> (cosign, cpio, curl, expat, java-11-openjdk, ncurses, netty, netty-tcnative, opera, python-Django, python-Pillow, shadow, sudo, and wpa_supplicant), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (firefox).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986225/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 14:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Formatted Rust kernel documentation available</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986167/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Rust code being added to the kernel is documented using the usual <a
href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/rustdoc/what-is-rustdoc.html">rustdoc</a>
conventions; that documentation is now <a
href="https://rust.docs.kernel.org/kernel/">available on kernel.org</a> in
formatted form.  There is also <a
href="https://rust.docs.kernel.org/next/kernel/">the linux-next version of
the documentation</a> for Rust code that will land in the kernel soon.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986167/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 22:28:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.11-rc4</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986163/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/986162/">fourth 6.11 kernel prepatch</a> is out for
testing.  According to Linus:
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	But it all looks fairly normal. rc4 is bigger than either rc2 or
	rc3 were, but not hugely so, and it's actually a normal pattern,
	where it takes a while before people find some issues. So nothing
	feels all that odd.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986163/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 22:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>