<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 18:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 18:49:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Mesa 25.0.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010898/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a
href="https://lists.freedesktop.org/archives/mesa-dev/2025-February/226464.html">Version
25.0.0</a> of the Mesa graphics library has been released.  "<q>The flashiest addition is probably the support for Vulkan 1.4 by Anv (Intel),
Asahi (Apple), Lavapipe (software), NVK (NVIDIA), PanVK (Mali), RADV (AMD),
and Turnip (Qualcomm).

Users can expect the usual flurry of improvements across all drivers and
components.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010898/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 17:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>RISC-V and Fedora: All Aboard! (Fedora Magazine)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010857/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/">Fedora Project</a> has <a
href="https://fedoramagazine.org/risc-v-and-fedora-all-aboard/">announced</a>
two milestones in its journey to supporting the RISC-V architecture: a
dedicated RISC-V Koji build system instance is live in the Fedora data
center, and <a
href="https://dl.fedoraproject.org/pub/alt/risc-v/release/41/">Fedora
41-based images</a> are now available for RISC-V. It is also <a
href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Architectures/RISC-V/QEMU">possible</a>
to run Fedora RISC-V images using QEMU for those without supported
hardware.</p>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010857/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Lange: The secret maze of Debian images</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010855/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Debian Developer Thomas Lange has written a <a
href="https://blog.fai-project.org/posts/cdimages-maze/">blog post</a>
in the attempt to help users find the right Debian image for their
systems.</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
It's difficult to find the right Debian image. We have thousands of
ISO files and cloud images and we support multiple CPU architectures
and several download methods. The directory structure of our main
image server is like a maze, and our web pages for downloading are
also confusing.
</blockquote>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010855/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010853/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (gcc-toolset-14-gcc, nodejs:18, and nodejs:22), <b>Fedora</b> (bootc), <b>Gentoo</b> (OpenSSH), <b>Oracle</b> (doxygen, libxml2, mingw-glib2, and NetworkManager), <b>Red Hat</b> (bind, bind9.16, bind9.18, kernel, kernel-rt, mysql, and mysql:8.0), <b>Slackware</b> (openssh), <b>SUSE</b> (buildah, emacs, glibc, google-osconfig-agent, grub2, java-11-openj9, kernel, netty, netty-tcnative, openssh, openvswitch, podman, and ucode-intel), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (atril, libsndfile, libtasn1-6, openssh, python-virtualenv, and symfony).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010853/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Pi-hole v6 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010682/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://pi-hole.net/">Pi-hole</a> v6 has been <a
href="https://pi-hole.net/blog/2025/02/18/introducing-pi-hole-v6/#page-content">released</a>. The
latest version of the popular ad-blocking software sports a redesigned
user interface, has support for subscribing to allowlists, and brings
a new REST API and embedded web server. Its Docker/OCI image is now
based on <a href="https://www.alpinelinux.org/">Alpine Linux</a>
rather than <a href="https://debian.org/">Debian</a> to reduce image
size. See the announcement for guidance on upgrading existing Pi-hole
installations.</p>

<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010682/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 19:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A milestone for reproducible openSUSE</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010629/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Reproducible-openSUSE project has <a
href="https://news.opensuse.org/2025/02/18/rbos-project-hits-milestone/">announced</a>
that it has created a usable version of openSUSE with 100% reproducible
packages.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	[Bernhard] Wiedemann took on this 4-month-long project to create a
	fork of openSUSE that has 100% bit-reproducible packages. So far
	ring0 (aka bootstrap) and ring1 with 3,300 software packages have
	all successfully been patched and tested.
</blockquote>
<p>
This build is not yet recommended for production use, though.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010629/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 14:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Stable kernel 6.12.15</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010624/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1010623/">6.12.15</a> stable kernel update has been
fast-tracked to release.  It seems that its predecessor contains <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/CAJMi0nTbyi6VGTmmZ43wYWwJWur0XPtuswZ_5UaXB+S6Z=Mo6A@mail.gmail.com">a
regression in the XFS filesystem</a> that can lead to kernel crashes.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010624/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 14:43:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010621/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (gnutls28, openssh, and pam-pkcs11), <b>Mageia</b> (microcode and python-cryptography), <b>Oracle</b> (nodejs:18, nodejs:20, and rsync), <b>Red Hat</b> (gcc, nodejs:20, and nodejs:22), <b>SUSE</b> (emacs, kernel, openvswitch, and ucode-intel), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (Docker).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010621/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 14:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Three stable kernels under the sky</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010352/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Greg Kroah-Hartman has released three more stable kernels:
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1010354/">6.13.3</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1010356/">6.12.14</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1010357/">6.6.78</a>.
There was a bit of confusion that resulted in the patch for
<a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord/?id=CVE-2025-21687">CVE 2025-21687</a>
getting applied twice — but that doesn't result in any problems for users of the
kernel, just a bit of extra noise in the CVE database, so Kroah-Hartman has
decided to leave the releases as-is instead of rushing another point release.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010352/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 14:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010328/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (container-tools:rhel8, gcc, libxml2, nodejs:18, and nodejs:20), <b>Debian</b> (freerdp2, golang-glog, trafficserver, and tryton-client), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, krb5, libheif, microcode_ctl, nginx, nginx-mod-fancyindex, nginx-mod-modsecurity, nginx-mod-naxsi, nginx-mod-vts, and webkitgtk), <b>Mageia</b> (ffmpeg, golang, postgresql13 and postgresql15, and python-zipp), <b>Oracle</b> (container-tools:ol8, gcc, gcc-toolset-13-gcc, gcc-toolset-14-gcc, kernel, libxml2, and nodejs:20), <b>Red Hat</b> (gcc, idm:DL1, and ipa), <b>SUSE</b> (buildah, chromium, glibc, kernel, kernel-firmware-all-20250206, libecpg6, postgresql15, python, python3, python311, and ruby3.4-rubygem-rack), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (intel-microcode).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010328/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 12:35:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.14-rc3</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010232/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1010231/">6.14-rc3</a> kernel prepatch is out for
testing; the announcement, for unknown reasons, went only to the
linux-btrfs list.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	So the first few weeks of the 6.14 release development were
	smaller-than-usual, but rc3 is actually right in line with normal
	releases at this point. Probably just timing of pull requests, and
	we'll see how next week goes. But nothing looks worrisome.
</blockquote>
<p>
Along with the usual stream of fixes, this release includes the "<a
href="https://git.kernel.org/linus/35fa2d88ca94">faux bus</a>", designed
for simple drivers that just need some sort of virtual bus to be associated
with; this bus come with <a
href="https://git.kernel.org/linus/78418f300d3">Rust bindings</a> from the
outset.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1010232/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 23:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1009765/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (doxygen, gcc-toolset-13-gcc, gcc-toolset-14-gcc, kernel, and libxml2), <b>Debian</b> (chromium, postgresql-13, and webkit2gtk), <b>Fedora</b> (krb5, openssl, and python3.13), <b>Mageia</b> (ark, ofono, and perl-Net-OAuth, perl-Crypt-URandom, perl-Module-Build), <b>Oracle</b> (firefox, gcc, gcc-toolset-14-gcc, kernel, openssl, tbb, and thunderbird), <b>Red Hat</b> (libxml2), <b>SUSE</b> (chromium, golang-github-prometheus-prometheus, grafana, kernel, kernel-firmware-ath10k-20250206, kernel-firmware-bnx2-20250206, kernel-firmware-brcm-20250206, kernel-firmware-chelsio-20250206, kernel-firmware-dpaa2-20250206, kernel-firmware-mwifiex-20250206, kernel-firmware-platform-20250206, kernel-firmware-realtek-20250206, kernel-firmware-serial-20250206, kernel-firmware-ueagle-20250206, libtasn1, python312, qemu, SUSE Manager Client Tools, SUSE Manager Client Tools MU 5.0.3, and ucode-intel-20250211), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (activemq and libsndfile).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1009765/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 14:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New leadership for Asahi Linux</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1009528/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Asahi Linux project, which is working to support Linux on Apple
silicon, has <a
href="https://asahilinux.org/2025/02/passing-the-torch/">announced</a> the
resignation of Hector "marcan" Martin as its lead, and his replacement by a
seven-person committee.  "<q>Today's news is bittersweet. We are grateful
to marcan for kicking off this project and tirelessly working on it these
past years. Our community will miss him. Still, with your support, the
project has a bright future to come</q>".  Martin has explained his reasons
for leaving at length in <a
href="https://marcan.st/2025/02/resigning-as-asahi-linux-project-lead/">this
blog post</a>.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1009528/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 16:04:15 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>OpenSUSE Tumbleweed switches to SELinux</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1009522/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The openSUSE project has <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/a4280691-a338-4b45-8e62-904d1884a154@suse.de">announced</a>
that future installations of the Tumbleweed rolling distribution will use
SELinux for mandatory access control rather than AppArmor.  Existing
installations will not be migrated, and AppArmor will continue to be
maintained for Tumbleweed.  The openSUSE Leap distribution is not changing
— for now at least.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1009522/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 15:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1009450/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (doxygen and openssl), <b>Debian</b> (dcmtk and webkit2gtk), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, clevis-pin-tpm2, envision, fido-device-onboard, gotify-desktop, keylime-agent-rust, keyring-ima-signer, libkrun, python3.10, python3.11, python3.14, rust-afterburn, rust-cargo-vendor-filterer, rust-coreos-installer, rust-eif_build, rust-gst-plugin-reqwest, rust-nu, rust-openssl, rust-openssl-sys, rust-pore, rust-rpm-sequoia, rust-sequoia-keyring-linter, rust-sequoia-octopus-librnp, rust-sequoia-policy-config, rust-sequoia-sqv, rust-sevctl, rust-snphost, rust-tealdeer, rustup, and s390utils), <b>Mageia</b> (ffmpeg, php-tcpdf, python-tornado, and subversion), <b>Red Hat</b> (openssl and python-jinja2), <b>SUSE</b> (crun, glibc, kernel, libngtcp2-16, libtasn1, netty, ovmf, podman, python, and python3), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (ansible, digikam, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.15, linux-azure-6.8, and ruby2.7).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1009450/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for February 6, 2025</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007000/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Inside this week's LWN.net Weekly Edition:
        <p>
        <ul>
<li> <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1007000/">Front</a>: Finding concurrency bugs with sched_ext; Rust abstractions; 6.14 Merge window; Sealed system mappings; OpenSUSE board; Julia; Site tour.
            <li> <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1007002/">Briefs</a>: Binutils 2.44; Firefox 135.0; Freedesktop GitLab; GNU C Library 2.41; GTK; Servo; Thunderbird updates; Sanctions; Quotes; ...
            <li> <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1007003/">Announcements</a>: Newsletters, conferences, security updates, patches, and more.
            </ul>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007000/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Exposing concurrency bugs with a custom scheduler</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007689/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Jake Hillion gave
<a href="https://fosdem.org/2025/schedule/event/fosdem-2025-4489-concurrency-testing-using-custom-linux-schedulers/">
a presentation</a> at
<a href="https://fosdem.org/2025/">
FOSDEM</a> about using
<a href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/next/scheduler/sched-ext.html">
sched_ext</a>, the BPF
scheduling framework that was introduced in kernel version 6.12, to help find
elusive concurrency problems. In collaboration with Johannes Bechberger, he has
built a scheduler that can reveal theoretically possible but unobserved
concurrency bugs in test code in a few minutes. Since their scheduler only
relies on mainline kernel features, it can theoretically be applied to any
application that runs on Linux — although there are a number of caveats since
the project is still in its early days.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1007689/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 14:54:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] An update on sealed system mappings</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006375/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Jeff Xu has been working on
<a href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20241125202021.3684919-1-jeffxu@google.com/">
a patch set</a> that makes certain mappings in a process's address space
impossible to change, sealing them against tampering. This has some potential
security benefits — mainly, making
sure that someone cannot relocate the
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/446528/">vsyscall and
vDSO mappings</a> — but some kernel developers haven't
been impressed with the patches.
While the core functionality (sealing the mappings) is sound, some of the
supporting code for enabling and disabling the new feature caused concern by
going against the normal design for such things. Reviewers also questioned
how this feature would interact with checkpointing and with sandboxing.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006375/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 17:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The rest of the 6.14 merge window</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006378/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[By the time that Linus Torvalds <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1007546/">released
6.14-rc1</a> and closed the merge window for this development cycle, some
9,307 non-merge changesets had been pulled into the mainline
repository — the lowest level of merge-window activity seen in years.
There were, nonetheless, a number of interesting changes in the
5,000 commits pulled since <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1005651/">the
first-half merge-window summary</a> was written.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006378/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] New horizons for Julia</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006117/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://julialang.org/">Julia</a>, a free, general-purpose
programming language aimed at science, engineering, and related arenas of
technical computing, has steadily improved and widened its scope of
application since its <a
href="https://julialang.org/blog/2012/02/why-we-created-julia">initial public
release in&nbsp;2012</a>. As part of its <a
href="https://julialang.org/blog/2024/10/julia-1.11-highlights/">1.11&nbsp;release</a> from late 2024, Julia made several inroads into areas
outside of its traditional focus, provided its users with advances in
tooling, and has seen several improvements in performance and programmer
convenience. 
These recent developments in and
around Julia go a long way to answer several longstanding complaints from
both new and experienced users. We last <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/958337/">looked
in on the language</a> one year ago,
for its previous major release, Julia&nbsp;1.10.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006117/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 16:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A look at the openSUSE board election</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006916/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The election to replace outgoing <a
href="https://www.opensuse.org/">openSUSE</a> board members is
underway, with four candidates vying for three seats. The election was
initially scheduled to be completed in December, but the timeline was <a
href="https://news.opensuse.org/2025/01/07/board-elections-for-three-seats-revised/">extended</a>
due to too few candidates standing for the seats. Voting closes on
February&nbsp;2 and the results are expected to be announced on
February&nbsp;3.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006916/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 15:24:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Resistance to Rust abstractions for DMA mapping</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006805/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[While the path toward the ability to write device drivers in Rust has been
anything but smooth, steady progress has been made and that goal is close
to being achieved — for some types of drivers at least.  Device drivers
need to be able to set up memory areas for direct memory access (DMA)
transfers, though; that means Rust drivers will need a set of
abstractions to interface with the kernel's DMA-mapping subsystem.  Those
abstractions have run into resistance that has the potential to block
progress on the Rust-for-Linux project as a whole.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1006805/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 19:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Codeberg responds to hate attacks</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1009227/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://codeberg.org/">Codeberg</a> development forge has
recently been subject to sustained attacks resulting in, among other
things, abusive email being sent to the site's users.  The organization has
now put up <a
href="https://blog.codeberg.org/we-stay-strong-against-hate-and-hatred.html">a
description and a defiant response</a>:
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Extreme right forces actively target members of our communities and
	discriminate based on ethnicity and gender, political background,
	sexual orientation, disabilities, nationality and faith. However
	diversity is an important asset in free/libre software communities
	and it is what makes our software great and development productive.
<p>
	By targeting some of our most active translators, nicest
	designers, best developers and all other motivated contributors,
	they are hurting the free/libre software ecosystem as a whole.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/1009227/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 19:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>