<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 02:34:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 9 Aug 2024 02:54:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>0.0.0.0 Day: Exploiting Localhost APIs From the Browser (Oligo Security)</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984838/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Oligo Security blog <a
href="https://www.oligo.security/blog/0-0-0-0-day-exploiting-localhost-apis-from-the-browser">discloses</a>
a web-browser vulnerability that has been named "0.0.0.0 day".  In short,
browsers will allow JavaScript code to open connections to the all-zeroes
IPv4 address; the result is that any port that is open on the local host
can be accessed by a remote site.  "<q>When services use localhost, they
assume a constrained environment. This assumption, which can (as in the
case of this vulnerability) be faulty, results in insecure server
implementations.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984838/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984807/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (freeradius and freeradius:3.0), <b>Debian</b> (chromium, odoo, and roundcube), <b>Fedora</b> (microcode_ctl, mingw-qt5-qtbase, mingw-qt6-qtbase, opentofu, orc, python-setuptools, and vim), <b>Gentoo</b> (Nokogiri), <b>Oracle</b> (kernel), <b>Red Hat</b> (go-toolset:rhel8, golang, kernel, krb5, libtiff, python-setuptools, and python39:3.9 and python39-devel:3.9), <b>SUSE</b> (python-Django), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (krb5).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984807/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 13:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for August 1, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983267/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for August 1, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983267/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 04:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Showing up for Python in GNOME</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983897/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>A few years ago, <a
href="https://pygobject.gnome.org/">PyGObject</a>&mdash;the Python
package that provides bindings for <a
href="https://www.gtk.org/">GTK</a> and <a
href="https://www.gnome.org/">GNOME</a> applications&mdash;was not
faring particularly well. Several maintainers had left the project and its
development was not keeping pace with changes in GTK. At this year's
GUADEC, Dan Yeaw presented a <a
href="https://events.gnome.org/event/209/contributions/757/">talk</a>
about the project's decline, improvements in the last year, and his
experience getting involved in an undermaintained project.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983897/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 17:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Pulling Linux up by its bootstraps</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983340/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
A <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/841797/">
bootstrappable build</a> is one that builds existing
software from scratch — for example, building GCC without relying on an existing
copy of GCC. In 2023, the Guix project
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/930650/">announced</a> that the project had reduced the size
of the binary bootstrap seed needed to build its operating system to just 357-bytes —
not counting the Linux kernel required to run the build process. Now, the
<a href="https://github.com/fosslinux/live-bootstrap">live-bootstrap</a> project
has gone a step further and removed the need for an existing kernel at all.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983340/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 13:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Famfs: a filesystem interface to shareable memory</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983105/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[At the 2024 <a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux
Storage, Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>, John Groves led
a session on famfs, which is a filesystem he has developed that uses the
kernel's <a
href="https://docs.kernel.org/filesystems/dax.html">direct-access (DAX)</a>
mechanism to access memory that is shareable between hosts.  The discussion
was aimed at whether a different approach should be taken and, in
particular, whether FUSE should be used instead of implementing as an
in-kernel filesystem.  As noted in the <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20240229002020.85535-1-john@groves.net/">thread</a> about his
proposal for an LSFMM+BPF session, and the mailing-list discussions on <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/cover.1708709155.git.john%40groves.net/">the first</a> and <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-fsdevel/cover.1714409084.git.john@groves.net/">second
version</a> of his patch set, there is some skepticism that a new in-kernel
filesystem is warranted for the use case.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983105/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 21:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Report from the annual general meeting at GUADEC</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983203/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>At <a
href="https://foundation.gnome.org/2023/12/20/guadec-2024-in-denver-colorado/">GUADEC</a>
in Denver, Colorado on July&nbsp;21, the GNOME Foundation held its <a
href="https://events.gnome.org/event/209/contributions/778/">annual
general meeting</a> (AGM) to provide updates from the <a
href="https://wiki.gnome.org/FoundationBoard">foundation's board</a> and committees.
Topics included work accomplished in the past year, challenges
facing the GNOME Foundation–including fundraising and finding a new
executive director–and some insight into plans for the next year. And
last, but not least, the awarding of the <a
href="https://wiki.gnome.org/Pants">Pants of Thanks</a>.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983203/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] The rest of the 6.11 merge window</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982605/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The release of <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/CAHk-=wiyNokz0d3b=GRORij=mGvwoYHy=+bv6m2Hu_VqNdg66g@mail.gmail.com/">6.11-rc1</a>
marked the end of the 6.11 merge window on July&nbsp;28.  By that time,
12,102 non-merge changesets had been pulled into the mainline repository;
about 8,000 of those came in after <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/982034/">the
first-half summary</a> was written.  Quite a few significant changes were
to be found in those changesets; there is also one big change that did not
make it.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982605/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 13:54:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] May the FOLL_FORCE not be with you</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983169/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[One of the simplest hardening concepts to understand is that memory should
never be both writable and executable, otherwise an attacker can use it to
load and run arbitrary code.  That rule is generally followed in Linux
systems, but there is a glaring loophole that is exploitable from user
space to inject code into a running process.  Attackers have duly exploited
it.  A new effort to close the hole ran into trouble early in the merge
window, but a solution may yet be found in time for the 6.11 kernel
release.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983169/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] What became of getrandom() in the vDSO</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983186/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/980447/">the previous episode</a> of the
<tt>vgetrandom()</tt> story, Jason Donenfeld had put together a version of
the <a
href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man2/getrandom.2.html"><tt>getrandom()</tt></a>
system call that ran in user space, significantly improving performance for
applications that need a lot of random data while retaining all of the
guarantees provided by the system call.  At that time, it seemed that a
consensus had built around the implementation and that it was headed toward
the mainline in that form.  A few milliseconds after that article was
posted, though, a Linus-Torvalds-shaped obstacle appeared in its path.
That obstacle has been overcome and this work has now been merged for the
6.11 kernel, but its form has changed somewhat.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983186/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 16:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] More informative kernel panics for Fedora</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982398/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
On July 12, Jocelyn Falempe
<a href="https://discussion.fedoraproject.org/t/f42-change-proposal-enable-drm-panic-system-wide/125542">
proposed</a> a change to the configuration options that Fedora sets for its
kernels, in order to make kernel panics easier to report.
Falempe would like to enable the kernel's recently added
DRM-panic feature, which adds
a graphical crash screen that is reminiscent of the infamous
Windows "blue screen of death" for kernel panics. The feature introduces a few
tradeoffs, including currently limited driver support, so the proposal spawned a
good deal of discussion.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982398/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 15:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Firefox support added to Puppeteer</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984733/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Mozilla has <a href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2024/08/puppeteer-support-for-firefox/">announced</a> that <a href="https://pptr.dev/">Puppeteer</a>, a browser automation and testing library, now has first-class support for Firefox using the
<a href="https://w3c.github.io/webdriver-bidi/">WebDriver BiDi</a> protocol. Puppeteer can be used to drive headless browser instances, and is commonly used for automated end-to-end web site tests.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Whilst the features offered by Puppeteer won't be a surprise,
bringing support to multiple browsers has been a significant
undertaking. The Firefox support is not based on a Firefox-specific
automation protocol, but on WebDriver BiDi, a cross browser protocol
that's undergoing standardization at the W3C, and currently has
implementation in both Gecko and Chromium. This use of a
cross-browser protocol should make it much easier to support many
different browsers going forward.  
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984733/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 19:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984702/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (firefox-esr, openjdk-17, and wpa), <b>Gentoo</b> (aiohttp, Bitcoin, Cairo, Go, json-c, Levenshtein, libXpm, nghttp2, PostgreSQL, and Redis), <b>Red Hat</b> (kernel, kernel-rt, python-setuptools, python-urllib3, python3.11-setuptools, and wget), <b>Slackware</b> (mozilla), <b>SUSE</b> (bind, curl, docker, ffmpeg, ffmpeg-4, kernel, kernel-firmware, libnbd, patch, shadow, and thunderbird), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (python-django and wpa).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984702/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 13:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Firefox 129.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984617/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/129.0/releasenotes/">Version
129.0</a> of the Firefox browser has been released.  Changes include some
improvements to the reader mode, tab previews, and use of HTTPS by default.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984617/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 14:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984598/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (libreoffice), <b>Gentoo</b> (containerd and firefox), <b>Red Hat</b> (httpd), <b>SUSE</b> (ca-certificates-mozilla, ksh, openssl-3-livepatches, podman, python-Twisted, and skopeo), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (imagemagick).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984598/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 13:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>GNU Binutils 2.43 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984539/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Version 2.43 of the GNU Binutils package is out.  Changes include some
improvements to the assembler and the linker, better support for hardware
event counters in the Gprofng profiler, and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984539/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 14:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984552/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (openjdk-11), <b>Fedora</b> (bind, bind-dyndb-ldap, chromium, ffmpeg, hostapd, trafficserver, and wpa_supplicant), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (curl and linux-oem-6.5).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984552/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 14:26:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.11-rc2</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984501/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has released <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/984500/">6.11-rc2</a> for testing.
"<q>Hopefully we've gotten rid of the bulk of the silly noise here in rc2,
and not added too much new noise, so that we can get on with the process of
finding more meaningful issues.</q>"]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984501/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Three stable kernel updates for Saturday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984448/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/984449/">6.10.3</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/984450/">6.6.44</a>, and <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/984451/">6.1.103</a> stable kernel updates have all been released. As usual, they
contain important fixes throughout the tree. Users of those kernels
should upgrade.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984448/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 13:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/984370/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (chromium), <b>SUSE</b> (docker and patch), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (bind9, gross, linux-azure, linux-azure-4.15, linux-lowlatency-hwe-6.5, and tomcat8, tomcat9).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/984370/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 13:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>