<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 05:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 05:48:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for September 5, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987605/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for September 5, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987605/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Whither the Apple AGX graphics driver?</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/988438/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Much of the early Rust code for the kernel has taken the form of
reimplementations of existing drivers as a proof of concept.  One project,
though, is entirely new: the driver for Apple GPUs written by Asahi Lina.
This driver has shipped with <a href="https://asahilinux.org/">Asahi
Linux</a> for some time and, by many accounts, is stable, usable, and a
shining example of how Rust can be used in a complex kernel subsystem.
That driver remains outside of the mainline kernel, though, and merging
currently looks like a distant prospect.  The reasons for that state of
affairs highlight some of the difficulties inherent in integrating a new
language (and its associated development style) into the Linux kernel.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/988438/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 13:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Transcribing audio with AI using Speech Note</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987315/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>One of the joys of writing about technology is the opportunity to
cover interesting talks on open&#8209;source and free&#8209;software topics. One
of the pains is creating transcriptions of said talks, or continually
referring back to a recording, to be able to write about
them. <a href="https://github.com/mkiol/dsnote">Speech Note</a> is an
open-source application that uses machine-learning models, running locally, to
translate speech to text and take the pain out of transcription. It
also handles text to speech, and language translations. While not
perfect, its transcriptions are better than one might expect, even when
handling jargon, accents, and less-than-perfect audio.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987315/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 15:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Advances in font technology and GTK text rendering</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987176/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>At this year's <a href="https://events.gnome.org/event/209/">GUADEC</a> in Denver, Colorado, Behdad Esfahbod and Matthias Clasen
presented a <a href="https://events.gnome.org/event/209/contributions/749/">two-part talk</a> on a topic that's deeply important to desktop
environments: fonts. Esfahbod covered advances in font
technology that are making their way to becoming standards, and Clasen briefly
discussed improvements in GTK text rendering. The talk presented some
fascinating insights into the problems around accurately rendering
writing systems on the desktop, and where font technologies may be
going in the near future.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987176/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 15:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A SpamAssassin surprise</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/987566/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Here is a piece of advice for anybody wanting an easy and frustration-free
life: do not run your own email system.  While there numerous advantages to
keeping some control over your communications, there is also a long list of
things that can go wrong.  A recent failure of spam filtering on the LWN
email system illustrated one of those ways, as well as shining a light on
how even a seemingly independent email system is tied to other services
across the net.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/987566/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 14:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Plasma Mobile for highly configurable Linux phones</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/986899/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://plasma-mobile.org">Plasma Mobile</a> is an open-source
user interface for mobile devices, developed by the KDE community. It's
built on the same foundations as <a
href="https://kde.org/plasma-desktop/">Plasma Desktop</a>, including <a
href="https://develop.kde.org/products/frameworks/">KDE Frameworks</a> and the <a
href="https://invent.kde.org/plasma/kwin#kwin">KWin</a> window
manager. Much like its desktop counterpart, Plasma Mobile caters to
advanced users by offering extensive customizability. It is offered as an
option on phones with <a href="https://plasma-mobile.org/get/">various mobile Linux
distributions</a>.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/986899/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 15:11:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989772/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (389-ds:1.4, dovecot, emacs, and glib2), <b>Fedora</b> (bluez, iwd, libell, linux-firmware, seamonkey, vim, and wireshark), <b>Mageia</b> (apr, libtiff, Nginx, openssl, orc, unbound, webmin, and zziplib), <b>Red Hat</b> (389-ds:1.4), and <b>SUSE</b> (containerd, curl, go1.22, go1.23, gstreamer-plugins-bad, kernel, ntpd-rs, python-Django, and python311).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989772/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 13:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Pandoc 3.4 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989660/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a
href="https://pandoc.org/releases.html#pandoc-3.4-2024-09-09">Version
3.4</a> of the <a href="https://pandoc.org/">Pandoc</a>
document-conversion tool has been released. Notable changes in this
release include a new ANSI output format (for console output), a <a
href="https://github.com/jgm/pandoc/issues/10142">switch</a> to  <a
href="https://weasyprint.org/">WeasyPrint</a> as the PDF engine for
HTML to PDF conversion, the ability to position captions
above or below tables and figures, and much more.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989660/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 18:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Radicle 1.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989605/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://radicle.xyz/2024/09/10/radicle-1.0.html">Version 1.0</a>
of the Radicle development platform has been released.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Radicle 1.0 represents the culmination of years of experimentation
	and hard work from our team and community, where we set out to
	ensure that free and open source software ecosystems can flourish
	without having to rely on the whims of Big Tech. We designed
	Radicle with a first-principles approach, as a natural extension to
	Git, expanding it to work in a collaborative, local-first,
	peer-to-peer setting.
</blockquote>
<p>
LWN <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/966869/">looked at Radicle</a> in March.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989605/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 13:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989602/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (cacti), <b>Fedora</b> (aardvark-dns, expat, and firefox), <b>Mageia</b> (ffmpeg, ntfs-3g, and vim), <b>Oracle</b> (emacs, glib2, java-11-openjdk, and qt5-qtbase), <b>Red Hat</b> (emacs, python-setuptools, python3.11, python3.11-setuptools, python3.12-setuptools, python3.9, and python39:3.9), <b>Slackware</b> (netatalk), <b>SUSE</b> (buildah, expat, java-1_8_0-ibm, kanidm, kernel, and postgresql16), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (netty, php7.0, php7.2, tiff, and webkit2gtk).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989602/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 12:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Redox OS 0.9.0</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989517/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.redox-os.org/news/release-0.9.0/">Version
0.9.0</a> of <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/979524/">Redox OS</a>,
an open-source, Unix-like operating system written in
Rust, has been released. Notable changes in this release include
performance and stability improvements, better management of physical
and virtual memory, bootloader improvements, and more. It also brings
support for RustPython, Perl 5, Simple HTTP Server, the addition of
several applications including GNU Nano, Helix, and the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/984638/">COSMIC</a>
Files, Editor, and Terminal applications. See the <a
href="https://www.redox-os.org/news/release-0.9.0/#changelog">changelog
section of the announcement</a> for a full list of changes in the release.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989517/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 19:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989488/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (amanda, aom, bluez, python-jwcrypto, and thunderbird), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, firefox, and thunderbird), <b>Red Hat</b> (bubblewrap and flatpak, containernetworking-plugins, flatpak, and runc), <b>Slackware</b> (python3), <b>SUSE</b> (apache2, bubblewrap and flatpak, postgresql16, and wireshark), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (thunderbird).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989488/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:17:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Adams: Linux&apos;s bedtime routine</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989489/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Jacob Adams <a
href="https://tookmund.com/2024/09/hibernation-preparation">wanders into
the kernel's hibernation code</a>:
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	How does Linux move from an awake machine to a hibernating one? How
	does it then manage to restore all state? These questions led me to
	read way too much C in trying to figure out how this particular
	hardware/software boundary is navigated.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989489/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:20:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.11-rc7</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989426/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Linus has released <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/989425/">6.11-rc7</a> for testing.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	And I wish I could say that things have calmed down, but I can't
	really say that. In fact, rc7 is slightly bigger than both rc6 and
	rc5 were, both in number of commits, and in actual diff
	size. That's not really how it should work out.
<p>
	That said, there's nothing *scary* in here. 
</blockquote>
<p>
He is apparently "<q>still waffling</q>" about whether to release 6.11 next
weekend, which would cause the 6.12 merge window to land on top of the
Maintainers Summit, Linux Plumbers Conference, and Open Source Summit.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989426/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 22:33:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Three weekend stable kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989409/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/989410/">6.10.9</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/989411/">6.6.50</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/989412/">6.1.109</a>
stable kernel updates have been released; each contains another set of
important fixes.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989409/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 16:08:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>NGINX has moved to Github</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989229/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://nginx.org/">NGINX</a> team has <a
href="https://mailman.nginx.org/pipermail/nginx-announce/2024/ITL3AOQSAJANFJXMM3VOVOIGOUADWFFK.html">announced</a>
that official NGINX open-source development has moved away from
<a href="http://hg.nginx.org/nginx.org">Mercurial</a> to <a href="https://github.com/nginx/nginx">GitHub</a>, and
the project will now be taking <a
href="https://github.com/nginx/nginx/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md">contributions</a>
in the form of pull requests:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>Additionally, starting today, we will begin accepting bugs reports,
feature requests and enhancements directly through GitHub, under the
"Issues" tab. Moreover, we've moved our community forums to the GitHub
"Discussions" area, where you will now be able
to engage in conversation, ask, and answer questions.</p>

<p>[...] We understand that changes like these may require adjustment,
so to give you more time, we will continue accepting patches and
provide community support via mailing lists until December 31st, 2024.</p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989229/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 17:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Man pages maintenance suspended</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989215/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Alejandro Colomar, who has been maintaining the Linux man pages for the
last four years, has <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/4d7tq6a7febsoru3wjium4ekttuw2ouocv6jstdkthnacmzr6x@f2zfbe5hs7h5">announced</a>
that he will have to stop that work.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	 I've been doing it in my free time, and no company has sponsored
	 that work at all.  At the moment, I cannot sustain this work
	 economically any more, and will temporarily and indefinitely stop
	 working on this project.  If any company has interests in the
	 future of the project, I'd welcome an offer to sponsor my work
	 here; if so, please let me know.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989215/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 14:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The realtime preemption end game — for real this time</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989212/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Work on realtime preemption for the Linux kernel <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/106010/">got its start</a> almost exactly 20&nbsp;years ago
(though it had its roots in earlier work, of course).  It is fair to say
that finishing that job has taken a bit longer than anybody involved would
have expected.  Now, though, Sebastian Andrzej Siewior has <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20240906111841.562402-1-bigeasy@linutronix.de">posted a brief
patch series</a> making it possible to enable realtime preemption in the
mainline kernel on three architectures.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	With the printk bits merged, PREEMPT_RT could be enabled on X86,
	ARM64 and Risc-V. These three architectures merged required changes
	over the years leaving me in a position where I have no essential
	changes in the queue that would affect them.
</blockquote>
<p>
Congratulations are due to the many developers who have worked on this
project for the last two decades.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989212/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 14:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989196/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (bubblewrap, flatpak), <b>Debian</b> (libxml2), <b>Fedora</b> (lua-mpack, mingw-python3, python-django, python-django4.2, python3.11, python3.13, and python3.9), <b>Oracle</b> (bubblewrap, flatpak), <b>Red Hat</b> (fence-agents, python-urllib3, resource-agents, and wget), <b>Slackware</b> (expat and mozilla), <b>SUSE</b> (buildah, chromium, firefox, gradle, java-1_8_0-ibm, kubernetes1.26, postgresql16, python-Django, python312-pip, and systemd), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (python-aiohttp).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989196/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 13:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rust 1.81.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989106/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2024/09/05/Rust-1.81.0.html">Version
1.81.0</a> of the Rust language has been released.  Changes include the
stabilization of the <tt>Error</tt> trait in <tt>core</tt>, some new sort
algorithms, some linting improvements, and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989106/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 17:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989046/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (bubblewrap and flatpak, containernetworking-plugins, fence-agents, ghostscript, krb5, orc, podman, python3.11, python3.9, resource-agents, runc, and wget), <b>Debian</b> (chromium, cinder, glance, gnutls28, nova, nsis, python-oslo.utils, ruby-sinatra, and setuptools), <b>Fedora</b> (kernel), <b>Oracle</b> (bubblewrap and flatpak, buildah, containernetworking-plugins, fence-agents, ghostscript, gvisor-tap-vsock, kernel, krb5, libndp, nodejs:18, orc, podman, postgresql, python-urllib3, python3.11, python3.12, python3.9, runc, skopeo, and wget), <b>SUSE</b> (hdf5, netcdf, trilinos), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (firefox, imagemagick, ironic, openssl, python-django, vim, and znc).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989046/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Samba 4.21.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/989047/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Version 4.21.0 of the Samba Windows interoperability suite has been
released.  Changes include some authentication hardening, a number of LDAP
improvements, per-user and per-group veto and hide files, group-managed
service accounts, and quite a bit more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/989047/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>