<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 07:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 3 May 2024 08:11:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>A new set of stable kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972209/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Greg Kroah-Hartman has announced the release of the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/972210/">6.8.9</a>, <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/972211/">6.6.30</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/972212/">6.1.90</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/972213/">5.15.158</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/972214/">5.10.216</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/972215/">5.4.275</a>, and <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/972216/">4.19.313</a> stable kernels.  As is the norm, they
contain lots of important fixes throughout the kernel tree.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972209/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 15:16:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rust 1.78.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972191/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2024/05/02/Rust-1.78.0.html">Version
1.78.0</a> of the Rust language has been released.  Changes include a new
mechanism for diagnostic attributes, changes to how assertions around
<tt>unsafe</tt> blocks are handled, and more.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Rust now supports a <tt>#[diagnostic]</tt> attribute namespace to
	influence compiler error messages. These are treated as hints which
	the compiler is not required to use, and it is also not an error to
	provide a diagnostic that the compiler doesn't recognize. This
	flexibility allows source code to provide diagnostics even when
	they're not supported by all compilers, whether those are different
	versions or entirely different implementations.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972191/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 14:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972186/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (chromium and distro-info-data), <b>Fedora</b> (et, php-tcpdf, python-aiohttp, python-openapi-core, thunderbird, tpm2-tools, and tpm2-tss), <b>Red Hat</b> (nodejs:16 and podman), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (firefox).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972186/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 14:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for April 25, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970328/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for April 25, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970328/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 01:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Existential types in Rust</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970186/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
For several years, contributors to the Rust project have
been working to improve support for asynchronous
code. The benefits of these efforts are not confined to asynchronous code,
however. Members of the Rust community have been working toward adding explicit
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Type_system#Existential_types">
existential types</a> to Rust since 2017. Existential types are not a common feature
of programming languages (something
<a href="https://rust-lang.github.io/rfcs/2515-type_alias_impl_trait.html">
the RFC</a> acknowledges), so the motivation for their inclusion might be somewhat
obscure.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970186/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A change in direction for security-module stacking?</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970070/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The long-running effort to complete the work on stacking (or composing) the
Linux security modules (LSMs) recently encountered a barrier—in the form of
a "suggestion" to discontinue it from Linus Torvalds.  His complaint
revolved around the indirect function calls that are used to implement
LSMs, but he also did not think much of the effort to switch away from
those calls.  While it does not appear that a major course-change is in store
for LSMs, it is clear that Torvalds is not happy with the direction of that
subsystem.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970070/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 17:50:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Rust for embedded Linux kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970216/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The Rust programming language, it is hoped, will bring a new level of
safety to the Linux kernel.  At the moment, though, there are still a
number of impediments to getting useful Rust code into the kernel.  In the
Embedded Open Source Summit track of the <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/open-source-summit-north-america/">Open
Source Summit North America</a>, Fabien Parent provided an overview of his
work aimed at improving the infrastructure needed to write the device
drivers needed by embedded systems in Rust; there is still some work to be
done.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970216/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 13:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Linus and Dirk chat about AI, XZ, hardware, and more</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970293/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>One of the mainstays of the the Linux Foundation's Open Source Summit is the "fireside chat"
(sans fire) between Linus Torvalds and Dirk Hohndel to discuss open source and
Linux kernel topics of the day. On April 17, at <a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/open-source-summit-north-america/">Open Source Summit
North America</a> (OSSNA) in Seattle, Washington, they held with tradition
and discussed a range of topics including proper whitespace parsing,
security, and the current AI craze.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970293/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 17:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Weighted memory interleaving and new system calls</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/969379/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Gregory Price recently posted
<a href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-kernel/20231223181101.1954-1-gregory.price@memverge.com/">
a patch set</a> that adds support for weighted memory interleaving — allowing a
process's memory to be distributed between
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-uniform_memory_access">
non-uniform memory access</a> (NUMA)
nodes in a more controlled way.
According to his performance measurements, the patch set could provide a
significant improvement for computers with network-attached memory.
The patch set also
introduces new system calls and paves the way for future extensions
intended to give processes more control over their own memory.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/969379/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 14:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Gentoo bans AI-created contributions</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/970072/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://wiki.gentoo.org/wiki/Project:Council">Gentoo Council</a> member Michał Górny <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/gentoo-dev/a2b8c68b1649213cf237f40e41f9a460a5667c34.camel@gentoo.org/">posted</a>
an RFC to the gentoo-dev mailing
list in late February about banning "<q>'AI'-backed (LLM/GPT/whatever)
contributions</q>" to the Gentoo Linux project. Górny wrote that the spread of the
"<q>AI&nbsp;bubble</q>" indicated a need for Gentoo to formally take a stand on AI
tools. After a lengthy discussion, the Gentoo Council <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/gentoo-dev/f56698adfcd7eae64a82d1b367e8af71a1261819.camel%40gentoo.org/">voted</a>
unanimously this week to adopt his proposal and ban contributions generated with AI/ML tools.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/970072/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 15:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Warning about WARN_ON()</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/969923/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Kernel developers, like conscientious developers for many projects, will
often include checks in the code for conditions that are never expected to
occur, but which would indicate a serious problem should that expectation
turn out to be incorrect.  For years, developers have been encouraged (to
put it politely) to avoid using assertions that crash the machine for such
conditions unless there is truly no alternative.  Increasingly, though, use
of the kernel's <tt>WARN_ON()</tt> family of macros, which developers were
told to use instead, is also being discouraged.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/969923/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 14:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>GNU nano 8.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971980/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Version 8.0 of the terminal text editor <a href="https://www.nano-editor.org/">GNU nano</a> has been
released. This update includes several changes to keybindings to be
more newcomer-friendly, such as remapping Ctrl-F to forward-search and
adding an option for modern bindings:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Command-line option --modernbindings (-/) makes ^Q quit, ^X cut,
   ^C copy, ^V paste, ^Z undo, ^Y redo, ^O open a file, ^W write a
   file, ^R replace, ^G find again, ^D find again backwards, ^A set
   the mark, ^T jump to a line, ^P show the position, and ^E execute.
</blockquote>

<p>The release also provides access to 14 levels of gray scale in xterm (up
from four), as well as many bug fixes.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971980/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 17:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Dolstra steps down from NixOS Foundation board</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971973/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
The NixOS Foundation board
<a href="https://discourse.nixos.org/t/nixos-foundation-board-giving-power-to-the-community/44552">
announced</a> on April 30 that Eelco Dolstra is stepping down from the board
following the <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/970824/">recent calls for his resignation</a>.
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Eelco is the principal author of Nix and undoubtedly a central figure in the
ecosystem that grew around it. We confirm that Eelco showed no intention to be
perceived as or act like the BDFL [Benevolent Dictator for Life]
of the Nix ecosystem, or the Nix code base. To
commit to that in a timely manner, he has decided to formally step down from the
board.
</blockquote>

<p>
The board also announced their intent to set up new, explicit governance for the
project, answerable to the community:
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
We will appoint a constitutional assembly within the next 14 days.
Its task will be to set up a new governance structure, run by the
community, that is capable of serving the community's needs. Once
established, we will delegate our power to institutions within that
new structure. This entire process will take place in a public space,
such that it's traceable for anyone concerned. We are committed to
listening to everyone who may help with solving the problems the
community is facing.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971973/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 14:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972029/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (nghttp2 and qtbase-opensource-src), <b>Mageia</b> (cjson, freerdp, guava, krb5, libarchive, and mediawiki), <b>Oracle</b> (container-tools:4.0 and container-tools:ol8), <b>Red Hat</b> (bind, buildah, container-tools:3.0, container-tools:rhel8, expat, gnutls, golang, grafana, kernel, kernel-rt, libreswan, libvirt, linux-firmware, mod_http2, pcp, pcs, podman, python-jwcrypto, rhc-worker-script, shadow-utils, skopeo, sssd, tigervnc, unbound, and yajl), <b>SUSE</b> (kernel and python311), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (gerbv and node-json5).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972029/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 13:36:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Yocto Project 5.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971785/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Version
5.0 of the <a href="https://www.yoctoproject.org/">Yocto Project</a>
distribution builder has been released.  The list of new features is long;
see <a
href="http://downloads.yoctoproject.org/releases/yocto/yocto-5.0/RELEASENOTES">the
release notes</a> for the details.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971785/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 14:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>&quot;run0&quot; as a sudo replacement</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971745/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://mastodon.social/@pid_eins/112353324518585654">This
Mastodon stream</a> from Lennart Poettering describes a <tt>sudo</tt>
replacement — called <tt>run0</tt> — that will be part of the upcoming
systemd 256 release.  It takes a rather different approach to the execution
of privileged commands, avoiding the use of setuid (which he calls "SUID")
permissions entirely.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	So, in my ideal world, we'd have an OS entirely without SUID. Let's
	throw out the concept of SUID on the dump of UNIX' bad ideas. An
	execution context for privileged code that is half under the
	control of unprivileged code and that needs careful manual clean-up
	is just not how security engineering should be done in 2024
	anymore.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971745/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 14:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971740/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (org-mode), <b>Oracle</b> (shim and tigervnc), <b>Red Hat</b> (ansible-core, avahi, buildah, container-tools:4.0, containernetworking-plugins, edk2, exfatprogs, fence-agents, file, freeglut, freerdp, frr, grub2, gstreamer1-plugins-bad-free, gstreamer1-plugins-base, gstreamer1-plugins-good, harfbuzz, httpd, ipa, kernel, libjpeg-turbo, libnbd, LibRaw, libsndfile, libssh, libtiff, libvirt, libX11, libXpm, mingw components, mingw-glib2, mingw-pixman, mod_http2, mod_jk and mod_proxy_cluster, motif, mutt, openssl and openssl-fips-provider, osbuild and osbuild-composer, pam, pcp, pcs, perl, pmix, podman, python-jinja2, python3.11, python3.11-cryptography, python3.11-urllib3, qemu-kvm, qt5-qtbase, runc, skopeo, squashfs-tools, systemd, tcpdump, tigervnc, toolbox, traceroute, webkit2gtk3, wpa_supplicant, xorg-x11-server, xorg-x11-server-Xwayland, and zziplib), <b>SUSE</b> (docker, ffmpeg, ffmpeg-4, frr, and kernel), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (anope, freerdp3, and php7.0, php7.2, php7.4, php8.1).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971740/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 13:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Git 2.45.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971742/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://lwn.net/ml/git/xmqq8r0ww0sj.fsf@gitster.g/">Version 2.45.0</a> of the Git
source-code management system has been released.  Changes include a new
<tt>list</tt> command for <tt>git&nbsp;reflog</tt>, a couple of new
configuration variables for <tt>git&nbsp;diff</tt>, the ability to drop
redundant commits while cherry-picking, a number of performance
improvements, and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971742/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 13:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Amarok 3.0 &quot;Castaway&quot; released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971568/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://apps.kde.org/amarok/">Amarok</a> music player project
has <a
href="https://blogs.kde.org/2024/04/29/amarok-3.0-castaway-released/">announced</a>
the release of version&nbsp;3.0, which is codenamed "Castaway".  It is the first
stable version using Qt&nbsp;5 and KDE Frameworks&nbsp;5, and the first stable
release since the final Qt-4-based&nbsp;2.9.0 in 2018.
<blockquote class="bq">
The road to 3.0 has not been a short one. Much of the Qt5/KF5 porting was done in 2015 already, but finishing and polishing everything up has been a slow, sometimes ongoing and sometimes stalled process ever since. 3.0 Alpha was released in February 2021 and has been since used by many people, as have been nightly builds of git master available for various distributions. Now in the past few months, an effort was made to get everything ready for a proper 3.0 release.
<p>
Common usecases should work quite well, and in addition to fixing KF5 port
related regressions reported in pre-releases, 3.0 features many bugfixes
and implemented features for longstanding issues, the oldest such
documented being from 2009. However, with more than 20 years of development
history, it is likely that not every feature Amarok has been tested
thoroughly in the new release, and specifically some Internet services that
have changed their API in recent years are not available, at least for
now. It might well be that getting them in better state wouldn't require
huge effort, however, so if you know your way with Qt and KDE Frameworks
and your favourite Internet music service does not work with Amarok 3.0,
you are extremely welcome to join in and help!
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971568/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 20:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971487/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (buildah, go-toolset:rhel8, golang, java-11-openjdk, java-21-openjdk, libreswan, thunderbird, and tigervnc), <b>Debian</b> (chromium, emacs, frr, mediawiki, ruby-rack, trafficserver, and zabbix), <b>Fedora</b> (chromium, grub2, python-idna, and python-reportlab), <b>Mageia</b> (chromium-browser-stable, firefox, opencryptoki, and thunderbird), <b>Red Hat</b> (container-tools:4.0, container-tools:rhel8, git-lfs, and shim), <b>SUSE</b> (frr, java-11-openjdk, java-1_8_0-openjdk, kernel, pdns-recursor, and shim), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (apache2, cpio, curl, glibc, gnutls28, less, libvirt, and pillow).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971487/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 13:44:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>McQueen: Update from the GNOME board</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971436/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Robert McQueen has posted <a
href="https://ramcq.net/2024/04/26/update-from-the-gnome-board/">a message
from the GNOME Foundation board</a> describing the current financial
situation, plans to improve it, and an increase in the size of the board.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	The Foundation has a reserves policy which specifies a minimum
	amount of money we have to keep in our accounts. This is so that if
	there is a significant interruption to our usual income, we can
	preserve our core operations while we work on new funding
	sources. We've now "hit the buffers" of this reserves policy,
	meaning the Board can't approve any more deficit budgets – to keep
	spending at the same level we must increase our income.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971436/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 13:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kernel prepatch 6.9-rc6</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971414/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/971413/">6.9-rc6</a> kernel prepatch is out for
testing.
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	Things continue to look pretty normal, and nothing here really
	stands out. The biggest single change that stands out in the
	diffstat is literally a documentation update, everything else looks
	pretty small and spread out.
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971414/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 22:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Four weekend stable kernel releases</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971361/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/971362/">6.8.8</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/971363/">6.6.29</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/971364/">6.1.88</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/971365/">5.15.157</a>
stable kernels have been released; each contains another set of important
fixes.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971361/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 16:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/971289/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Debian</b> (knot-resolver, pdns-recursor, and putty), <b>Fedora</b> (xen), <b>Mageia</b> (editorconfig-core-c, glibc, mbedtls, webkit2, and wireshark), <b>Oracle</b> (buildah), <b>Red Hat</b> (buildah and yajl), <b>Slackware</b> (libarchive), <b>SUSE</b> (dcmtk, openCryptoki, php7, php74, php8, python-gunicorn, python-idna, qemu, and thunderbird), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (cryptojs, freerdp2, nghttp2, and zabbix).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/971289/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 13:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>