<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>LWN.net</title>
        <link>https://lwn.net</link>
        <description>LWN.net is a comprehensive source of news and opinions from
        and about the Linux community.  This is the main LWN.net feed,
        listing all articles which are posted to the site front page.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>lwn@lwn.net</webMaster>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 13:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 13:33:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <atom:link href="https://lwn.net/headlines/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml">
        </atom:link>
        <item>
            <title>Stable kernel updates for Saturday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983652/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983653/">6.10.2</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983654/">6.9.12</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983655/">6.6.43</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983656/">6.1.102</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983657/">5.15.164</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983658/">5.10.223</a>,
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983659/">5.4.281</a>, and
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983660/">4.19.319</a>
stable kernel updates have all been released; each contains a relatively
small set of important fixes, <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/linux-kernel/20240723-fs-lock-recover-compatfix-v1-1-148096719529@google.com/">at
least one of which</a> appears to close a security hole.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983652/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Friday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983523/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (linux-firmware and squid), <b>Debian</b> (bind9), <b>Fedora</b> (kubernetes, thunderbird, and tinyproxy), <b>Oracle</b> (containernetworking-plugins, cups, edk2, httpd, httpd:2.4, kernel, kernel-container, libreoffice, libuv, libvirt, python3, and runc), <b>Red Hat</b> (freeradius:3.0, httpd, and squid), and <b>SUSE</b> (giflib and python-dnspython).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983523/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 13:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rust 1.80.0 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983265/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2024/07/25/Rust-1.80.0.html">Version
1.80.0</a> of the Rust language has been released.  Changes include the new
<tt>LazyCell</tt> and <tt>LazyLock</tt> types (which delay data
initialization until the first access), the stabilization of the
exclusive-range syntax for <tt>match</tt> patterns, and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983265/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 14:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Three new stable kernels</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983331/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983332/">6.9.11</a>, <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983333/">6.6.42</a>, and <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983335/">6.1.101</a> stable kernels have been released.  As
usual, they contain important fixes throughout the tree.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983331/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 14:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Linux Mint 22 &quot;Wilma&quot; released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983301/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Linux Mint has <a
href="https://blog.linuxmint.com/?p=4731">announced</a> version 22 of
the distribution in three editions: Cinnamon, MATE, and Xfce. Mint 22
is based on Ubuntu 24.04 and uses kernel version 6.8.0:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
Linux Mint 22 is a long term support release which will be supported
until 2029. It comes with updated software and brings refinements and
many new features to make your desktop even more comfortable to use.
</blockquote>

<p>LWN <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/981130/">covered</a> the
Linux Mint 22 beta in early July. See the <a
href="https://www.linuxmint.com/rel_wilma_whatsnew.php">new
features</a> page and <a
href="https://www.linuxmint.com/rel_wilma.php">release notes</a> for
more information on this release.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983301/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 13:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Thursday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983328/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>AlmaLinux</b> (containernetworking-plugins, cups, edk2, httpd, httpd:2.4, libreoffice, libuv, libvirt, python3, and runc), <b>Fedora</b> (exim, python-zipp, xdg-desktop-portal-hyprland, and xmedcon), <b>Red Hat</b> (cups, fence-agents, freeradius, freeradius:3.0, httpd:2.4, kernel, kernel-rt, nodejs:18, podman, and resource-agents), <b>Slackware</b> (htdig and libxml2), <b>SUSE</b> (exim), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (ocsinventory-server, php-cas, and poppler).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983328/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 14:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] LWN.net Weekly Edition for July 18, 2024</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981628/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The LWN.net Weekly Edition for July 18, 2024 is available.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981628/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Changing the filesystem-maintenance model</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981854/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Maintenance of the kernel is a difficult, often thankless, task; how it is
being handled, the role of maintainers, burnout, and so on are recurring
topics at kernel-related conferences.  At
the 2024 <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a>, Josef Bacik and
Christian Brauner led a session to discuss possible changes to the way
filesystems are maintained, though Bacik took the lead role (and the podium).  There are a number of interrelated topics,
including merging new filesystems, removing old ones, making and testing changes
throughout the filesystem tree, and more.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981854/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 14:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] SUSE asks openSUSE to consider name change</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981018/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.suse.com/">SUSE</a> has, in a somewhat clumsy
fashion, asked <a href="https://www.opensuse.org/">openSUSE</a>
to consider rebranding to clear up confusion over the
relationship between SUSE the company and openSUSE as a community
project. That, in turn, has opened conversations about revising
openSUSE governance and more. So far, there is no concrete proposal to
consider, no timeline, or even a process for the community and company
to follow to make any decisions.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981018/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 16:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Hierarchical storage management, fanotify, FUSE, and more</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981392/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Amir Goldstein led a filesystem-track session at the 2024 <a
href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lsfmmbpf/">Linux Storage,
Filesystem, Memory Management, and BPF Summit</a> on his project to build a
<a
href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hierarchical_storage_management">hierarchical
storage management</a> (HSM) system using <a
href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/latest/admin-guide/filesystem-monitoring.html">fanotify</a>.
The idea is to monitor file access in order to determine when to retrieve
content from non-local storage (e.g. the cloud).  The session was a
follow-up to last year's <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/932415/">introduction to the
project</a>, which covered some of the problems he had encountered; this
year, he
was updating attendees on its status and progress, along with some other
problem areas that he wanted to discuss.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981392/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 14:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A hash table by any other name</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/972580/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
On June 25, Matthew Wilcox posted
<a href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/20240625211803.2750563-1-willy@infradead.org/">
a second version of a patch set</a>
introducing a new
data structure called rosebush, which
"<q>is a resizing, scalable, cache-aware, RCU optimised hash
table.</q>" The kernel already has generic hash tables, though, including
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/751374/">rhashtable</a>. Wilcox believes that the design of
rhashtable is not the best choice for performance, and has written rosebush as
an alternative for use in the
<a href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/latest/filesystems/vfs.html#directory-entry-cache-dcache">
directory-entry cache</a> (dcache) — the filesystem cache used to speed up
file-name lookup.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/972580/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 17:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Development statistics for the 6.10 kernel</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981559/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The 6.10 kernel was <a
href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/CAHk-=wjV_O2g_K19McjGKrxFxMFDqex+fyGcKc3uac1ft_O2gg@mail.gmail.com/">released</a>
on July&nbsp;14 after a nine-week development cycle.  This time around,
13,312 non-merge changesets were pulled into the mainline repository — the
lowest changeset count since 5.17 in early 2022.  Longstanding tradition
says that it is time for LWN to gather some statistics on where the new
code for 6.10 came from and how it got to the mainline; read on for the
details.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981559/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 15:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] A look at Linux Mint 22</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981130/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Linux Mint has <a
href="https://blog.linuxmint.com/?p=4725">released</a> a beta of its
next long-term-support (LTS) release, Linux&nbsp;Mint&nbsp;22 (code-named "Wilma"), based on <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/971143/">Ubuntu&nbsp;24.04</a>. Aside from the standard
software updates that come with any major upgrade, some of Wilma's
largest selling points are what it <em>doesn't</em> have; namely snap
packages or GNOME applications that have broken theming on non-GNOME
desktops like Mint's Cinnamon desktop.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981130/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 14:32:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Nix alternatives and spinoffs</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981124/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Since the
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/970824/">
disagreements</a> that led to Eelco Dolstra
<a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/971973/">
stepping down from the NixOS
Foundation board</a>, there have been a number of projects forked from or inspired
by
<a href="https://nixos.org/">
Nix</a> that have stepped up to compete with it. Two months on, some of these
projects are now well-established enough to look at what they have to offer and
how they compare to each other. Overall, users have a number of good options to
choose from, whether they're seeking a compatible replacement for Nix (the
configuration language and package manager) or NixOS (the Linux distribution),
or something that takes the same ideas in a different direction.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981124/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 16:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[$] Reports from OSPM 2024, part 1</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/981371/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[The sixth edition of the <a
href="https://retis.sssup.it/ospm-summit/">Power Management and Scheduling
in the Linux Kernel (OSPM) Summit</a> took place on May 30-31 2024, and was
graciously hosted by the <a href="https://www.irit.fr/en/home">Institut de
Recherche en Informatique de Toulouse (IRIT)</a> in Toulouse, France.  This
is the first of a series of articles describing the discussions held at
OSPM 2024; topics covered include latency hints, energy-aware scheduling,
ChromeOS, and user-space schedulers.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/981371/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 14:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Stable kernel update 6.10.1</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983153/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Greg Kroah-Hartman has released the <a
href="https://lwn.net/Articles/983154/">6.10.1</a> stable kernel update. This release
contains a small number of seemingly urgent regression fixes. Users of
this kernel series are advised to upgrade.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983153/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 17:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>OpenMandriva ROME 24.07 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983133/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Updated installation images for the <a
href="https://www.openmandriva.org/">OpenMandriva</a> ROME rolling release Linux distribution are <a
href="https://www.openmandriva.org/en/news/article/openmandriva-rome-24-07-released">now available</a>. Notable features in the
24.07 snapshot include KDE&nbsp;Plasma&nbsp;6 as the default desktop, the addition of <a
href="https://github.com/ValveSoftware/Proton">Proton</a> and Proton
experimental packages for playing Windows games on Linux, as well as 
GNOME&nbsp;46.3 and LXQt&nbsp;2.0.0 spins.</p>
<p></p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983133/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 16:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>OpenSSL announces new governance structure</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983120/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>OpenSSL has <a
href="https://openssl-library.org/post/2024-07-24-openssl-new-governance-structure/">announced</a>
that it has adopted a new governance framework:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
<p>The OpenSSL Management Committee (OMC) has been dissolved, and two
boards of directors have been elected for the <a
href="https://openssl-foundation.org/">Foundation</a> and the <a
href="https://openssl-corporation.org/">Corporation</a>. Each
organization has ten voting members. These boards share all the
responsibilities and authorities of the former OMC co-equally.</p>

<p>To further engage our communities, we are establishing two advisory
committees for each entity: a Business Advisory Committee (BAC) and a
Technical Advisory Committee (TAC). The communities will elect the
members of the BACs and TACs, creating a direct channel for community
input in roadmap development and reflecting the diverse perspectives
of OpenSSL's communities.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>OpenSSL has also announced that two projects have adopted the <a
href="https://openssl-mission.org/faq/index.html">OpenSSL Mission</a>
and become <a href="https://openssl-projects.org/">OpenSSL
projects</a>: <a
href="https://www.bouncycastle.org/">Bouncy Castle</a>, which provides
cryptographic APIs for Java and C#, and the <a
href="https://cryptlib.com/">cryptlib</a> security
software development toolkit. See the announcement for full details.</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983120/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 15:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Let&apos;s Encrypt plans to drop support for OCSP.</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982965/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>
Let's Encrypt has
<a href="https://letsencrypt.org/2024/07/23/replacing-ocsp-with-crls.html">announced</a>
that it intends to end support "<q>as soon as possible</q>" for the 
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_Certificate_Status_Protocol">
Online Certificate Status Protocol</a> (OCSP) over privacy concerns. OCSP was developed as a
lighter-weight alternative to
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Certificate_revocation_list">
Certificate Revocation Lists</a> (CRLs) that did not involve downloading
the entire CRL in order to check whether a certificate was valid. Let's Encrypt will continue
supporting OCSP as long as it is a requirement for Microsoft's
<a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/security/trusted-root/program-requirements">
Trusted Root Program</a>, but hopes to discontinue it soon:
</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
We plan to end support for OCSP primarily because it represents a considerable risk to privacy on the Internet. When someone visits a website using a browser or other software that checks for certificate revocation via OCSP, the Certificate Authority (CA) operating the OCSP responder immediately becomes aware of which website is being visited from that visitor's particular IP address. Even when a CA intentionally does not retain this information, as is the case with Let's Encrypt, CAs could be legally compelled to collect it. CRLs do not have this issue.
</blockquote>

<p>
People using Let's Encrypt as their CA should, for the most part, not need to change their setups.
All modern browsers support CRLs, so end-users shouldn't notice an impact either.
</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982965/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 13:19:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>daroc</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Wednesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/983083/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (ghostscript and xmedcon), <b>Gentoo</b> (Dmidecode, ExifTool, and Freenet), <b>Red Hat</b> (containernetworking-plugins, cups, edk2, httpd, httpd:2.4, kernel, kernel-rt, krb5, libreoffice, libuv, libvirt, linux-firmware, nghttp2, nodejs, openssh, python3, runc, thunderbird, and tpm2-tss), <b>Slackware</b> (aaa_glibc, bind, and mozilla), <b>SUSE</b> (postgresql14, python-sentry-sdk, and shadow), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (activemq, bind9, haproxy, nova, provd, python-zipp, squid, squid3, and tomcat).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/983083/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 12:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Improvements to the PSF Grants program</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982967/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Python Software Foundation (PSF) board has <a
href="https://pyfound.blogspot.com/2024/07/psf-board-update-on-improvements-to-psf.html">announced</a>
improvements to its grants program that have been enacted as a
response to "<q>concerns and frustrations</q>" with the program:</p>

<blockquote class="bq">
The PSF Board takes the <a href="https://pythonafrica.blogspot.com/2023/12/an-open-letter-to-python-software_5.html">open letter</a> from the pan-African delegation
seriously, and we began to draft a plan to address everything in the
letter. We also set up improved two-way communications so that we can
continue the conversation with the community. The writers of the open
letter have now met several times with members of the PSF board. We
are thankful for their insight and guidance on how we can work
together and be thoroughly and consistently supportive of the
pan-African Python community.
</blockquote>

<p>So far the PSF has set up <a
href="https://pyfound.blogspot.com/2024/03/djangocon-africa-grant-process.html">office
hours</a> to improve communications, <a
href="https://pyfound.blogspot.com/2024/03/djangocon-africa-grant-process.html">published
a retrospective</a> on the DjangoCon Africa review, and put out a <a
href="https://pyfound.blogspot.com/2024/05/psf-grants-program-2022-2023.html">transparency
report</a> on grants from the past two years. The PSF board has also
voted to "<q>use the same criteria for all grant requests, no matter
their country of origin</q>".</p>]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982967/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 19:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jzb</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Zuckerberg: Open Source AI Is the Path Forward</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982954/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg has <a
href="https://about.fb.com/news/2024/07/open-source-ai-is-the-path-forward/">posted
an article</a> announcing some new releases of the Llama large language
model and going on at length about why open-source models are important:
<p>
<blockquote class="bq">
	AI has more potential than any other modern technology to increase
	human productivity, creativity, and quality of life – and to
	accelerate economic growth while unlocking progress in medical and
	scientific research. Open source will ensure that more people
	around the world have access to the benefits and opportunities of
	AI, that power isn't concentrated in the hands of a small number of
	companies, and that the technology can be deployed more evenly and
	safely across society.
<p>
	There is an ongoing debate about the safety of open source AI
	models, and my view is that open source AI will be safer than the
	alternatives. I think governments will conclude it's in their
	interest to support open source because it will make the world more
	prosperous and safer.
</blockquote>
<p>
Of course, whether Llama is truly open source is debatable at best, but it
is more open than many of the alternatives.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982954/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 16:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>GNU C Library 2.40 released</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982940/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://lwn.net/ml/all/10946288.T7Z3S40VBb@kona">Version 2.40</a> of the GNU C
Library has been released.  Changes include partial support for the ISO C23
standard, a new tunable for the testing of setuid programs, improved 64-bit
Arm vector support, and a handful of security fixes.  See <a
href="https://sourceware.org/glibc/wiki/Release/2.40">the release notes</a>
for details.]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982940/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 13:37:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Tuesday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982939/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (gtk3 and jpegxl), <b>Red Hat</b> (kpatch-patch and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (apache2, git, gnome-shell, java-11-openjdk, java-21-openjdk, kernel, kernel-firmware, kernel-firmware-nvidia-gspx-G06, libgit2, mozilla-nss, nodejs20, python-Django, and python312), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (linux-aws, linux-aws, linux-aws-5.4, linux-iot, linux-aws-5.15, pymongo, and ruby-rack).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982939/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 13:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>corbet</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Security updates for Monday</title>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/982845/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Security updates have been issued by <b>Fedora</b> (botan2, chromium, ffmpeg, fluent-bit, gtk3, httpd, suricata, tcpreplay, and thunderbird), <b>Mageia</b> (apache, chromium-browser-stable, libfm &amp; libfm-qt, and thunderbird), <b>Oracle</b> (firefox, java-1.8.0-openjdk, java-11-openjdk, java-17-openjdk, java-21-openjdk, kernel, libndp, qt5-qtbase, ruby, skopeo, thunderbird, and virt:ol and virt-devel:rhel), <b>Red Hat</b> (containernetworking-plugins, firefox, libndp, qt5-qtbase, and thunderbird), <b>SUSE</b> (caddy, chromium, emacs, global, mockito, snakeyaml, testng, and opera), and <b>Ubuntu</b> (thunderbird).]]></description>
            <guid>https://lwn.net/Articles/982845/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 13:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>jake</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>